[
    {
        "question": "Running a fuel tank dry before switching tanks is not a good practice because\n",
        "answer": "the engine-driven fuel pump or electric fuel boost pump draw air into the fuel system\nand cause vapor lock.\n",
        "choiceone": "any foreign matter in the tank will be pumped into the fuel system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the engine-driven fuel pump is lubricated by fuel and operating on a dry tank may\ncause pump failure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What energy source is used to drive the turbine of a turbocharged airplane?\n",
        "answer": "Engine exhaust gases.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ignition system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Engine compressor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One advantage of fuel injection systems over carburetor systems is\n",
        "answer": "better fuel distribution to the cylinders.\n",
        "choiceone": "easier hot-engine starting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "less difficulty with hot weather vapor locks during ground operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a steep turn to the left, when using spoilers ...\n",
        "answer": "The right aileron will descend, the left one will ascend, the right spoiler will retract\nand the left one will extend.\n",
        "choiceone": "The right aileron will descend, the left one will ascend, the right spoiler will extend\nand the left one will retract.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The right aileron will ascend, the left one will descend, the right spoiler will extend\nand the left one will retract.\n",
        "choicethree": "The right aileron will ascend, the left one will descend, the right spoiler will retract\nand the left one will extend.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A main landing gear is said to be \u201clocked down\" when:\n",
        "answer": "the strut is locked by an overcentre mechanism.\n",
        "choiceone": "itis in the down position.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the actuating cylinder is at the end of it's travel.\n",
        "choicethree": "the corresponding indicator lamp is amber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cabin pressure is regulated by the:\n",
        "answer": "Outflow valve.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cabin inlet airflow valve.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air cycle machine.\n",
        "choicethree": "Air conditioning pack.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ight, ice begins forming on the outside of the fuel tank in use. This could\n\n",
        "answer": "a leak in the fuel line.\n",
        "choiceone": "water in the fuel.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a broken dip tube.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Constant Speed Drive aims at ensuring\n",
        "answer": "that the electric generator produces a constant frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "equal AC voltage from all generators.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that the starter-motor maintains a constant RPM not\n",
        "choicethree": "that the CSD remains at a constant RPM not withstanding the generator RPM\nwithstanding the acceleration of the engine.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a current is passed through a conductor whi\nmagnetic field:\n\npositioned perpendicular to a\n",
        "answer": "a force will be exerted on the conductor.\n",
        "choiceone": "the current will increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there will be no effect unless the conductor is moved.\n",
        "choicethree": "the intensity of the magnetic field will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reason for using inverters in an electrical system is\n",
        "answer": "To change DC into AC.\n",
        "choiceone": "To avoid a short circuit.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To change the DC voltage.\n",
        "choicethree": "To change AC into DC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The type of windings commonly used in DC starter motors are:\n",
        "answer": "series wound.\n",
        "choiceone": "shunt wound.\n",
        "choicetwo": "series shunt wound.\n",
        "choicethree": "compound wound.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of a voltage regulator is to control the output voltage of the:\n",
        "answer": "generator at varying loads and speeds.\n",
        "choiceone": "batteries at varying loads.\n",
        "choicetwo": "generators at varying speeds and the batteries at varying loads.\n",
        "choicethree": "TRU.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In general, in twin-engine aeroplanes with \u2018constant speed propeller\u2019\n",
        "answer": "the oil pressure turns the propeller blades towards smaller pitch angle.\n",
        "choiceone": "the aerodynamic force turns the propeller blades towards higher pitch angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the spring force turns the propeller blades towards smaller pitch angle.\n",
        "choicethree": "the oil pressure turns the propeller blades towards higher pitch angle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under what condition is V(MC) the highest?\n",
        "answer": "CG is at the most rearward allowable position.\n",
        "choiceone": "Gross weight is at the maximum allowable value.\n",
        "choicetwo": "CG is at the most forward allowable position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a turbo-jet, the purpose of the turbine is to ...\n",
        "answer": "drive the compressor by using part of the energy from the exhaust gases\n",
        "choiceone": "clear the burnt gases, the expansion of which provide the thrust\n",
        "choicetwo": "compress the air in order to provide a better charge of the combustion chamber\n",
        "choicethree": "drive devices like pumps, regulator, generator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding a jet engine:\n|. The maximum thrust remains constant as the pressure altitude increases.\nIl. The specific fuel consumption increases slightly as the pressure altitud\nconstant TAS.\n\n",
        "answer": "lis incorrect, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "lis incorrect, Il is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lis correct, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "lis correct, Il is correct.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The bypass ratio:\n|. is the ratio of bypass air mass flow to HP compressor mass flow.\nIl. can be determined from the inlet air mass flow and the HP compressor mass flow.\n",
        "answer": "lis correct, Il is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "lis correct, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lis incorrect, Il is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "lis incorrect, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low oil pressure is sometimes the result of a\n",
        "answer": "worn oil pump\n",
        "choiceone": "too large oil pump\n",
        "choicetwo": "restricted oil passage\n",
        "choicethree": "too small scavenger pump.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Smoke detectors fitted on transport aircraft are of the following type :\n",
        "answer": "optical or ionization\n",
        "choiceone": "electrical\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The disadvantages of a chemical oxygen source for the passenger cabin are : 1. a flow\nwhich cannot be modulated, 2. a heavy and bulky system, 3. non reversible functioning,\n4. risks of explosion, 5. poor autonomy. The combination regrouping all the correct\n\nstatements is:\n",
        "answer": "1,3,5\n",
        "choiceone": "1,2,3,4,5\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,4\n",
        "choicethree": "1,2,3,5\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should be the indication on the magnetic compass as you roll into a standard rate\nturn to the right from a south heading in the Northern Hemisphere?\n",
        "answer": "The compass will indicate a turn to the right, but at a faster rate than is actually\noccurring.\n",
        "choiceone": "The compass will initially indicate a turn to the left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The compass will remain on south for a short time, then gradually catch up to the\nmagnetic heading of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A gyroplane will have the greatest tendency to roll during\n",
        "answer": "horizontal flight at high speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "climbing flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "descending flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "craft is flying from a cold air mass into a warm air mass. The TAS and true altitude\n\n",
        "answer": "Both increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "TAS increases, true altitude decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAS decreases, true altitude increases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airfield, elevation 3000 feet, has a pressure altitude of 3500 feet. What is the QFE?\n",
        "answer": "896.5 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "913.s hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "879.8 hPa\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the static source of an altimeter becomes blocked during a descent th\nwill:\n",
        "answer": "continue to display the reading at which the blockage occurred.\n",
        "choiceone": "gradually indicate zero.\n",
        "choicetwo": "under-read.\n",
        "choicethree": "indicate a height with the subscale setting on QNH.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ASI consists of a gas tight casing which has:\n",
        "answer": "pitot pressure fed into an open capsule and static pressure fed outside the capsule\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule and pitot pressure fed into a second\nopen capsule\n",
        "choicetwo": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule\n",
        "choicethree": "static pressure fed through a restrictive choke\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is maintal\nprobable cause is:\n\n1g FL 120 in cloud. The ASI reading falls to zero. The most\n",
        "answer": "ASI malfunction.\n",
        "choiceone": "Static vent blocked by ice.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pitot head and static vent blocked by ice.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aircraft climbs at a constant IAS in the standard atmosphere, the Mach number will:\n",
        "answer": "increase\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease\n",
        "choicetwo": "remain constant\n",
        "choicethree": "remain constant unless the aircraft flies through an inversion\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rotor of the DGI spins up and away from the pilot when 090 is ir\nlatitude compensation nut situated on the near right hand side of the inner gimbal from\nthe gyro axis, has been set to give zero drift on the ground at the equator. To\ncompensate for earth rotation at 30 S the latitude compensating nut:\n",
        "answer": "must be adjusted outwards;\n",
        "choiceone": "must be adjusted inwards;\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not adjusted since the latitude nut can only be used to correct for apparent\nwander in the northern hemisphere.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The turning error of a direct reading magnetic compass:\n",
        "answer": "increases when the magnetic latitude increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases when the magnetic latitude increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "does not depend on the magnetic latitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "decreases when the magnetic longitude increases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of rigi\ninstruments:\n\nused for the operation of the following gyroscopic\n",
        "answer": "Directional Gyro and Artificial Horizon.\n",
        "choiceone": "Directional Gyro and Turn indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Artificial Horizon and Turn indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate angle of bank for a rate one turn at 110 knots?\n",
        "answer": "18 degrees\n",
        "choiceone": "25 degrees\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 degrees\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of a trim tab (device) is to:\n",
        "answer": "reduce or to cancel control forces.\n",
        "choiceone": "trim the aeroplane at low airspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lower manoeuvring control forces.\n",
        "choicethree": "trim the aeroplane during normal flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these signals are inputs, at least, in the stall warning computers?\n",
        "answer": "Angle of attack and flaps and slats deflection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Angle of attack, flaps deflection and EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Angle of attack, flaps deflection, EPR and N1.\n",
        "choicethree": "Angle of attack and flaps and spoilers deflection.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The radio altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "centimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "millimetric\n",
        "choicethree": "metric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should help prevent aircraft induced oscillation on a gyroplane?-\n",
        "answer": "Adding a horizontal stabilizer.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increasing cyclic control sensitivity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Lowering the center of gravity below the thrust line.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should a pilot do to maintain \u2018best range\u2019 airplane performance when a tailwin\nencountered?\n",
        "answer": "Decrease speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increase speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Maintain speed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are outboard ailerons normally used?\n",
        "answer": "Low-speed flight only.\n",
        "choiceone": "High-speed flight only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low-speed and high-speed flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the different types of aircraft structures, the shell structures efficiently transmit\nthe: 1. normal bending stresses 2. tangent bending stresses 3. torsional moment 4.\nshear stresses The combination regrouping all the correct statements is :\n\n",
        "answer": "1,2,3\n",
        "choiceone": "2,3,4\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,2,4\n",
        "choicethree": "1,3,4\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Large transport aeroplane hydraulic systems usually operate with a system pressure of\napproximately:\n",
        "answer": "3000 psi\n",
        "choiceone": "1000 psi\n",
        "choicetwo": "4000 psi\n",
        "choicethree": "2000 psi\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The component that transforms the hydraulic pressure into a linear motion is called ...\n",
        "answer": "An actuator or jack.\n",
        "choiceone": "An accumulator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A Pressure regulator.\n",
        "choicethree": "A hydraulic pump.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming cabin differential pressure has attained the required value in normal flight\nconditions, if flight altitude is maintained:\n",
        "answer": "a constant mass air flow is permitted through the cabin.\n",
        "choiceone": "the pressurisation system ceases to function until leakage reduces the pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the outflow valves will move to the fully closed position.\n",
        "choicethree": "the outflow valves will move to the fully open position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the preheating coil used in hot air balloons is to\n",
        "answer": "vaporize the fuel for more efficient burner operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "prevent ice from forming in the fuel lines.\n",
        "choicetwo": "warm the fuel tanks for more efficient fuel flow.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fuel pumps submerged in the fuel tanks of a large aeroplane are:\n",
        "answer": "centrifugal low pressure type pumps.\n",
        "choiceone": "low pressure variable swash plate pumps.\n",
        "choicetwo": "centrifugal high pressure pumps.\n",
        "choicethree": "high pressure swash plate pumps.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an alternator rotor coil you can find :\n",
        "answer": "AC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only induced current.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dc.\n",
        "choicethree": "Three-phase AC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming the initiating cause is removed, which of these statements about resetting are\ncorrect or incorrect?\n\nI. A fuse is not resettable\n\nIl A circuit breaker is resettable.\n",
        "answer": "lis correct, Il is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "lis incorrect, Il is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lis correct, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "lis incorrect, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency of the current provided by an alternator depends on...\n",
        "answer": "its rotation speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "the strength of the excitation current.\n",
        "choicetwo": "its load.\n",
        "choicethree": "its phase balance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an engine fails to stop with the magneto switch in OFF position, the cause may be:\n",
        "answer": "excessive carbon formation in cylinder head.\n",
        "choiceone": "switch wire grounded\n",
        "choicetwo": "defective condenser\n",
        "choicethree": "fouled spark plugs\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb in a standard atmosphere with constant MAP and RPM indications and at\na constant mixture setting, the power output of a piston engine:\n",
        "answer": "increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only stays constant if the propeller lever is pushed.\n",
        "choicethree": "stays constant.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does V(NE) speed vary with altitude?\n",
        "answer": "Varies inversely with altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Varies directly with altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Remains the same at all altitudes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fan in a high by-pass ratio turbo-jet engine produces:\n",
        "answer": "the greater part of the thrust.\n",
        "choiceone": "half the thrust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the lesser part of the thrust.\n",
        "choicethree": "none of the thrust.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary reason for a limitation being imposed on the temperature of gas flow is to :\n",
        "answer": "ensure that the maximum acceptable temperature at the turbine blades is not\nexceeded.\n",
        "choiceone": "ensure that the maximum acceptable temperature within the combustion chamber is\nnot exceeded.\n",
        "choicetwo": "prevent damage to the jet pipe from overheating.\n",
        "choicethree": "prevent overheating and subsequent creep of the nozzle\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A smoke mask is a :\n",
        "answer": "mask with flow on request and covers the whole face.\n",
        "choiceone": "continuous flow mask and covers only the nose and the mouth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "continuous flow mask and covers the whole face.\n",
        "choicethree": "mask with flow on request and covers only the nose and the mouth.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is breathed in when using a passenger oxygen mask?\n",
        "answer": "Cabin air and oxygen.\n",
        "choiceone": "100% oxygen.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cabin air and oxygen or 100% oxygen.\n",
        "choicethree": "A mixture of oxygen and freon gas.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which factors must be recorded by the approved flight recorder?\n",
        "answer": "Airspeed, time, altitude, vertical acceleration, and heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Time, true altitude, calibrated airspeed, vertical speed, and heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Elapsed time, airspeed, altitude, vertical acceleration, and magnetic course.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which may lead to a power push-over in a gyroplane?\n",
        "answer": "Rotor force is removed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decreasing power too quickly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A gyroplane will have the greatest tendency to roll during\n",
        "answer": "horizontal flight at high speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "climbing flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "descending flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the indications of the pulsating VASI?\n",
        "answer": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - steady white, slightly below glide slope steady\nred, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choiceone": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - green, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High - pulsing white, on course and on glidepath - steady white, off course but on\nglidepath - pulsing white and red; low - pulsing red.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true about magnetic deviation of a compass?\n",
        "answer": "Deviation varies for different headings of the same aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Deviation is the same for all aircraft in the same locality.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deviation is different in a given aircraft in different localities.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 85.) What route should you take if cleared for the Washoe Two\nDeparture and your assigned route is V6?\n",
        "answer": "Climb on the LOC south course to WAGGE where you will be vectored to V6.\n",
        "choiceone": "Climb on the LOC south course to cross WAGGE at 9,000, turn left and fly direct to\nFMG VORTAC and cross at or above 10,000, and proceed on FMG R-241.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Climb on the LOC south course to WAGGE, turn left and fly direct to FMG VORTAC. If\nat 10,000 turn left and proceed on FMG R-241; if not at 10,000 enter depicted holding\npattern and climb to 10,000 before proceeding on FMG R-241.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a pitot tube is clogged, which instrument would be affected?\n",
        "answer": "Airspeed indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altimeter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vertical speed indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which instrument would be affected by excessively low pressure in the\nvacuum system?\n",
        "answer": "Heading indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airspeed indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pressure altimeter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The location of the static vent which could provide the most accurate measurement of\nstatic pressure under variable flight conditions i\n\n",
        "answer": "One on each side of the aircraft where the system will compensate for variation of\naircraft attitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the Pitot head which encounters relatively undisturbed air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In the cockpit where it is not influenced by a variable angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft leaves FL 160 for an approach and landing at an airfield. The pilot will set\nQNH at the:\n",
        "answer": "Transition level.\n",
        "choiceone": "Transition Layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transition Altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is maintal\nprobable cause is:\n\n1g FL 120 in cloud. The ASI reading falls to zero. The most\n",
        "answer": "ASI malfunction.\n",
        "choiceone": "Static vent blocked by ice.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pitot head and static vent blocked by ice.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The limits of the green scale of an airspeed indicator are:\n",
        "answer": "VS1 and VNO.\n",
        "choiceone": "VS1 and VMO.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VSO and VNE.\n",
        "choicethree": "VS1 and VNE.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a steep turn, the northerly turning error on a direct reading magnetic compass on the\nnorthern hemisphere\n\n",
        "answer": "equal to 180\u00b0 on a 090\u00b0 heading in a right turn.\n",
        "choiceone": "none on a 270\u00b0 heading in a left turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "none on a 090\u00b0 heading in a right turn.\n",
        "choicethree": "equal to 180\u00b0 on a 270\u00b0 heading in a right turn.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Artificial Horizon employs a;\n",
        "answer": "Earth gyro\n",
        "choiceone": "Tied gyro\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rate gyro\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a stabilised climbing turn at a constant rate, the instruments which indicate the\n\ncorrect pitch and bank are the:\n",
        "answer": "attitude indicator and turn-and-slip indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "vertical-speed indicator and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What indications should you get from the Turn and Slip indicator during taxi?\n",
        "answer": "The ball moves opposite to the turn and the needle deflects in the direction of the\nturn.\n",
        "choiceone": "The needle and ball should move freely in the direction of the turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ball deflects opposite to the turn and the needle remains central.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate angle of bank for a rate one turn at 110 knots?\n",
        "answer": "18 degrees\n",
        "choiceone": "25 degrees\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 degrees\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flight director indicates the:\n",
        "answer": "optimum instantaneous trajectory to reach selected radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "optimum trajectory at the moment it is entered to reach a selected radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "trajectory permitting reaching a selected radial in minimum time.\n",
        "choicethree": "trajectory permitting reaching a selected radial over a minimum distance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the relationship betwee\nincreased?\n\n\\duced and parasite drag when the gross weight is\n",
        "answer": "Induced drag increases more than parasite drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "Parasite drag increases more than induced drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Both parasite and induced drag are equally increased.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "craft attitude tends to return to its original position after\nthe controls have been neutralized.\n",
        "answer": "Positive static stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "Positive dynamic stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Neutral dynamic stability.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are outboard ailerons normally used?\n",
        "answer": "Low-speed flight only.\n",
        "choiceone": "High-speed flight only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low-speed and high-speed flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "craft attitude tends to move farther from\nposition after the controls have been neutralized.\n\noriginal\n",
        "answer": "Negative static stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "Positive static stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Negative dynamic stability.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the movement of the center of pressure when the wingtips of a sweptwing\nairplane are shock-stalled first?\n",
        "answer": "Inward and forward.\n",
        "choiceone": "Inward and aft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Outward and forward.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cabin air for modern aircraft is usually taken from:\n",
        "answer": "the low pressure compressor and from the high pressure compressor if necessary.\n",
        "choiceone": "the second fan stage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the low pressure compressor.\n",
        "choicethree": "the high pressure compressor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pressurization of the cabin is controlled by :\n",
        "answer": "The cabin outflow valve.\n",
        "choiceone": "The cabin inlet airflow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The engine's RPM.\n",
        "choicethree": "The engine's bleed valves.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The refueling in a transport jet aircraft is made ...\n",
        "answer": "By means of the aircraft suction pumps through a unique point (an underwing\nrefueling center).\n",
        "choiceone": "Through the refueling cap of every tank\n",
        "choicetwo": "By means of the aircraft suction pumps.\n",
        "choicethree": "Through a unique point (an underwing refueling center).\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fuses are rated to a value by:\n",
        "answer": "the number of amperes they will carry.\n",
        "choiceone": "the number of volts they will pass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "their wattage.\n",
        "choicethree": "their resistance measured in ohms.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cFrequency wild\" in relation to a AC generation system means the generator :\n",
        "answer": "output frequency varies with engine speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "output frequency is too low.\n",
        "choicetwo": "output frequency is too high.\n",
        "choicethree": "voltage regulator is out of adjustment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A feeder fault on a direct current circuit results from a flux unbalance between the:\n",
        "answer": "voltage coil and the series winding turn.\n",
        "choiceone": "shunt exciter and the series winding turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "voltage coil and the series winding.\n",
        "choicethree": "generator and the series winding turn.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The function of a constant speed drive (CSD) in an AC generating system is to :\n",
        "answer": "drive the generator at a constant speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "vary generator rpm in order to compensate for various AC loads.\n",
        "choicetwo": "directly maintain a constant proportion between the rpm of an engine and a\ngenerator.\n",
        "choicethree": "vary the engine rpm (within limits) to compensate for various AC loads.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would be likely to increase the possi\noccurring within a piston engine ?\n\nity of detonation\n",
        "answer": "using too lean a fuel/air mixture ratio\n",
        "choiceone": "using an engine with a low compression ratio\n",
        "choicetwo": "slightly retarding the ignition timing\n",
        "choicethree": "the use of a fuel with a high octane rating as compared to the use of one with alow\noctane rating\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under what condition should stalls never be practiced in a twin-engine airplane?\n",
        "answer": "With one engine inoperative.\n",
        "choiceone": "With climb power on.\n",
        "choicetwo": "With full flaps and gear extended.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the drag versus TAS curve for a jet aeroplane, the speed for maximum range\ncorresponds with:\n",
        "answer": "the point of contact of the tangent from the origin to the drag curve.\n",
        "choiceone": "the point of intersection of the parasite drag curve and the induced drag curve.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the point of contact of the tangent from the origin to the parasite drag curve.\n",
        "choicethree": "the point of contact of the tangent from the origin to the induced drag curve.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fan in a high by-pass ratio turbo-jet engine produces:\n",
        "answer": "the greater part of the thrust.\n",
        "choiceone": "half the thrust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the lesser part of the thrust.\n",
        "choicethree": "none of the thrust.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The bypass ratio:\n|. is the ratio of bypass air mass flow to HP compressor mass flow.\nIl. can be determined from the inlet air mass flow and the HP compressor mass flow.\n",
        "answer": "lis correct, Il is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "lis correct, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lis incorrect, Il is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "lis incorrect, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An impulse turbine is a turbine in which the expansion takes place:\n",
        "answer": "fully in the stator.\n",
        "choiceone": "in order to produce a degree of jet propulsion < 1/2.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fully in the rotor.\n",
        "choicethree": "in the stator and in the rotor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the flow in a divergent (subsonic)\ngas turbine engine intake?\n\n|. The speed decreases in flow direction.\nll. The total pressure remains constant in flow direction.\n",
        "answer": "lis correct, Il is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "lis incorrect, Il is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lis correct, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "lis incorrect, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a pressurized aircraft, the first-aid (therapeutic) oxygen is designed to:\n",
        "answer": "give medical assistance to passengers with pathological respiratory disorders.\n",
        "choiceone": "protect the flight crew and cabin attendants against fumes and noxious gases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "protect all the occupants against the effects of accidental depressurisation.\n",
        "choicethree": "protect certain passengers, and is only carried on board for these people.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "nificance of the blue radial line on the airspeed\nmultiengine airplane and when is it to be used? It indicates the\n\n",
        "answer": "speed which will provide the maximum altitude gain in a given time when one engine\nis inoperative and should be used for climb and final approach during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "choiceone": "minimum speed at which the airplane is controllable when the critical engine is\nsuddenly made inoperative and should be used at all altitudes when an engine is\ninoperative.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed which will provide the greatest height for a given distance of forward travel\nwhen one engine is inoperative and should be used for all climbs during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true about magnetic deviation of a compass?\n",
        "answer": "Deviation varies for different headings of the same aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Deviation is the same for all aircraft in the same locality.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deviation is different in a given aircraft in different localities.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deviation error of the magnetic compass is caused by\n",
        "answer": "certain metals and electrical systems within the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "northerly turning error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the difference in location of true north and magnetic north.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 87.) Where\nLake Charles?\n\nthe VOR COP when flying east on V306 from D:\n",
        "answer": "30 NM east of DAS.\n",
        "choiceone": "50 NM east of DAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "40 NM east of DAS.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 85.) What is the mi\nWASH2 WAGGE Departure?\n\njum rate climb per NM to 9,000 feet required for the\n",
        "answer": "400 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "750 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "875 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should be the indication on the magnetic compass as you roll into a standard rate\nturn to the right from a south heading in the Northern Hemisphere?\n",
        "answer": "The compass will indicate a turn to the right, but at a faster rate than is actually\noccurring.\n",
        "choiceone": "The compass will initially indicate a turn to the left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The compass will remain on south for a short time, then gradually catch up to the\nmagnetic heading of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 87.) At STRUT intersection headed eastbound, ATC instructs you to\nhold west on the 10 DME fix west of LCH on V306, standard turns, what entry procedure\nis recommended?\n",
        "answer": "Direct.\n",
        "choiceone": "Teardrop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Parallel.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pitot line is blocked, the VSI will:\n",
        "answer": "read normally\n",
        "choiceone": "read zero ftmm rate of climb/descent\n",
        "choicetwo": "over-read\n",
        "choicethree": "under-read\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ASI compressibility error will increase with increase of TAS and:\n",
        "answer": "Increase with altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Decrease with altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increase with increase of density.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "level flight, it becomes necessary to use an alternate source of static pressure\nje the aircraft, with the cabin pressure being lower than static, the following\nvariations in instrument indication would be expected:\n\n",
        "answer": "the altimeter will read higher than normal, airspeed greater than normal and the\nvertical-speed indicator will momentarily show a climb;\n",
        "choiceone": "the altimeter will read higher than normal, airspeed will not change and the vertical-\nspeed indicator will momentarily show a descent;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the altimeter will read lower than normal, airspeed greater than normal and the\nvertical-speed indicator will momentarily show a climb and then a descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The elevation of aerodrome A is 390 feet and aerodrome B 450 feet. The pilot of an\naeroplane at A, sets the altimeter to read aerodrome elevation and then flies to B without\nresetting the altimeter. Aerodrome pressure at A on departure was 1004 hPa. On\nlanding at B the altimeter reads 630 feet, and assuming 1 hPa is 30 feet, the QNH is\napproximately:\n",
        "answer": "1011 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "1013 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "1019 hPa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To allow for changes in the viscosity of the air, the VSI employs:\n",
        "answer": "a restrictive choke\n",
        "choiceone": "a logarithmic scale\n",
        "choicetwo": "diaphragm overload stops\n",
        "choicethree": "a complex capillary/orifice choke system\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a combined Machiairspeed indicator the purpose of the barber's pole is to indicate:\n",
        "answer": "Vmo, and this value increases at high altitudes\n",
        "choiceone": "Vmo, and this is a fixed value at all altitudes\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vmo, and this value decreases at high altitudes\n",
        "choicethree": "the maximum safe airspeed with the flaps/slats extended\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The percentage error due to the positioning of the static vent\n",
        "answer": "the same in the Machmeter as in the ASI\n",
        "choiceone": "greater in the ASI than in the Machmeter\n",
        "choicetwo": "greater in the Machmeter than in the ASI\n",
        "choicethree": "either greater or smaller when comparing the ASI and the Machmeter,\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the building principle of a gyroscope, the best efficiency is obtained through the\nconcentration of the mass:\n",
        "answer": "on the periphery and with a high rotational speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "close to the axis and with a high rotational speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the periphery and with a low rotational speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "close to the axis and with a low rotational speed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the rotational speed of the Turn and Slip gyro rotor is below the calibrated speed the:\n",
        "answer": "Turn indicator underreads, slip not affected.\n",
        "choiceone": "Turn indicator overreads.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turn indicator and Slip underreads.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate angle of bank for a rate one turn at 110 knots?\n",
        "answer": "18 degrees\n",
        "choiceone": "25 degrees\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 degrees\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The radio altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "centimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "millimetric\n",
        "choicethree": "metric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the ground wire between the magneto and the ignition switch becomes disconnected,\nthe most noticeable result will be that the engine\n",
        "answer": "cannot be shut down by turning the switch to the OFF position.\n",
        "choiceone": "will run very rough.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cannot be started with the switch in the ON position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which direction from the primary control surface does a servo tab move?\n",
        "answer": "Opposite direction.\n",
        "choiceone": "Same direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Remains fixed for all positions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At which speed will increasing the pitch attitude cause an airplane to climb?\n",
        "answer": "High speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any speed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What affects indicated stall speed?\n",
        "answer": "Weight, load factor, and power.\n",
        "choiceone": "Load factor, angle of attack, and power.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Angle of attack, weight, and air density.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the door operation of a transport airplane equipped with evacuation slides\ncontrolled from the outside, the slide:\n\n",
        "answer": "is disarmed automatically.\n",
        "choiceone": "unfolds and becomes inflated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unfolds but does not become inflated.\n",
        "choicethree": "becomes inflated in its packboard thus preventing its unfolding.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Large transport aeroplane hydraulic systems usually operate with a system pressure of\napproximately:\n",
        "answer": "3000 psi\n",
        "choiceone": "1000 psi\n",
        "choicetwo": "4000 psi\n",
        "choicethree": "2000 psi\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term \u201cpressure cabin\" applies when an aeroplane :\n",
        "answer": "has the means to maintain cabin pressure higher than ambient pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "has the ability to maintain a constant cabin differential pressure at all flight altitudes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "has the ability to maintain a constant cabin altitude at all flight altitudes.\n",
        "choicethree": "is only pressurised in the area of the control cabin.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cabin altitude means the:\n",
        "answer": "cabin pressure expressed as altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight level the aircraft is flying at.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight level altitude at maximum differential pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "difference in height between the cabin floor and ceiling.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum quantity of fuel that can be dumped with the jettisoning system is:\n",
        "answer": "All up to a defined reserve quantity.\n",
        "choiceone": "All fuel until the maximum landing weight is reached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 tons.\n",
        "choicethree": "All fuel.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Specific fuel consumption is defined as the :\n",
        "answer": "mass of fuel required to produce unit power for unit time.\n",
        "choiceone": "quantity of fuel required to run the engine for one minute at maximum operating\nconditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maximum fuel consumption of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicethree": "designed fuel consumption for a given rpm.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an aircraft equipped with a DC main power system, AC for instrument operation may\nbe obtained from :\n",
        "answer": "an inverter.\n",
        "choiceone": "a contactor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a TRU.\n",
        "choicethree": "a rectifier.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The working cycle of a four-stroke engine is :\n",
        "answer": "induction, compression, power, exhaust.\n",
        "choiceone": "induction, power, compression, exhaust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "compression induction, power, exhaust.\n",
        "choicethree": "induction, compression, expansion, power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "in a piston engine turbo-supercharger centrifugal compressor :\n",
        "answer": "enters the eye of the impeller and leaves at a tangent to the periphery.\n",
        "choiceone": "enters at the periphery and leaves via the eye of the impeller.\n",
        "choicetwo": "enters at a tangent to the rotor and leaves via the stator.\n",
        "choicethree": "enters via the diffuser and is fed to the impeller at the optimum angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a turbine engine, the term self-sustai\nwhich the engine:\n\nig speed relates to the lowest rpm range at\n",
        "answer": "will continue to run without any further starter assistance.\n",
        "choiceone": "is designed to idle after starting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "operates most efficiently in the cruise.\n",
        "choicethree": "will enable the generators to supply bus bar voltage.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The conditions under which you obtain the highest engine power are :\n",
        "answer": "cold and dry air at high pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "cold and humid air at high pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "warm and dry air at high pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "warm and humid air at low pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An impulse coupling is inhibited at higher than normal rotational starting speeds by:\n",
        "answer": "centrifugal force.\n",
        "choiceone": "engine oil pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a coil spring.\n",
        "choicethree": "electro-magnetic action of an operating magneto.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A \u201chung start\" is the failure of an engine to accelerate to its normal idle speed. It may be\ncaused by:\n",
        "answer": "an attempt to ignite the fuel before the engine has been accelerated sufficiently by\nthe starter.\n",
        "choiceone": "failure of the fuel to ignite in the starting sequence after the engine has been\naccelerated to the required rpm by the starter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "compressor surging.\n",
        "choicethree": "the starter cutting out early in the starting sequence before the engine has\naccelerated to the required rpm for ignition.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a multi-engined aircraft a fire detection system includes :\n",
        "answer": "a warning light for each engine and a single alarm bell common to all engines\n",
        "choiceone": "a single warning light and a single alarm bell\n",
        "choicetwo": "both a warning light and an alarm bell unique to each engine\n",
        "choicethree": "a single warning light but a separate alarm bell for each engine\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the flight deck oxygen supply system. The\npurpose of the oxygen regulator (as a function of\ndemand and altitude) is to:\n\n1. decrease oxygen pressure from 1800 PSI (in the\nbottles) down to about 50-75 PSI (low pressure system)\n2. supply pure oxygen\n\n3. supply diluted oxygen\n\n4. supply oxygen at normal pressure\n\n5. supply oxygen at emergency/positive pressure\n\n6. trigger the continuous cabin altitude warning at 10000\nft cabin altitude\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements\n\n",
        "answer": "2,3,4,5\n",
        "choiceone": "3,4, 5,6\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,2,3,4\n",
        "choicethree": "1,3,4,6\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the maximum operating pressure of the oxygen system is exceeded the:\n",
        "answer": "oxygen is discharged overboard via a safety plug.\n",
        "choiceone": "oxygen becomes unusable for the passengers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "passenger oxygen masks will drop down.\n",
        "choicethree": "oxygen bottles will explode.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "nificance of the blue radial line on the airspeed\nmultiengine airplane and when is it to be used? It indicates the\n\n",
        "answer": "speed which will provide the maximum altitude gain in a given time when one engine\nis inoperative and should be used for climb and final approach during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "choiceone": "minimum speed at which the airplane is controllable when the critical engine is\nsuddenly made inoperative and should be used at all altitudes when an engine is\ninoperative.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed which will provide the greatest height for a given distance of forward travel\nwhen one engine is inoperative and should be used for all climbs during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify touchdown zone lighting (TDZL).\n",
        "answer": "Two rows of transverse light bars disposed symmetrically about the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flush centerline lights spaced at 50-foot intervals extending through the touchdown\nzone.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate white and green centerline lights extending from 75 feet from the threshold\nthrough the touchdown zone.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 87.) Where\nLake Charles?\n\nthe VOR COP when flying east on V306 from D:\n",
        "answer": "30 NM east of DAS.\n",
        "choiceone": "50 NM east of DAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "40 NM east of DAS.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How should you preflight check the altimeter prior to an IFR flight?\n",
        "answer": "Set the altimeter to the current altimeter setting. The indication should be within 75\nfeet of the actual elevation for acceptable accuracy.\n",
        "choiceone": "Set the altimeter to 29.92\" Hg. With current temperature and the altimeter indication,\ndetermine the true altitude to compare with the field elevation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Set the altimeter first with 29.92\" Hg and then the current altimeter setting. The\nchange in altitude should correspond to the change in setting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When making an airborne VOR check, what is the maximum allowable tolerance\nbetween the two indicators of a dual VOR system (units independent of each other\nexcept the antenna)?\n\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees between the two indicated bearings of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus or minus 4 degrees when set to identical radials of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 degrees between the two indicated radials of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deviation error of the magnetic compass is caused by\n",
        "answer": "certain metals and electrical systems within the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "northerly turning error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the difference in location of true north and magnetic north.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which procedure is recommended to prevent or overcome spatial disorientation?\n",
        "answer": "Rely entirely on the indications of the flight instruments.\n",
        "choiceone": "Avoid steep turns and rough control movements.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Reduce head and eye movements to the greatest extent possible.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Bourdon tube is used in:\n",
        "answer": "pressure sensors\n",
        "choiceone": "vibration detectors\n",
        "choicetwo": "smoke detectors\n",
        "choicethree": "turbine temperature probes\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "level flight, it becomes necessary to use an alternate source of static pressure\nje the aircraft, with the cabin pressure being lower than static, the following\nvariations in instrument indication would be expected:\n\n",
        "answer": "the altimeter will read higher than normal, airspeed greater than normal and the\nvertical-speed indicator will momentarily show a climb;\n",
        "choiceone": "the altimeter will read higher than normal, airspeed will not change and the vertical-\nspeed indicator will momentarily show a descent;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the altimeter will read lower than normal, airspeed greater than normal and the\nvertical-speed indicator will momentarily show a climb and then a descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "QNH is the sub-scale setting which will cause the altimeter to read:\n",
        "answer": "vertical displacement above mean sea level\n",
        "choiceone": "the altitude at which any given pressure exists in the standard atmosphere\n",
        "choicetwo": "vertical displacement above the airfield pressure datum\n",
        "choicethree": "pressure altitude\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft leaves FL 160 for an approach and landing at an airfield. The pilot will set\nQNH at the:\n",
        "answer": "Transition level.\n",
        "choiceone": "Transition Layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transition Altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb, the static line becomes blocked, the ASI will:\n",
        "answer": "under-read\n",
        "choiceone": "read normally\n",
        "choicetwo": "over-read\n",
        "choicethree": "read zero\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot opening is blocked, whi\nvent)?\n\nstruments would be affected (separate static\n",
        "answer": "ASI only.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and VSI.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ASI and VSI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a combined Machiairspeed indicator the purpose of the barber's pole is to indicate:\n",
        "answer": "Vmo, and this value increases at high altitudes\n",
        "choiceone": "Vmo, and this is a fixed value at all altitudes\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vmo, and this value decreases at high altitudes\n",
        "choicethree": "the maximum safe airspeed with the flaps/slats extended\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A RMI (Radio Magnetic Indicator) displays a warning flag which\nfailure. The radio bearing pointers:\n\n",
        "answer": "can be used to home to an NDB;\n",
        "choiceone": "are not to be used;\n",
        "choicetwo": "can be used to home to an NDB and a VOR station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One characteristic that a properly functioning gyro depends upon for operation is the:\n",
        "answer": "Resistance to deflection of the gyro rotor.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ability to resist precession at 90 degrees to an applied force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position of the gyro axis relative to the Earth's axis.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 022-10217A)\nConsidering the diagram n\u00b0, the flight director command bars position indicates that\nyou should:\n",
        "answer": "bank your aircraft to the left and increase the pitch angle.\n",
        "choiceone": "bank your aircraft to the right and increase the pitch angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "bank your aircraft to the left and reduce the pitch angle.\n",
        "choicethree": "bank your aircraft to the right and reduce the pitch angle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these signals are inputs, at least, in the stall warning computers?\n",
        "answer": "Angle of attack and flaps and slats deflection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Angle of attack, flaps deflection and EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Angle of attack, flaps deflection, EPR and N1.\n",
        "choicethree": "Angle of attack and flaps and spoilers deflection.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first indication of carburetor ice in an aircraft with a fixed-pitch propeller is\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in RPM.\n",
        "choiceone": "a decrease in manifold pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase in manifold pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "2-cycle engine thrust and fuel efficiency can be greatly compromised when\n",
        "answer": "exhaust systems are installed that are not specifically tuned for an engine.\n",
        "choiceone": "carbon deposits build up on exhaust valves.\n",
        "choicetwo": "intake valve lifters fail to pressurize and provide adequate fuel to the combustion\nchamber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a purpose of leading-edge flaps?\n",
        "answer": "Increase the camber of the wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Reduce lift without increasing airspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct airflow over the top of the wing at high angles of attack.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The advantage of mounting the tailplane on top of the vertical stabilizer is :\n",
        "answer": "to withdraw it from the influence of wing turbulence\n",
        "choiceone": "to a have greater effectiveness at high speed\n",
        "choicetwo": "that it does not require a de-icing system\n",
        "choicethree": "to decrease fuel consumption by creating a tail heavy situation\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of a control tab?\n",
        "answer": "Move the flight controls in the event of manual reversion.\n",
        "choiceone": "Reduce control forces by deflecting in the proper direction to move a primary flight\ncontrol.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prevent a control surface from moving to a full-deflection position due to\naerodynamic forces.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mixture control for a carburettor achieves its control by:\n",
        "answer": "varying the fuel supply to the main discharge tube.\n",
        "choiceone": "altering the depression on the main discharge tube.\n",
        "choicetwo": "varying the air supply to the main discharge tube.\n",
        "choicethree": "moving the butterfly valve through a separate linkage to the main throttle control.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ina hydraulic system, the reservoir is pressurized in order to:\n",
        "answer": "prevent pump cavitation\n",
        "choiceone": "seal the system\n",
        "choicetwo": "keep the hydraulic fluid at optimum temperature\n",
        "choicethree": "reduce fluid combustibility\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A modern Auxiliary Power Unit (APU) is designed to\nprovide power for ground starting of an engine. It also\nies both, in the air (subject to certification\nlimitations) and on the ground :\n\n",
        "answer": "air conditioning and electrical services.\n",
        "choiceone": "either air conditioning or electrical services, but never both at the same time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "air conditioning and electrical services (on the ground) electrical and hydraulic back-\nup services (in the air).\n",
        "choicethree": "air conditioning and thrust in the event of engine failure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term \u201cpressure cabin\" applies when an aeroplane :\n",
        "answer": "has the means to maintain cabin pressure higher than ambient pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "has the ability to maintain a constant cabin differential pressure at all flight altitudes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "has the ability to maintain a constant cabin altitude at all flight altitudes.\n",
        "choicethree": "is only pressurised in the area of the control cabin.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a bootstrap system, the purpose of the heat exchangers is to:\n",
        "answer": "cool bleed air and compressor air from the turbo refrigerator.\n",
        "choiceone": "allow a homogeneous temperature by mixing air flows from various air conditioning\ngroups in operation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cool bleed air.\n",
        "choicethree": "allow a steady compressor outlet temperature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the stator of a turbine, the speed V and static pressure Ps vary as follows:\n",
        "answer": "V increases, Ps decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "V decreases, Ps decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "V decreases, Ps increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "V increases, Ps increases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reason for using inverters in an electrical system is\n",
        "answer": "To change DC into AC.\n",
        "choiceone": "To avoid a short circuit.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To change the DC voltage.\n",
        "choicethree": "To change AC into DC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency of an AC generator is dependent on the :\n",
        "answer": "number of pairs of poles and the speed of the moving part.\n",
        "choiceone": "number of individual poles and the field strength.\n",
        "choicetwo": "field strength and the speed of the moving part.\n",
        "choicethree": "number of individual poles only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A unit that converts electrical DC into AC is:\n",
        "answer": "an inverter.\n",
        "choiceone": "a thermistor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an AC generator.\n",
        "choicethree": "a transformer rectifier unit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Apart from flight into known icing conditions, the intake system of a diesel engine:\n",
        "answer": "is never heated because a diesel engine is a injection engine.\n",
        "choiceone": "needs to be heated to prevent ice on the air filter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "needs to be heated at low power settings, due to vaporisation heat.\n",
        "choicethree": "is never heated because diesel engines operate at very high temperatures.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What criteria determines which engine is the \u2018critical\u2019 engine of a twin-engine airplane?\n",
        "answer": "The one with the center of thrust closest to the centerline of the fuselage.\n",
        "choiceone": "The one designated by the manufacturer which develops most usable thrust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The one with the center of thrust farthest from the centerline of the fuselage.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kind of compressor normally used as a turbocharger is:\n",
        "answer": "a radial compressor.\n",
        "choiceone": "an axial compressor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a hybrid compressor.\n",
        "choicethree": "a piston compressor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Smoke detectors fitted on transport aircraft are of the following type :\n",
        "answer": "optical or ionization\n",
        "choiceone": "electrical\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When selected to normal, the oxygen proportion of the\nairloxygen mixture supplied by the cockpit oxygen\nsystem regulator:\n",
        "answer": "increases when the altitude increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases when the altitude increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is constant whatever the altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "is 100 %.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A diluter demand oxygen regulator :\n",
        "answer": "delivers oxygen flow when inhaling.\n",
        "choiceone": "mixes air and oxygen in a passenger oxygen mask.\n",
        "choicetwo": "delivers oxygen flow only above FL 100.\n",
        "choicethree": "is only recommended for use with smoke in the cockpit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a lighted heliport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choiceone": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to starting the engine, the manifold pressure gauge usually\napproximately 29\" Hg. This is because the\n",
        "answer": "pressure within the manifold is the same as atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "pointer on the gauge is stuck at the full-power indication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "throttle is closed, trapping high air pressure in the manifold.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the maximum tolerance for the VOI ication when the CDI is centered and\nthe aircraft is directly over the airborne checkpoint?\n",
        "answer": "Plus or minus 6 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus 6degrees or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Plus or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which may lead to a power push-over in a gyroplane?\n",
        "answer": "Rotor force is removed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decreasing power too quickly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify runway remaining lighting on centerline lighting systems.\n",
        "answer": "Alternate red and white lights from 3,000 feet to 1,000 feet, then red lights to the end.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber lights from 3,000 feet to 1,000 feet, then alternate red and white lights to the\nend.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate red and white lights from 3,000 feet to the end of the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A possible result of using the emergency alternate source of static pressure inside the\ncabin of an unpressurized airplane is the\n",
        "answer": "altimeter may indicate an altitude higher than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "airspeed indicator may indicate less than normal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter may indicate an altitude lower than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "craft is flying from a cold air mass into a warm air mass. The TAS and true altitude\n\n",
        "answer": "Both increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "TAS increases, true altitude decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAS decreases, true altitude increases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the static vent became blocked during a descent, the altimeter would:\n",
        "answer": "over-read the correct altitude\n",
        "choiceone": "act normally\n",
        "choicetwo": "under-read the correct altitude\n",
        "choicethree": "read zero altitude\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The high Altitude Radio Altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicethree": "metric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The value of the compressibility error of an Airspeed Indicator (ASI) will:\n",
        "answer": "increase with increase in altitude and true airspeed;\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease, with decrease in density and increase with an increase in IAS;\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase with increase in true airspeed and decrease with increase in altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rectified Airspeed is:\n",
        "answer": "IAS corrected for instrument and pressure error.\n",
        "choiceone": "IAS corrected for density error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IAS corrected for density and compressibility errors.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The limits of the green scale of an airspeed indicator are:\n",
        "answer": "VS1 and VNO.\n",
        "choiceone": "VS1 and VMO.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VSO and VNE.\n",
        "choicethree": "VS1 and VNE.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A machmeter does not suffer from:\n",
        "answer": "compressibility error\n",
        "choiceone": "instrument error\n",
        "choicetwo": "position error\n",
        "choicethree": "error due to blockage of the static vent\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a CADC the output of vertical speed is achieved by means of:\n",
        "answer": "a measurement of the rate of change of altitude as sensed by the static pressure\ntransducer\n",
        "choiceone": "a dedicated vertical speed transducer\n",
        "choicetwo": "an integration of the CAS transducer output\n",
        "choicethree": "a combination of the outputs of the dynamic and static pressure transducers\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The deviations of a direct reading magnetic compass effected only by coefficients B and\nC are, 3 E on 230 (C) and 4 W on 130 (C), therefore the deviation on heading 315 (C) is:\n",
        "answer": "3,3E\n",
        "choiceone": "7,5W\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,3W\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The effect of decreasing rotor speed in the turn and slip indicator will cause:\n",
        "answer": "the turn indicator to under-read the rate of turn.\n",
        "choiceone": "the turn indicator to over-read and the slip indicator to under-read;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the turn indicator to under-indicate the angle of bank but will not effect the slip\nindicator;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a stabilised climbing turn at a constant rate, the instruments which indicate the\n\ncorrect pitch and bank are the:\n",
        "answer": "attitude indicator and turn-and-slip indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "vertical-speed indicator and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fuel enters a two-cycle engine through an\n",
        "answer": "intake port and intake valve.\n",
        "choiceone": "intake port and reed valve.\n",
        "choicetwo": "intake valve and reed valve.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formation of ice in a carburetor's throat is indicated by\n",
        "answer": "a drop in RPM, followed by rough engine operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "rough engine operation, followed by a decrease in oil pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a rapid increase in RPM, followed by rough engine operation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first indication of carburetor ice in an aircraft with a fixed-pitch propeller is\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in RPM.\n",
        "choiceone": "a decrease in manifold pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase in manifold pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum cumulative time that an emergency locator transmitter may be operated\nbefore the rechargeable battery must be recharged is\n",
        "answer": "60 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Regulations5 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "2-cycle engine thrust and fuel efficiency can be greatly compromised when\n",
        "answer": "exhaust systems are installed that are not specifically tuned for an engine.\n",
        "choiceone": "carbon deposits build up on exhaust valves.\n",
        "choicetwo": "intake valve lifters fail to pressurize and provide adequate fuel to the combustion\nchamber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The low temperature that causes carburetor ice in an engine equipped with a float-type\ncarburetor is normally the result of the\n",
        "answer": "vaporization of fuel and expansion of air in the carburetor.\n",
        "choiceone": "compression of air at the carburetor venturi.\n",
        "choicetwo": "freezing temperature of the air entering the carburetor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to an added safety factor, dual ignition systems also provide\n",
        "answer": "better combustion.\n",
        "choiceone": "increased spark plug life.\n",
        "choicetwo": "shorter engine warmup periods.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a characteristic of longitudinal instability?\n",
        "answer": "Pitch oscillations becoming progressively greater.\n",
        "choiceone": "Bank oscillations becoming progressively greater.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft constantly tries to pitch down.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Describe dynamic longitudinal stability.\n",
        "answer": "Motion about the lateral axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "Motion about the longitudinal axis.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Motion about the vertical axis.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If no corrective action is taken by the pilot as angle of ban!\nvertical component of lift and sink rate affected?\n\ncreased, how is the\n",
        "answer": "Lift decreases and the sink rate increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lift increases and the sink rate increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Lift decreases and the sink rate decreases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why must the angle of attack be increased during a turn to maintain altitude?\n",
        "answer": "Compensate for loss of vertical component of lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increase the horizontal component of lift equal to the vertical component.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Compensate for increase in drag.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the preheating coil used in hot air balloons is to\n",
        "answer": "vaporize the fuel for more efficient burner operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "prevent ice from forming in the fuel lines.\n",
        "choicetwo": "warm the fuel tanks for more efficient fuel flow.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During fuelling the automatic fuelling shut off valves will\n",
        "answer": "the fuel has reached a predetermined volume or mass.\n",
        "choiceone": "the surge vent tank is filled.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there is fire.\n",
        "choicethree": "fuelling system has reached a certain pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On modern transport aircraft, cockpit windows are protected against icing by :\n",
        "answer": "Electric heating.\n",
        "choiceone": "Vinyl coating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Anti-icing fluid.\n",
        "choicethree": "Rain repellent system.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a current is passed through a conductor,\n",
        "answer": "a force will be exerted on the conductor.\n",
        "choiceone": "the current will increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there will be no effect unless the conductor is moved.\n",
        "choicethree": "the intensity of the magnetic field will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As regards three-phase AC generators, the following conditions must be met for\nparalleling AC generators: 1. Equal voltage 2.Equal current 3.Equal frequencies 4.\nSame 5. Voltages of same phase The combination regrouping all the correct\nstatementsphase rotation is :\n",
        "answer": "1,3,4,5\n",
        "choiceone": "1,4,5\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,2,3,4\n",
        "choicethree": "1,3,5\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The part of a piston engine that transforms reciprocating movement into rotary motion\nis termed as the :\n",
        "answer": "crankshaft\n",
        "choiceone": "reduction gear\n",
        "choicetwo": "piston\n",
        "choicethree": "camshaft\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The power of a piston engine which will be measured by using a friction brake is :\n",
        "answer": "Brake horse power.\n",
        "choiceone": "Heat loss power.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicated horse power.\n",
        "choicethree": "Friction horse power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "in a piston engine turbo-supercharger centrifugal compressor :\n",
        "answer": "enters the eye of the impeller and leaves at a tangent to the periphery.\n",
        "choiceone": "enters at the periphery and leaves via the eye of the impeller.\n",
        "choicetwo": "enters at a tangent to the rotor and leaves via the stator.\n",
        "choicethree": "enters via the diffuser and is fed to the impeller at the optimum angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The state in which the breathing oxygen for the cockpit of jet transport aeroplanes is\nstored is :\n",
        "answer": "Gaseous.\n",
        "choiceone": "Chemical compound.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Liquid.\n",
        "choicethree": "Gaseous or chemical compound..\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the static pressure tubes are broken inside a pressurized cabin during a high-altitude\nflight, the altimeter would probably indicate\n",
        "answer": "lower than actual flight altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "sea level.\n",
        "choicetwo": "higher than actual flight altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 141.) Which displacement from the localizer centerline and\nglide slope at the 1,300-foot point from the runway is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "21 feet above the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "21 feet below the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the right of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "28 feet above the glide slope and approximately 250 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true about magnetic deviation of a compass?\n",
        "answer": "Deviation varies for different headings of the same aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Deviation is the same for all aircraft in the same locality.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deviation is different in a given aircraft in different localities.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to starting the engine, the manifold pressure gauge usually\napproximately 29\" Hg. This is because the\n",
        "answer": "pressure within the manifold is the same as atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "pointer on the gauge is stuck at the full-power indication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "throttle is closed, trapping high air pressure in the manifold.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When making an airborne VOR check, what is the maximum allowable tolerance\nbetween the two indicators of a dual VOR system (units independent of each other\nexcept the antenna)?\n\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees between the two indicated bearings of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus or minus 4 degrees when set to identical radials of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 degrees between the two indicated radials of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the runway distance remaining markers.\n",
        "answer": "Signs with increments of 1,000 feet distance remaining.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red markers laterally placed across the runway at 3,000 feet from the end.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow marker laterally placed across the runway with signs on the side denoting\ndistance to end.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify runway remaining lighting on centerline lighting systems.\n",
        "answer": "Alternate red and white lights from 3,000 feet to 1,000 feet, then red lights to the end.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber lights from 3,000 feet to 1,000 feet, then alternate red and white lights to the\nend.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate red and white lights from 3,000 feet to the end of the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, which would be correct about starting the rollout from a\nturn using a magnetic compass? Start the rollout\n",
        "answer": "after the compass indication passes south by a number of degrees approximately\nequal to the latitude minus the normal rollout lead.\n",
        "choiceone": "before the compass indication reaches south by a number of degrees approximately\nequal to the latitude over which the turn is made plus the pilot's normal lead.\n",
        "choicetwo": "after the compass indication passes south by a number of degrees approximately\nequal to the magnetic variation of the area over which the turn is made plus the\npilot's normal lead.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which procedure is recommended to prevent or overcome spatial disorientation?\n",
        "answer": "Rely entirely on the indications of the flight instruments.\n",
        "choiceone": "Avoid steep turns and rough control movements.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Reduce head and eye movements to the greatest extent possible.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pitot line is blocked, the VSI will:\n",
        "answer": "read normally\n",
        "choiceone": "read zero ftmm rate of climb/descent\n",
        "choicetwo": "over-read\n",
        "choicethree": "under-read\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot Head and Static Vent were blocked by ice, which instruments would be\naffected?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter, VSI and ASI would give inaccurate readings.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and Slip indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ASI would under read.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A simple pressure altimeter uses:\n",
        "answer": "static pressure fed into a gas tight casing, but outside a partially evacuated capsule\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure fed to an open capsule\n",
        "choicetwo": "pitot pressure fed to an open capsule\n",
        "choicethree": "static pressure fed outside a completely evacuated aneroid capsule.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reported QNH ofa given station is the:\n",
        "answer": "Station's barometric pressure corrected to mean sea level pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "actual barometric pressure measured at the station;\n",
        "choicetwo": "actual barometric pressure measured at sea level;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The high Altitude Radio Altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicethree": "metric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot opening is blocked, whi\nvent)?\n\nstruments would be affected (separate static\n",
        "answer": "ASI only.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and VSI.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ASI and VSI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is maintal\nprobable cause is:\n\n1g FL 120 in cloud. The ASI reading falls to zero. The most\n",
        "answer": "ASI malfunction.\n",
        "choiceone": "Static vent blocked by ice.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pitot head and static vent blocked by ice.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rectified Airspeed is:\n",
        "answer": "IAS corrected for instrument and pressure error.\n",
        "choiceone": "IAS corrected for density error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IAS corrected for density and compressibility errors.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ASI consists of a gas tight casing which has:\n",
        "answer": "pitot pressure fed into an open capsule and static pressure fed outside the capsule\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule and pitot pressure fed into a second\nopen capsule\n",
        "choicetwo": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule\n",
        "choicethree": "static pressure fed through a restrictive choke\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a stabilised climbing turn at a constant rate, the instruments which indicate the\n\ncorrect pitch and bank are the:\n",
        "answer": "attitude indicator and turn-and-slip indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "vertical-speed indicator and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tthe use of carburetor heat tends to\n",
        "answer": "decrease engine performance.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase engine performance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no effect on engine performance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of oxygen should be used to replenish an aircraft oxygen system?\n",
        "answer": "Aviation.\n",
        "choiceone": "Medical.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Industrial.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should help prevent aircraft induced oscillation on a gyroplane?-\n",
        "answer": "Adding a horizontal stabilizer.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increasing cyclic control sensitivity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Lowering the center of gravity below the thrust line.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Detonation occurs at high power settings when the\n",
        "answer": "fuel mixture explodes instead of burning progressively and evenly.\n",
        "choiceone": "fuel mixture is ignited too early by red-hot carbon deposits in the cylinder.\n",
        "choicetwo": "intake valve opens before the previous charge of fuel has finished burning in the\ncylinder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can turbulent air cause an increase in stalling speed of an airfoil?\n",
        "answer": "An abrupt change in relative wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "A decrease in angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sudden decrease in load factor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a hydraulic braking system, the accumulator is:\n",
        "answer": "an accumulator designed to restore brake energy in the event of a hydraulic failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "a damping type accumulator designed to take up the pressure fluctuations of the\nautomatic braking system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "designed to take up the hydraulic energy filtered by the anti-skid system in order to\nprevent wheel blocking.\n",
        "choicethree": "a buffer accumulator whose function is to assist the hydraulic system during high\nintensity braking.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On most modern airliners the cabin pressure is controlled by regulating the:\n",
        "answer": "Airflow leaving the cabin.\n",
        "choiceone": "Bleed air valve.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airflow entering the cabin.\n",
        "choicethree": "RPM of the engine.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the pneumatic supply system of a modern transport aircraft, the air pressure is\nregulated. This pressure regulation occurs just before the manifold by the :\n",
        "answer": "low pressure bleed air valve\n",
        "choiceone": "fan bleed air valve\n",
        "choicetwo": "intermediate pressure check-valve\n",
        "choicethree": "high pressure bleed air valve\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pressurization of tanks is maintained by the fuel:\n",
        "answer": "vent system.\n",
        "choiceone": "tank drains.\n",
        "choicetwo": "top off unit.\n",
        "choicethree": "dump system.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Constant Speed Drive aims at ensuring\n",
        "answer": "that the electric generator produces a constant frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "equal AC voltage from all generators.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that the starter-motor maintains a constant RPM not\n",
        "choicethree": "that the CSD remains at a constant RPM not withstanding the generator RPM\nwithstanding the acceleration of the engine.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an alternator rotor coil you can find :\n",
        "answer": "AC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only induced current.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dc.\n",
        "choicethree": "Three-phase AC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A unit that converts electrical DC into AC is:\n",
        "answer": "an inverter.\n",
        "choiceone": "a thermistor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an AC generator.\n",
        "choicethree": "a transformer rectifier unit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The working cycle of a four-stroke engine is :\n",
        "answer": "induction, compression, power, exhaust.\n",
        "choiceone": "induction, power, compression, exhaust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "compression induction, power, exhaust.\n",
        "choicethree": "induction, compression, expansion, power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The operating principle of magnetos in a piston engine ignition system consists of:\n",
        "answer": "opening the primary circuit in order to induce a low amperage, high voltage current,\nwhich is distributed to the spark plugs.\n",
        "choiceone": "obtaining a high amperage, low voltage current in order to generate the spark.\n",
        "choicetwo": "accumulating in a capacitor a low voltage current from the battery and inducing it as a\nhigh voltage current at the moment the spark is generated.\n",
        "choicethree": "creating a brief high intensity magnetic field that will be sent through the distributor\nat the appropriate time.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would be likely to increase the possi\noccurring within a piston engine ?\n\nity of detonation\n",
        "answer": "using too lean a fuel/air mixture ratio\n",
        "choiceone": "using an engine with a low compression ratio\n",
        "choicetwo": "slightly retarding the ignition timing\n",
        "choicethree": "the use of a fuel with a high octane rating as compared to the use of one with alow\noctane rating\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot normally uses the propeller autofeather system during :\n",
        "answer": "Take-off and landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cruise.\n",
        "choicethree": "Take-off.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the flow in a divergent (subsonic)\ngas turbine engine intake?\n\n|. The speed decreases in flow direction.\nll. The total pressure remains constant in flow direction.\n",
        "answer": "lis correct, Il is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "lis incorrect, Il is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lis correct, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "lis incorrect, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aircraft provided with resistance and capacitance variation type fire detection\nloops, a fire alarm is initiated by a temperature increase detected:\n",
        "answer": "at any isolated point of the loops or else generally on all the loops\n",
        "choiceone": "on at least one loop\n",
        "choicetwo": "only at an isolated point of the loops\n",
        "choicethree": "only in a uniform way along the loops\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "when the oxygen flows to the masks in the passenger cabin, the system is activated by\n",
        "answer": "firmly pulling the mask towards the face, after the cover has opened.\n",
        "choiceone": "activating the relevant switch in the cockpit.\n",
        "choicetwo": "firmly pulling the cover behind which the oxygen mask is stowed.\n",
        "choicethree": "pushing the mask against the face and breath normally.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 141.) Which displacement from the localizer centerline and\nglide slope at the 1,300-foot point from the runway is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "21 feet above the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "21 feet below the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the right of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "28 feet above the glide slope and approximately 250 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a military airport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choiceone": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choicetwo": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to starting the engine, the manifold pressure gauge usually\napproximately 29\" Hg. This is because the\n",
        "answer": "pressure within the manifold is the same as atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "pointer on the gauge is stuck at the full-power indication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "throttle is closed, trapping high air pressure in the manifold.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the advantage of a three-bar VASI?\n",
        "answer": "A normal glide angle is afforded both high and low cockpit aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Pilots have a choice of glide angles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The three-bar VASI is much more visible and can be used at a greater height.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Bourdon tube is used in:\n",
        "answer": "pressure sensors\n",
        "choiceone": "vibration detectors\n",
        "choicetwo": "smoke detectors\n",
        "choicethree": "turbine temperature probes\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot Head and Static Vent were blocked by ice, which instruments would be\naffected?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter, VSI and ASI would give inaccurate readings.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and Slip indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ASI would under read.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VSI may suffer from error due to:\n",
        "answer": "time lag, instrument calibration, blockage\n",
        "choiceone": "compressibility, time lag, blockage\n",
        "choicetwo": "density, aircraft manoeuvre, position of the static vent\n",
        "choicethree": "pitot blockage, static blockage, aircraft manoeuvre\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "level flight, it becomes necessary to use an alternate source of static pressure\nje the aircraft, with the cabin pressure being lower than static, the following\nvariations in instrument indication would be expected:\n\n",
        "answer": "the altimeter will read higher than normal, airspeed greater than normal and the\nvertical-speed indicator will momentarily show a climb;\n",
        "choiceone": "the altimeter will read higher than normal, airspeed will not change and the vertical-\nspeed indicator will momentarily show a descent;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the altimeter will read lower than normal, airspeed greater than normal and the\nvertical-speed indicator will momentarily show a climb and then a descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The location of the static vent which could provide the most accurate measurement of\nstatic pressure under variable flight conditions i\n\n",
        "answer": "One on each side of the aircraft where the system will compensate for variation of\naircraft attitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the Pitot head which encounters relatively undisturbed air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In the cockpit where it is not influenced by a variable angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When ambient temperature is warmer than standard at a particular altitude, the altimeter\nwill indicate:\n",
        "answer": "lower than true altitude;\n",
        "choiceone": "higher than true altitude;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same as true altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mach number is:\n",
        "answer": "the ratio of TAS to LSS at that temperature\n",
        "choiceone": "the ratio of IAS toLSS\n",
        "choicetwo": "the speed at which compressibility error must be calculated\n",
        "choicethree": "the ratio of EAS to LSS at that temperature\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following figures appear on an aeroplane deviation card: FOR MAGNETIC (45----90),\nSTEER COMPASS (38----92). The compass heading to steer to maintain a heading of\n075\u00b0 (M) is:\n",
        "answer": "74\n",
        "choiceone": "72\n",
        "choicetwo": "76\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The deviations of a direct reading magnetic compass effected only by coefficients B and\nC are, 3 E on 230 (C) and 4 W on 130 (C), therefore the deviation on heading 315 (C) is:\n",
        "answer": "3,3E\n",
        "choiceone": "7,5W\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,3W\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle of tilt of the rate gyro in a turn indicator is due to:\n",
        "answer": "primary precession which is generated by an aeroplanes rate of turn.\n",
        "choiceone": "the force in the horizontal plane generated by secondary precession balancing the\ntilt caused by primary precession;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the tension of the control spring opposing the angular tilt of the gyro;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft is rapidly accelerated in straight and level flight, or at take-off, what\ninherent precession characteristic will be displayed on the attitude indicator?\n",
        "answer": "The miniature aircraft would indicate a climb and bank.\n",
        "choiceone": "The miniature aircraft would indicate a descent.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The miniature aircraft would indicate a climb.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The effect of decreasing rotor speed in the turn and slip indicator will cause:\n",
        "answer": "the turn indicator to under-read the rate of turn.\n",
        "choiceone": "the turn indicator to over-read and the slip indicator to under-read;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the turn indicator to under-indicate the angle of bank but will not effect the slip\nindicator;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At a low bank angle, the measurement of rate-of-turn actually consists in measuring the:\n",
        "answer": "yaw rate of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "pitch rate of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "roll rate of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicethree": "bank of the aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A stall warning system is based on measuring the:\n",
        "answer": "angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "TAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "attitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum cumulative time that an emergency locator transmitter may be operated\nbefore the rechargeable battery must be recharged is\n",
        "answer": "60 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Regulations5 minutes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Detonation in an aircraft engine is most likely to occur whenever the\n",
        "answer": "engine is operated under conditions which cause the fuel mixture to burn\ninstantaneously.\n",
        "choiceone": "fuel/air ratio is such that the mixture burns extremely slow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fuel being used is of a higher grade than recommended by the engine manufacturer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true regarding fouling of the spark plugs of an aircraft engine?\n",
        "answer": "Spark plug fouling results from operating with an excessively rich mixture.\n",
        "choiceone": "Carbon fouling of the spark plugs is caused primarily by operating an engine at\nexcessively high cylinder head temperatures.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Excessive heat in the combustion chamber of a cylinder causes oil to form on the\ncenter electrode of a spark plug and this fouls the plug.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whatis the reason for variations in geometric pitch along a propeller or rotor blade?\n",
        "answer": "It permits a relatively constant angle of attack along its length when in cruising flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "It prevents the portion of the blade near the hub or root from stalling during cruising\nflight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It permits a relatively constant angle of incidence along its length when in cruising\nflight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the different types of aircraft structures, the shell structures efficiently transmit\nthe: 1. normal bending stresses 2. tangent bending stresses 3. torsional moment 4.\nshear stresses The combination regrouping all the correct statements is :\n\n",
        "answer": "1,2,3\n",
        "choiceone": "2,3,4\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,2,4\n",
        "choicethree": "1,3,4\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the door operation of a transport airplane equipped with evacuation slides\ncontrolled from the outside, the slide:\n\n",
        "answer": "is disarmed automatically.\n",
        "choiceone": "unfolds and becomes inflated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unfolds but does not become inflated.\n",
        "choicethree": "becomes inflated in its packboard thus preventing its unfolding.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hydraulic fluids used in systems of large modern airliners are:\n",
        "answer": "Phosphate ester base fluids.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mineral base fluids.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Water base fluids.\n",
        "choicethree": "Vegetable base fluids.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the profile grooves or the tread of a new aircraft tyre are worn, the tyre can be:\n",
        "answer": "Repaired several times.\n",
        "choiceone": "repaired once.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Never repaired.\n",
        "choicethree": "Used on the nose wheel only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thermal plugs are installed in:\n",
        "answer": "wheel rims.\n",
        "choiceone": "cabin windows.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cargo compartments.\n",
        "choicethree": "fire warning systems.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A torsion link assembly is installed on the landing gear to :\n",
        "answer": "avoid rotation of the piston rod relative to the gear oleo strut.\n",
        "choiceone": "absorb the spring tension.\n",
        "choicetwo": "control the wheels.\n",
        "choicethree": "lock the landing gear.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pressure in the cabin tends to become lower than the outside ambient air pressure\nthe:\n",
        "answer": "negative pressure relief valve will open.\n",
        "choiceone": "outflow valve open completely.\n",
        "choicetwo": "air cycle machine will stop.\n",
        "choicethree": "negative pressure relief valve will close\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an aeroplane utilising a constant frequency AC power supply, DC power is obtained\nfrom a:\n",
        "answer": "Transformer Rectifier Unit.\n",
        "choiceone": "rotary converter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "static inverter.\n",
        "choicethree": "3 phase current transformer unit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A test to assess the state of charge of a lead-acid battery would involve :\n",
        "answer": "comparing the \u201con-load\u201d and \u201coff-load\u201d battery voltages.\n",
        "choiceone": "checking the level of the electrolyte.\n",
        "choicetwo": "checking the discharge current of the battery \"on-load\u201d.\n",
        "choicethree": "checking the battery voltage \u201coff-load\u201d.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In jet aeroplanes the \u2018thermal anti-ice system\u2019 is primary supplied by\n",
        "answer": "bleed air from the engines.\n",
        "choiceone": "ram air, heated via a heat exchanger.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the APU.\n",
        "choicethree": "turbo compressors.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Engine Pressure Ratio (EPR) is the ratio of:\n",
        "answer": "the total turbine outlet pressure to the total compressor inlet pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "the total turbine inlet pressure to the total compressor outlet pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the total turbine outlet pressure to the total compressor outlet pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "the total turbine inlet pressure to the total compressor inlet pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft whose maximum approved configuration for passenger seats is 10 seats\nmust be equipped with:\n",
        "answer": "one fire-extinguisher in the cockpit and three fire-extinguishers in the passenger\ncabin.\n",
        "choiceone": "three fire-extinguishers in the passenger cabin only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "two fire-extinguishers in the cockpit and two fire-extinguishers in the passenger\ncabin.\n",
        "choicethree": "one fire-extinguisher in the cockpit and two fire-extinguishers in the passenger\ncabin.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Continuous loop fire detector systems operate on the principle that an increase in\ntemperature produces:\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in resistance\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase in resistance\n",
        "choicetwo": "a decrease in the reference current\n",
        "choicethree": "a decrease in pressure\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A diluter demand oxygen regulator :\n",
        "answer": "delivers oxygen flow when inhaling.\n",
        "choiceone": "mixes air and oxygen in a passenger oxygen mask.\n",
        "choicetwo": "delivers oxygen flow only above FL 100.\n",
        "choicethree": "is only recommended for use with smoke in the cockpit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When air is compressed for pressurization purposes, the percentage oxygen content is:\n",
        "answer": "unaffected.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreased.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increased.\n",
        "choicethree": "dependent on the degree of pressurisation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a pressurized aircraft, the first-aid (therapeutic) oxygen is designed to:\n",
        "answer": "give medical assistance to passengers with pathological respiratory disorders.\n",
        "choiceone": "protect the flight crew and cabin attendants against fumes and noxious gases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "protect all the occupants against the effects of accidental depressurisation.\n",
        "choicethree": "protect certain passengers, and is only carried on board for these people.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the maximum tolerance for the VOI ication when the CDI is centered and\nthe aircraft is directly over the airborne checkpoint?\n",
        "answer": "Plus or minus 6 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus 6degrees or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Plus or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A possible result of using the emergency alternate source of static pressure inside the\ncabin of an unpressurized airplane is the\n",
        "answer": "altimeter may indicate an altitude higher than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "airspeed indicator may indicate less than normal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter may indicate an altitude lower than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 85.) What is the mi\nWASH2 WAGGE Departure?\n\njum rate climb per NM to 9,000 feet required for the\n",
        "answer": "400 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "750 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "875 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify taxi leadoff lights associated with the centerline lighting system.\n",
        "answer": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to a point\non the exit.\n",
        "choiceone": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\ncenterline of the taxiway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\nedge of the taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a manifold pressure gauge consistently registers atmospheric pressure, the caus:\nprobably:\n",
        "answer": "leak in pressure gauge line.\n",
        "choiceone": "an aneroid capsule which is not properly calibrated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a very high atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "a very low atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "level flight, it becomes necessary to use an alternate source of static pressure\nje the aircraft, with the cabin pressure being lower than static, the following\nvariations in instrument indication would be expected:\n\n",
        "answer": "the altimeter will read higher than normal, airspeed greater than normal and the\nvertical-speed indicator will momentarily show a climb;\n",
        "choiceone": "the altimeter will read higher than normal, airspeed will not change and the vertical-\nspeed indicator will momentarily show a descent;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the altimeter will read lower than normal, airspeed greater than normal and the\nvertical-speed indicator will momentarily show a climb and then a descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Concerning the pitot and static system, the static pressure error:\n",
        "answer": "is caused by disturbed airflow around the static ports.\n",
        "choiceone": "is a direct effect of heating of the static ports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "affects the alternate static port only.\n",
        "choicethree": "is a direct effect of a blockage of the static port.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a pre-flight check the following details were noted: Airfield Elevation (4800 ft)-\nApron Elevation (4780 ft)- Height of static vent above ground ( 25 ft)- Altimeter reading\n(QFE)( 35 ft)\n",
        "answer": "30 ft underread.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 ft underread\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 ft underread\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a servo-assisted altimeter, the secondary winding from the E bar provides an\nelectrical current direct to the:\n",
        "answer": "amplifier\n",
        "choiceone": "capsule stack\n",
        "choicetwo": "two phase motor\n",
        "choicethree": "AC input lines of the primary winding\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "VFE is the maximum speed:\n",
        "answer": "with the flaps extended.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the flaps extended in the landing configuration.\n",
        "choicetwo": "with the flaps extended in the take-off configuration.\n",
        "choicethree": "at which the flaps can be operated when flying in turbulences.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The percentage error due to the positioning of the static vent\n",
        "answer": "the same in the Machmeter as in the ASI\n",
        "choiceone": "greater in the ASI than in the Machmeter\n",
        "choicetwo": "greater in the Machmeter than in the ASI\n",
        "choicethree": "either greater or smaller when comparing the ASI and the Machmeter,\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aircraft climbs at a constant IAS in the standard atmosphere, the Mach number will:\n",
        "answer": "increase\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease\n",
        "choicetwo": "remain constant\n",
        "choicethree": "remain constant unless the aircraft flies through an inversion\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A machmeter does not suffer from:\n",
        "answer": "compressibility error\n",
        "choiceone": "instrument error\n",
        "choicetwo": "position error\n",
        "choicethree": "error due to blockage of the static vent\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a combined Machiairspeed indicator the purpose of the barber's pole is to indicate:\n",
        "answer": "Vmo, and this value increases at high altitudes\n",
        "choiceone": "Vmo, and this is a fixed value at all altitudes\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vmo, and this value decreases at high altitudes\n",
        "choicethree": "the maximum safe airspeed with the flaps/slats extended\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rotor of the DGI spins up and away from the pilot when 090 is ir\nlatitude compensation nut situated on the near right hand side of the inner gimbal from\nthe gyro axis, has been set to give zero drift on the ground at the equator. To\ncompensate for earth rotation at 30 S the latitude compensating nut:\n",
        "answer": "must be adjusted outwards;\n",
        "choiceone": "must be adjusted inwards;\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not adjusted since the latitude nut can only be used to correct for apparent\nwander in the northern hemisphere.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle of tilt of the rate gyro in a turn indicator is due to:\n",
        "answer": "primary precession which is generated by an aeroplanes rate of turn.\n",
        "choiceone": "the force in the horizontal plane generated by secondary precession balancing the\ntilt caused by primary precession;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the tension of the control spring opposing the angular tilt of the gyro;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering a flight director of the command bars type:\n",
        "answer": "the horizontal bar is associated with the pitch channel.\n",
        "choiceone": "the horizontal bar is associated with the roll channel.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the vertical bar is associated with the pitch channel.\n",
        "choicethree": "the vertical bar may be associated with the pitch channel.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stall warning computer uses the following dat\n\n1- mass of the aeroplane\n2- angle of attack\n\n3- wing flap deflection\n\n4- position of the landing gear\n5- TAT\n\n6- pressure altitude\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:\n",
        "answer": "2,3\n",
        "choiceone": "2,3,5\n",
        "choicetwo": "1, 2,3,4\n",
        "choicethree": "1, 2,3, 4,5,6\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The radio altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "centimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "millimetric\n",
        "choicethree": "metric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The high Altitude Radio Altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicethree": "metric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The voltage regulator of a DC generator is connected in:\n",
        "answer": "series with the shunt field coil.\n",
        "choiceone": "series with the armature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "parallel with the shunt field coil.\n",
        "choicethree": "series with the equalising coil.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cabin air for modern airplanes is usually supplied by:\n",
        "answer": "main engine compressors.\n",
        "choiceone": "piston compressors.\n",
        "choicetwo": "roots type compressors.\n",
        "choicethree": "single radial compressors.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of an anti-servo tab?\n",
        "answer": "Prevent a control surface from moving to a full-deflection position due to\naerodynamic forces.\n",
        "choiceone": "Move the flight controls in the event of manual reversion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Reduce control forces by deflecting in the proper direction to move a primary flight\ncontrol.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The wing of an aircraft in flight, powered by engines\nlocated under the wing, is subjected to a bending\nmoment which causes its leading edge, from the wing\nroot to the wing tip, to operate in:\n",
        "answer": "compression, then in tension.\n",
        "choiceone": "tension, then in compression.\n",
        "choicetwo": "tension.\n",
        "choicethree": "compression.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When ambient temperature is warmer than standard at a particular altitude, the altimeter\nwill indicate:\n",
        "answer": "lower than true altitude;\n",
        "choiceone": "higher than true altitude;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same as true altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb with the autopilot engaged in the V/S mode (holding of vertical speed),\nthe auto-throttle:\n",
        "answer": "can be operated in the SPEED mode (holding of IAS).\n",
        "choiceone": "can be operated in the N1/ EPR mode (holding of N1 or EPR).\n",
        "choicetwo": "can be operated in the SPEED (holding of IAS ) or N1 (holding of N1) modes.\n",
        "choicethree": "is not available.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Upon which factor does wing loading during a level coordinated turn in smooth air\ndepend?\n",
        "answer": "Angle of bank.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rate of turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "True airspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming cabin differential pressure has attained the required value in normal flight\nconditions, if flight altitude is maintained:\n",
        "answer": "a constant mass air flow is permitted through the cabin.\n",
        "choiceone": "the pressurisation system ceases to function until leakage reduces the pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the outflow valves will move to the fully closed position.\n",
        "choicethree": "the outflow valves will move to the fully open position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which maximum range factor decreases as weight decreases ?\n",
        "answer": "Airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term \"Bootstrap\", when used to identify a cabin air conditioning and pressurisation\nsystem, refers to the :\n",
        "answer": "cold air unit (air cycle machine) arrangement.\n",
        "choiceone": "source of the charge air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "means by which pressurisation is controlled.\n",
        "choicethree": "charge air across the inter-cooler heat exchanger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cFrequency wild\" in relation to a AC generation system means the generator :\n",
        "answer": "output frequency varies with engine speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "output frequency is too low.\n",
        "choicetwo": "output frequency is too high.\n",
        "choicethree": "voltage regulator is out of adjustment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an altimeter indicates 3500 FT with the actual QNH of 1004, 7 hPa set, the approximate\npressure altitude i\n\n",
        "answer": "3745 FT\n",
        "choiceone": "3500 FT\n",
        "choicetwo": "3255 FT\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which stroke of a reciprocating engine is the gaseous mixture expanding within\nthe cylinder?\n",
        "answer": "Power.\n",
        "choiceone": "Intake.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Compression.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flying from warm\n(RAS) would:\n\nto cold air at a constant TAS. The Rectified Air Speed\n",
        "answer": "Increase\n",
        "choiceone": "Remain constant\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decrease\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The elevation of aerodrome A is 390 feet and aerodrome B 450 feet. The pilot of an\naeroplane at A, sets the altimeter to read aerodrome elevation and then flies to B without\nresetting the altimeter. Aerodrome pressure at A on departure was 1004 hPa. On\nlanding at B the altimeter reads 630 feet, and assuming 1 hPa is 30 feet, the QNH is\napproximately:\n",
        "answer": "1011 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "1013 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "1019 hPa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an altimeter is changed from 30.11\" Hg to 29.96\" Hg,\nindicated altitude change and by what value?\n\nwhich direction will the\n\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter will indicate 150 feet lower.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altimeter will indicate 15 feet lower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altimeter will indicate 150 feet higher.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Electrical bonding of an aircraft is used to: 1. protect the aircraft against lightning effects.\n2. reset the electrostatic potential of the aircraft to a value approximating 0 volt 3. reduce\nradio interference on radiocommunication systems 4. set the aircraft to a single\npotential The combination regrouping all the correct statements\n",
        "answer": "1,3,4\n",
        "choiceone": "1,2,3\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,4\n",
        "choicethree": "2,4\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the movement of the center of pressure when the wingtips of a sweptwing\nairplane are shock-stalled first?\n",
        "answer": "Inward and forward.\n",
        "choiceone": "Inward and aft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Outward and forward.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A relay is :\n",
        "answer": "An electromagnetically operated switch.\n",
        "choiceone": "A switch specially designed for AC circuits.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An electrical energy conversion unit.\n",
        "choicethree": "An electrical security switch.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ring laser gyro can measure:\n",
        "answer": "rotation about its sensitive axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "accelerations about its sensitive axis.\n",
        "choicetwo": "rotation in all directions.\n",
        "choicethree": "accelerations in all direction.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Running a fuel tank dry before switching tanks is not a good practice because\n",
        "answer": "the engine-driven fuel pump or electric fuel boost pump draw air into the fuel system\nand cause vapor lock.\n",
        "choiceone": "any foreign matter in the tank will be pumped into the fuel system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the engine-driven fuel pump is lubricated by fuel and operating on a dry tank may\ncause pump failure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a CADC the output of vertical speed is achieved by means of:\n",
        "answer": "a measurement of the rate of change of altitude as sensed by the static pressure\ntransducer\n",
        "choiceone": "a dedicated vertical speed transducer\n",
        "choicetwo": "an integration of the CAS transducer output\n",
        "choicethree": "a combination of the outputs of the dynamic and static pressure transducers\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A passenger emergency mask is a:\n",
        "answer": "continuous flow mask and cannot be used if there is smoke in the cabin.\n",
        "choiceone": "continuous flow mask and can be used if there is smoke in the cabin.\n",
        "choicetwo": "mask with flow on request and can be used if there is smoke.\n",
        "choicethree": "mask with flow on request and cannot be used if there is smoke in the cabin.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about structural design principles are correct or incorrect?\n|. In structural design, fail safe implies parallel structural parts.\n\nIl In structural design, safe life implies the structure will never fail during a declared time\nperiod or number of cycles.\n\n",
        "answer": "lis correct, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "lis incorrect, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lis correct, Il is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "lis incorrect, Il is correct.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of a diluter demand regulator in an oxygen system is to :\n",
        "answer": "deliver oxygen flow when inhaling.\n",
        "choiceone": "deliver oxygen flow only above FL 100.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is only recommended with smoke in the cockpit.\n",
        "choicethree": "mix air and oxygen in a passenger oxygen mask.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The radio altimeter is required to indicate zero height AGL as the main wheels touch\ndown on the runway. For this reason, it is necessary to:\n",
        "answer": "compensate for residual height and cable length.\n",
        "choiceone": "adjust the gross height according to the aeroplane instantaneous pitch.\n",
        "choicetwo": "change the display scale in short final, in order to have a precise readout.\n",
        "choicethree": "have a specific radio altimeter dedicated to automatic landing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a turbine engine, the term self-sustaining speed means the engine\n",
        "answer": "will run without any external assistance.\n",
        "choiceone": "operates most efficiently in the cruise...\n",
        "choicetwo": "will enable the generators to supply bus-bar voltage.\n",
        "choicethree": "is designed to idle after starting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A gyroplane will have the greatest tendency to roll during\n",
        "answer": "horizontal flight at high speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "climbing flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "descending flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aeroplane, spoilers are :\n",
        "answer": "upper wing surface devices, their deflection is symmetrical or asymmetrical.\n",
        "choiceone": "lower wing surface devices, their deflection is always asymmetrical.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lower wing surface devices, their deflection is symmetrical or asymmetrical.\n",
        "choicethree": "upper wing surface devices, their deflection is always asymmetrical.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pressure Altitude 8000 ft QNH Altitude 7500 ft OAT +30\u00b0C Terrain elevation 5700 ft.\nThe approximate absolute altitude is:\n",
        "answer": "2650 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "500 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "1800 ft\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cNose wheel shimmy\" may be described as :\n",
        "answer": "a possibly damaging vibration of the nose wheel when moving on the ground.\n",
        "choiceone": "the oscillatory movement of the nose wheel when extended prior to landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the amount of free movement of the nose wheel before steering takes effect.\n",
        "choicethree": "aircraft vibration caused by the nose wheel upon extension of the gear.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Concerning carburetor icing, which statement is true?\n",
        "answer": "Carburetor icing would most likely form when the air temperature is between -\n7degrees C and 21 degrees C and visible moisture or high humidity is present.\n",
        "choiceone": "The first indication of carburetor icing, in an aircraft equipped with a fixed-pitch\npropeller, is a decrease in manifold pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Carburetor icing will form in a carburetor whenever the ambient temperature is\nbelow freezing with a reduced or closed throttle setting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which maximum range factor decreases as weight decreases ?\n",
        "answer": "Airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Anon-cantilever wing\n\n",
        "answer": "a wing supported by braces or a strut connected to the fuselage.\n",
        "choiceone": "a wing planform other than rectangular.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a high wing configuration.\n",
        "choicethree": "a low wing configuration.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fuselage of an aircraft consists, among others, of stringers whose purpose is to:\n",
        "answer": "assist the skin in absorbing the longitudinal traction-compression stresses.\n",
        "choiceone": "withstand the shear stresses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "provide sound and thermal isolation.\n",
        "choicethree": "integrate the strains due to pressurization to which the skin is subjected and convert\nthem into a tensile stress.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the door operation of a transport airplane equipped with evacuation slides\ncontrolled from the outside, the slide:\n\n",
        "answer": "is disarmed automatically.\n",
        "choiceone": "unfolds and becomes inflated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unfolds but does not become inflated.\n",
        "choicethree": "becomes inflated in its packboard thus preventing its unfolding.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thermal plugs are installed in:\n",
        "answer": "wheel rims.\n",
        "choiceone": "cabin windows.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cargo compartments.\n",
        "choicethree": "fire warning systems.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The secondary Surveillance Radar (SSR) uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "centimetric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicethree": "myriametric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a ditching situation, the passenger life jackets will be inflated :\n",
        "answer": "when leaving the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "immediately on the opening of the exits.\n",
        "choicetwo": "immediately on ditching.\n",
        "choicethree": "once the passengers are in the water.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of a ditching control is to:\n",
        "answer": "close the outflow valve(s).\n",
        "choiceone": "achieve rapid depressurisation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "open the outflow valve(s).\n",
        "choicethree": "direct pressurisation air to the flotation bags.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cabin air for modern airplanes is usually supplied by:\n",
        "answer": "main engine compressors.\n",
        "choiceone": "piston compressors.\n",
        "choicetwo": "roots type compressors.\n",
        "choicethree": "single radial compressors.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pressure in the cabin tends to become lower than the outside ambient air pressure\nthe:\n",
        "answer": "negative pressure relief valve will open.\n",
        "choiceone": "outflow valve open completely.\n",
        "choicetwo": "air cycle machine will stop.\n",
        "choicethree": "negative pressure relief valve will close\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A feeder fault on a direct current circuit results from a flux unbalance between the:\n",
        "answer": "voltage coil and the series winding turn.\n",
        "choiceone": "shunt exciter and the series winding turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "voltage coil and the series winding.\n",
        "choicethree": "generator and the series winding turn.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The compression ratio of a piston engine is the ratio of the:\n",
        "answer": "volume of the cylinder with the piston at bottom dead centre to that with the piston at\ntop dead centre.\n",
        "choiceone": "weight of the air induced to its weight after compression.\n",
        "choicetwo": "diameter of the bore to the piston stroke.\n",
        "choicethree": "area of the piston to the cylinder volume.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A CSD unit which has been disconnected in flight :\n",
        "answer": "may be reset on the ground only, after engine shut-down.\n",
        "choiceone": "automatically resets in flight providing engine rpm is below a given value.\n",
        "choicetwo": "automatically resets at engine shut-down.\n",
        "choicethree": "may be reset in flight using the reset mechanism.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aircraft provided with resistance and capacitance variation type fire detection\nloops, a fire alarm is initiated by a temperature increase detected:\n",
        "answer": "at any isolated point of the loops or else generally on all the loops\n",
        "choiceone": "on at least one loop\n",
        "choicetwo": "only at an isolated point of the loops\n",
        "choicethree": "only in a uniform way along the loops\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Smoke detectors fitted on transport aircraft are of the following type :\n",
        "answer": "optical or ionization\n",
        "choiceone": "electrical\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A public transport aircraft is operated at FL 390. The total number of oxygen dispensing\nunits and outlets in the cabin must be at least the same as the total number of :\n",
        "answer": "seats exceeded by 10%.\n",
        "choiceone": "passengers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "passengers exceeded by 10%.\n",
        "choicethree": "seats.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The state in which the breathing oxygen for the cockpit of jet transport aeroplanes is\nstored is :\n",
        "answer": "Gaseous.\n",
        "choiceone": "Chemical compound.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Liquid.\n",
        "choicethree": "Gaseous or chemical compound..\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a pressurized aircraft, the first-aid (therapeutic) oxygen is designed to:\n",
        "answer": "give medical assistance to passengers with pathological respiratory disorders.\n",
        "choiceone": "protect the flight crew and cabin attendants against fumes and noxious gases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "protect all the occupants against the effects of accidental depressurisation.\n",
        "choicethree": "protect certain passengers, and is only carried on board for these people.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 85.) What is the mi\nWASH2 WAGGE Departure?\n\njum rate climb per NM to 9,000 feet required for the\n",
        "answer": "400 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "750 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "875 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the advantage of a three-bar VASI?\n",
        "answer": "A normal glide angle is afforded both high and low cockpit aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Pilots have a choice of glide angles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The three-bar VASI is much more visible and can be used at a greater height.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, a magnetic compass will normally indicate a turn toward\n\nthe north if\n",
        "answer": "an aircraft is accelerated while on an east or west heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "a left turn is entered from a west heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an aircraft is decelerated while on an east or west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A possible result of using the emergency alternate source of static pressure inside the\ncabin of an unpressurized airplane is the\n",
        "answer": "altimeter may indicate an altitude higher than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "airspeed indicator may indicate less than normal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter may indicate an altitude lower than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, if an aircrat\ncompass will normally indicate\n\naccelerated or decelerated, the magnetic\n",
        "answer": "correctly when on a north or south heading while either accelerating or decelerating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a turn momentarily, with changes in airspeed on any heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a turn toward the south while accelerating on a west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 85 and 86.) Which combination of indications confirm that you are\napproaching WAGGE intersection slightly to the right of the LOC centerline on\ndeparture?\n\n",
        "answer": "2 and 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 and 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 and 4.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The RPM indicator of a piston engine can include a small red arc within the arc normally\nused (green arc).\nIn the RPM range corresponding to this small red arc the:\n",
        "answer": "propeller generates vibration, continuous rating is forbidden\n",
        "choiceone": "rating is the maximum possible in continuous mode\n",
        "choicetwo": "rating is the minimum usable in cruise\n",
        "choicethree": "propeller efficiency is minimum at this rating\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Concerning the pitot and static system, the static pressure error:\n",
        "answer": "is caused by disturbed airflow around the static ports.\n",
        "choiceone": "is a direct effect of heating of the static ports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "affects the alternate static port only.\n",
        "choicethree": "is a direct effect of a blockage of the static port.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Transition level is obtained from:\n",
        "answer": "ATC or VOR ATIS.\n",
        "choiceone": "Jeppesen or Aerad flight guides.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1500 feet above airfield elevation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Static air temperature is:\n",
        "answer": "(a) the correct temperature of the ambient air surrounding the aircraft but unaffected\nby the presence or movement of the aircraft\n",
        "choiceone": "(b) the correct temperature of the air surrounding the aircraft as affected by the\npresence or movement of the aircraft\n",
        "choicetwo": "(c) the temperature of the aircraft skin measured at a stagnation point\n",
        "choicethree": "(d) the temperature of the air within the static line\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To allow for changes in the viscosity of the air, the VSI employs:\n",
        "answer": "a restrictive choke\n",
        "choiceone": "a logarithmic scale\n",
        "choicetwo": "diaphragm overload stops\n",
        "choicethree": "a complex capillary/orifice choke system\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A machmeter does not suffer from:\n",
        "answer": "compressibility error\n",
        "choiceone": "instrument error\n",
        "choicetwo": "position error\n",
        "choicethree": "error due to blockage of the static vent\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The percentage error due to the positioning of the static vent\n",
        "answer": "the same in the Machmeter as in the ASI\n",
        "choiceone": "greater in the ASI than in the Machmeter\n",
        "choicetwo": "greater in the Machmeter than in the ASI\n",
        "choicethree": "either greater or smaller when comparing the ASI and the Machmeter,\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The deviations of a direct reading magnetic compass effected only by coefficients B and\nC are, 3 E on 230 (C) and 4 W on 130 (C), therefore the deviation on heading 315 (C) is:\n",
        "answer": "3,3E\n",
        "choiceone": "7,5W\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,3W\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following figures appear on an aeroplane deviation card: FOR MAGNETIC (45----90),\nSTEER COMPASS (38----92). The compass heading to steer to maintain a heading of\n075\u00b0 (M) is:\n",
        "answer": "74\n",
        "choiceone": "72\n",
        "choicetwo": "76\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the building principle of a gyroscope, the best efficiency is obtained through the\nconcentration of the mass:\n",
        "answer": "on the periphery and with a high rotational speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "close to the axis and with a high rotational speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the periphery and with a low rotational speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "close to the axis and with a low rotational speed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The gyroscope of a turn indicator has:\n\n(NB: the rotor spin axis is not counted for the number of degrees of freedom of the gyro)\n",
        "answer": "1 degree of freedom.\n",
        "choiceone": "0 degree of freedom.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 degrees of freedom.\n",
        "choicethree": "3 degrees of freedom.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering a flight director of the command bars type:\n",
        "answer": "the horizontal bar is associated with the pitch channel.\n",
        "choiceone": "the horizontal bar is associated with the roll channel.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the vertical bar is associated with the pitch channel.\n",
        "choicethree": "the vertical bar may be associated with the pitch channel.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why must the angle of attack be increased during a turn to maintain altitude?\n",
        "answer": "Compensate for loss of vertical component of lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increase the horizontal component of lift equal to the vertical component.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Compensate for increase in drag.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a steep turn to the left, when using spoilers ...\n",
        "answer": "The right aileron will descend, the left one will ascend, the right spoiler will retract\nand the left one will extend.\n",
        "choiceone": "The right aileron will descend, the left one will ascend, the right spoiler will extend\nand the left one will retract.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The right aileron will ascend, the left one will descend, the right spoiler will extend\nand the left one will retract.\n",
        "choicethree": "The right aileron will ascend, the left one will descend, the right spoiler will retract\nand the left one will extend.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What characteristic should exist if an airplane is loaded to the rear of its CG range?\n",
        "answer": "Unstable about the lateral axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "Sluggish in aileron control.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sluggish in rudder control.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mixture control for a carburettor achieves its control by:\n",
        "answer": "varying the fuel supply to the main discharge tube.\n",
        "choiceone": "altering the depression on the main discharge tube.\n",
        "choicetwo": "varying the air supply to the main discharge tube.\n",
        "choicethree": "moving the butterfly valve through a separate linkage to the main throttle control.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to energy storage, the accumulator of the hydraulic system is used :\n",
        "answer": "for damping pressure surges in the system.\n",
        "choiceone": "for pressure storage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "as a pressure relief valve.\n",
        "choicethree": "for fluid storage.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A reverse thrust door warning light on the flight deck instrument panel illuminates when:\n",
        "answer": "the reverser doors are unlocked.\n",
        "choiceone": "the reverser doors are locked.\n",
        "choicetwo": "reverse has been selected but the doors have remained locked.\n",
        "choicethree": "the reverser doors have moved to the reverse thrust position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In accordance with Civil Aviation Regulations , each occupant of the cockpit seats on\nduty in a non-pressurized airplane must have an oxygen supply reserve for the entire\nflight time at pressure altitudes greater than:\n",
        "answer": "10000 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "14000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12500 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "13000 ft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a normal pressurised climb after take-off:\n",
        "answer": "cabin pressure decreases more slowly than atmospheric pressure\n",
        "choiceone": "absolute cabin pressure increases to compensate for the fall in pressure outside the\naircraft\n",
        "choicetwo": "the pressurisation system is inoperative until an altitude of 10 000 feet is reached\n",
        "choicethree": "the cabin differential pressure is maintained constant\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most widely used AC frequency in aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "400 Hi.\n",
        "choiceone": "115 Hz.\n",
        "choicetwo": "50 Hz.\n",
        "choicethree": "60 Hz.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a current is passed through a conductor whi\nmagnetic field:\n\npositioned perpendicular to a\n",
        "answer": "a force will be exerted on the conductor.\n",
        "choiceone": "the current will increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there will be no effect unless the conductor is moved.\n",
        "choicethree": "the intensity of the magnetic field will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an aircraft equipped with a DC main power system, AC for instrument operation may\nbe obtained from :\n",
        "answer": "an inverter.\n",
        "choiceone": "a contactor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a TRU.\n",
        "choicethree": "a rectifier.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The function of a constant speed drive (CSD) in an AC generating system is to :\n",
        "answer": "drive the generator at a constant speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "vary generator rpm in order to compensate for various AC loads.\n",
        "choicetwo": "directly maintain a constant proportion between the rpm of an engine and a\ngenerator.\n",
        "choicethree": "vary the engine rpm (within limits) to compensate for various AC loads.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As regards three-phase AC generators, the following conditions must be met for\nparalleling AC generators: 1. Equal voltage 2.Equal current 3.Equal frequencies 4.\nSame 5. Voltages of same phase The combination regrouping all the correct\nstatementsphase rotation is :\n",
        "answer": "1,3,4,5\n",
        "choiceone": "1,4,5\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,2,3,4\n",
        "choicethree": "1,3,5\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the pilot moves the mixture lever of a piston engine towards a lean position the :\n",
        "answer": "amount of fuel entering the combustion chamber is reduced.\n",
        "choiceone": "volume of air entering the carburettor is reduced.\n",
        "choicetwo": "amount of fuel entering the combustion chamber is increased.\n",
        "choicethree": "volume of air entering the carburettor is increased.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For piston engines, mixture ratio is the ratio between the\n",
        "answer": "mass of fuel and mass of air entering the cylinder.\n",
        "choiceone": "volume of fuel and volume of air entering the carburettor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "mass of fuel and volume of air entering the carburettor.\n",
        "choicethree": "volume of fuel and volume of air entering the cylinder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding a jet engine:\n|. The maximum thrust remains constant as the pressure altitude increases.\nIl. The specific fuel consumption increases slightly as the pressure altitud\nconstant TAS.\n\n",
        "answer": "lis incorrect, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "lis incorrect, Il is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lis correct, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "lis correct, Il is correct.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a bimetallic strip is used as a switch in a fire detection loop, a delay is\nincorporated after a fire alarm is triggered in order to:\n",
        "answer": "avoid false alarms in case of vibrations.\n",
        "choiceone": "allow temperatures to equalise.\n",
        "choicetwo": "delay the triggering of the fire extinguishers and increase their efficiency.\n",
        "choicethree": "wait for the triggering of the second fire detection loop in order to confirm the fire.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the \"Pressure Relief Valve\" in a high pressure oxygen system is to :\n",
        "answer": "relieve overpressure if the pressure reducing valve malfunctions\n",
        "choiceone": "act as a manual shut-off valve\n",
        "choicetwo": "maximize the charging pressure of the system\n",
        "choicethree": "reduce pressure in the oxygen reservoir to a suitable manifold pressure for the\nregulator\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The state in which the breathing oxygen for the cockpit of jet transport aeroplanes is\nstored is :\n",
        "answer": "Gaseous.\n",
        "choiceone": "Chemical compound.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Liquid.\n",
        "choicethree": "Gaseous or chemical compound..\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The demand valve of a diluter-demand type oxygen regulator in normal mode, operates\nwhen the :\n",
        "answer": "user breathes in\n",
        "choiceone": "diluter control is in normal position\n",
        "choicetwo": "user requires 100 percent oxygen\n",
        "choicethree": "pressure in the oxygen reservoir is more than 500 psi\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should be the indication on the magnetic compass as you roll into a standard rate\nturn to the right from a south heading in the Northern Hemisphere?\n",
        "answer": "The compass will indicate a turn to the right, but at a faster rate than is actually\noccurring.\n",
        "choiceone": "The compass will initially indicate a turn to the left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The compass will remain on south for a short time, then gradually catch up to the\nmagnetic heading of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a military airport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choiceone": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choicetwo": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, which would be correct about starting the rollout from a\nturn using a magnetic compass? Start the rollout\n",
        "answer": "after the compass indication passes south by a number of degrees approximately\nequal to the latitude minus the normal rollout lead.\n",
        "choiceone": "before the compass indication reaches south by a number of degrees approximately\nequal to the latitude over which the turn is made plus the pilot's normal lead.\n",
        "choicetwo": "after the compass indication passes south by a number of degrees approximately\nequal to the magnetic variation of the area over which the turn is made plus the\npilot's normal lead.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify runway remaining lighting on centerline lighting systems.\n",
        "answer": "Alternate red and white lights from 3,000 feet to 1,000 feet, then red lights to the end.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber lights from 3,000 feet to 1,000 feet, then alternate red and white lights to the\nend.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate red and white lights from 3,000 feet to the end of the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Bourdon tube is used in:\n",
        "answer": "pressure sensors\n",
        "choiceone": "vibration detectors\n",
        "choicetwo": "smoke detectors\n",
        "choicethree": "turbine temperature probes\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ASI compressibility error will increase with increase of TAS and:\n",
        "answer": "Increase with altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Decrease with altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increase with increase of density.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reported QNH ofa given station is the:\n",
        "answer": "Station's barometric pressure corrected to mean sea level pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "actual barometric pressure measured at the station;\n",
        "choicetwo": "actual barometric pressure measured at sea level;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Static air temperature is:\n",
        "answer": "(a) the correct temperature of the ambient air surrounding the aircraft but unaffected\nby the presence or movement of the aircraft\n",
        "choiceone": "(b) the correct temperature of the air surrounding the aircraft as affected by the\npresence or movement of the aircraft\n",
        "choicetwo": "(c) the temperature of the aircraft skin measured at a stagnation point\n",
        "choicethree": "(d) the temperature of the air within the static line\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When ambient temperature is warmer than standard at a particular altitude, the altimeter\nwill indicate:\n",
        "answer": "lower than true altitude;\n",
        "choiceone": "higher than true altitude;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same as true altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a pre-flight check the following details were noted: Airfield Elevation (4800 ft)-\nApron Elevation (4780 ft)- Height of static vent above ground ( 25 ft)- Altimeter reading\n(QFE)( 35 ft)\n",
        "answer": "30 ft underread.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 ft underread\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 ft underread\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The value of the compressibility error of an Airspeed Indicator (ASI) will:\n",
        "answer": "increase with increase in altitude and true airspeed;\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease, with decrease in density and increase with an increase in IAS;\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase with increase in true airspeed and decrease with increase in altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mach number is:\n",
        "answer": "the ratio of TAS to LSS at that temperature\n",
        "choiceone": "the ratio of IAS toLSS\n",
        "choicetwo": "the speed at which compressibility error must be calculated\n",
        "choicethree": "the ratio of EAS to LSS at that temperature\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A machmeter does not suffer from:\n",
        "answer": "compressibility error\n",
        "choiceone": "instrument error\n",
        "choicetwo": "position error\n",
        "choicethree": "error due to blockage of the static vent\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A RMI (Radio Magnetic Indicator) displays a warning flag which\nfailure. The radio bearing pointers:\n\n",
        "answer": "can be used to home to an NDB;\n",
        "choiceone": "are not to be used;\n",
        "choicetwo": "can be used to home to an NDB and a VOR station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Errors in both pitch and bank indication on an attitude indicator are usually ata\nmaximum as the aircraft rolls out of a:\n",
        "answer": "180 degree turn;\n",
        "choiceone": "90 degree turn;\n",
        "choicetwo": "270 degree turn.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an electrically driven artificial horizon, the axis wander about the pitch axis is\ncontrolled by:\n",
        "answer": "A mercury switch at right angles to the pitch axis inducing torque about the roll axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "A mercury switch parallel to the pitch axis inducing torque about the pitch axis.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A mercury switch at right angles to the roll axis inducing torque about the pitch axis.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The gyroscope of a turn indicator has:\n\n(NB: the rotor spin axis is not counted for the number of degrees of freedom of the gyro)\n",
        "answer": "1 degree of freedom.\n",
        "choiceone": "0 degree of freedom.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 degrees of freedom.\n",
        "choicethree": "3 degrees of freedom.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When, in flight, the needle of a needle-and-ball indicator is on the left and the ball on the\nright, the aeroplane is:\n",
        "answer": "turning left with too much left rudder pedal.\n",
        "choiceone": "turning left with not enough left rudder pedal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "turning right with too much left rudder pedal.\n",
        "choicethree": "turning right with not enough left rudder pedal.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fuel enters a two-cycle engine through an\n",
        "answer": "intake port and intake valve.\n",
        "choiceone": "intake port and reed valve.\n",
        "choicetwo": "intake valve and reed valve.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should help prevent aircraft induced oscillation on a gyroplane?-\n",
        "answer": "Adding a horizontal stabilizer.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increasing cyclic control sensitivity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Lowering the center of gravity below the thrust line.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "constant angle of bank and altitude?\n",
        "answer": "The rate of turn will decrease resulting in no changes in load factor.\n",
        "choiceone": "The rate of turn will decrease resulting in a decreased load factor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The rate of turn will increase resulting in an increased load factor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At which speed will increasing the pitch attitude cause an airplane to climb?\n",
        "answer": "High speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any speed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to energy storage, the accumulator of the hydraulic system is used :\n",
        "answer": "for damping pressure surges in the system.\n",
        "choiceone": "for pressure storage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "as a pressure relief valve.\n",
        "choicethree": "for fluid storage.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The illumination of the green landing gear light indicates that the landing gear is :\n",
        "answer": "locked-down.\n",
        "choiceone": "locked-down and its door is locked.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not in the required position.\n",
        "choicethree": "in the required position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cConditioned\u201d air is air that has :\n",
        "answer": "been controlled in respect of temperature and pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "had any moisture removed from it.\n",
        "choicetwo": "had the oxygen content increased.\n",
        "choicethree": "had the oxygen content reduced.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pneumatic system accumulator is useful :\n",
        "answer": "to eliminate the fluid pressure variations.\n",
        "choiceone": "to offset for the starting of some devices.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in emergency cases.\n",
        "choicethree": "to eliminate the fluid flow variations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cross-feed fuel system enables:\n",
        "answer": "the supply of any jet engine from any fuel tank.\n",
        "choiceone": "the supply of the jet engines mounted on a wing from any fuel tank within that wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the supply of the outboard jet engines from any outboard\n",
        "choicethree": "only the transfer of fuel from the centre tank to the wing tanks.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fuses are rated to a value by:\n",
        "answer": "the number of amperes they will carry.\n",
        "choiceone": "the number of volts they will pass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "their wattage.\n",
        "choicethree": "their resistance measured in ohms.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Immediately after starting engine(s) with no other electrical services switched on, an\nammeter showing a high charge rate to the battery :\n",
        "answer": "would be normal and is only cause for concern if the high charge rate persists.\n",
        "choiceone": "indicates a battery failure since there should be no immediate charge.\n",
        "choicetwo": "indicates a generator failure, thus requiring the engine to be shut down immediately.\n",
        "choicethree": "indicates a faulty reverse current relay.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The emergency lighting system must be able to function and supply a certain level of\nlighting after the main electric power system has been cut off for at least:\n",
        "answer": "10 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "90 seconds\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "30 minutes\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The octane rating of a fuel characterises the :\n",
        "answer": "the anti-knock capability\n",
        "choiceone": "quantity of heat generated by its combustion\n",
        "choicetwo": "fuel electrical conductivity\n",
        "choicethree": "fuel volatility\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true concerning the effect of the application of carburettor heat?\n",
        "answer": "it reduces the density of air entering the carburettor, thus enriching the fuel/air\nmixture\n",
        "choiceone": "it reduces the density of air entering the carburettor, thus leaning the fuel/air mixture\n",
        "choicetwo": "it reduces the volume of air entering the carburettor,thus enriching the fuel/air\nmixture\n",
        "choicethree": "it reduces the volume of air entering the carburettor,thus leaning the fuel/air mixture\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under what condition should stalls never be practiced in a twin-engine airplane?\n",
        "answer": "With one engine inoperative.\n",
        "choiceone": "With climb power on.\n",
        "choicetwo": "With full flaps and gear extended.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does V(NE) speed vary with altitude?\n",
        "answer": "Varies inversely with altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Varies directly with altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Remains the same at all altitudes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Engine Pressure Ratio (EPR) is the ratio of:\n",
        "answer": "the total turbine outlet pressure to the total compressor inlet pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "the total turbine inlet pressure to the total compressor outlet pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the total turbine outlet pressure to the total compressor outlet pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "the total turbine inlet pressure to the total compressor inlet pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A gaseous sensor/responder tube fire sensor is tested by\n",
        "answer": "heating up the sensor with test power connection.\n",
        "choiceone": "checking the wiring harness for faults but not the sensor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "checking the sensor with pressurized gas.\n",
        "choicethree": "checking the continuity of the system with a test switch.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The state in which the breathing oxygen for the cockpit of jet transport aeroplanes is\nstored is :\n",
        "answer": "Gaseous.\n",
        "choiceone": "Chemical compound.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Liquid.\n",
        "choicethree": "Gaseous or chemical compound..\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the runway distance remaining markers.\n",
        "answer": "Signs with increments of 1,000 feet distance remaining.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red markers laterally placed across the runway at 3,000 feet from the end.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow marker laterally placed across the runway with signs on the side denoting\ndistance to end.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, if an aircrat\ncompass will normally indicate\n\naccelerated or decelerated, the magnetic\n",
        "answer": "correctly when on a north or south heading while either accelerating or decelerating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a turn momentarily, with changes in airspeed on any heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a turn toward the south while accelerating on a west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a military airport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choiceone": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choicetwo": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How will the airspeed icator react if the ram ai\nice, but the drain hole and static port are not?\n\nput to the pitot head is blocked by\n",
        "answer": "Indication will drop to zero.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indication will rise to the top of the scale.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indication will remain constant but will increase in a climb.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot head is blocked, what airspeed indication can he expected?\n",
        "answer": "No change of IAS in level flight, even with large power changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "A decrease of IAS during a climb.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Constant IAS during a descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 85.) Of the following, which is the minimum acceptable rate of climb (feet\nper minute) to 9,000 feet required for the WASH2 WAGGE departure at a GS of 150\nknots?\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet per minute.\n",
        "choiceone": "750 feet per minute.\n",
        "choicetwo": "825 feet per minute.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pitot line is blocked, the VSI will:\n",
        "answer": "read normally\n",
        "choiceone": "read zero ftmm rate of climb/descent\n",
        "choicetwo": "over-read\n",
        "choicethree": "under-read\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ASI compressibility error will increase with increase of TAS and:\n",
        "answer": "Increase with altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Decrease with altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increase with increase of density.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Concerning the pitot and static system, the static pressure error:\n",
        "answer": "is caused by disturbed airflow around the static ports.\n",
        "choiceone": "is a direct effect of heating of the static ports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "affects the alternate static port only.\n",
        "choicethree": "is a direct effect of a blockage of the static port.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QFE at an aerodrome (elevation) 1790 feet is 962 hPa and the QNH 1022 hPa. If the\ntransition level is FLO40 the physical level of the transition level above the aerodrome is\napproximately:\n",
        "answer": "2464 feet\n",
        "choiceone": "2150 feet\n",
        "choicetwo": "2280 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The deviations of a direct reading magnetic compass effected only by coefficients B and\nC are, 3 E on 230 (C) and 4 W on 130 (C), therefore the deviation on heading 315 (C) is:\n",
        "answer": "3,3E\n",
        "choiceone": "7,5W\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,3W\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the northern hemisphere, an aircraft takes-off on a runway with an alignment of 045\u00b0.\nDuring the rake-off run, the compass indicates:\n",
        "answer": "a value below 045\u00b0.\n",
        "choiceone": "045\u00b0.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a value above 045\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "225\u00b0.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of rigi\ninstruments:\n\nused for the operation of the following gyroscopic\n",
        "answer": "Directional Gyro and Artificial Horizon.\n",
        "choiceone": "Directional Gyro and Turn indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Artificial Horizon and Turn indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft is rapidly accelerated in straight and level flight, or at take-off, what\ninherent precession characteristic will be displayed on the attitude indicator?\n",
        "answer": "The miniature aircraft would indicate a climb and bank.\n",
        "choiceone": "The miniature aircraft would indicate a descent.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The miniature aircraft would indicate a climb.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One characteristic that a properly functioning gyro depends upon for operation is the:\n",
        "answer": "Resistance to deflection of the gyro rotor.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ability to resist precession at 90 degrees to an applied force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position of the gyro axis relative to the Earth's axis.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a stabilised climbing turn at a constant rate, the instruments which indicate the\n\ncorrect pitch and bank are the:\n",
        "answer": "attitude indicator and turn-and-slip indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "vertical-speed indicator and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of a trim tab (device) is to:\n",
        "answer": "reduce or to cancel control forces.\n",
        "choiceone": "trim the aeroplane at low airspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lower manoeuvring control forces.\n",
        "choicethree": "trim the aeroplane during normal flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first indication of carburetor ice in an aircraft with a fixed-pitch propeller is\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in RPM.\n",
        "choiceone": "a decrease in manifold pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase in manifold pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is considered a primary flight control?\n",
        "answer": "Elevator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Slats.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dorsal fin.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a purpose of leading-edge flaps?\n",
        "answer": "Increase the camber of the wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Reduce lift without increasing airspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct airflow over the top of the wing at high angles of attack.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a non-stressed skin type wing, the wing structure elements which take up the\nvertical bending moments Mx are:\n",
        "answer": "the spars.\n",
        "choiceone": "the ribs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the webs.\n",
        "choicethree": "the skin.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At which speed will increasing the pitch attitude cause an airplane to climb?\n",
        "answer": "High speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any speed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An artificial feel unit is necessary in the pitch channel when:\n",
        "answer": "the elevators are actuated by irreversible servo-control units.\n",
        "choiceone": "the elevators are actuated by reversible servo-control units.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elevators are fitted with servo-tabs or trim tabs.\n",
        "choicethree": "there is a trimmable stabilizer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the door operation of a transport airplane equipped with evacuation slides\ncontrolled from the outside, the slide:\n\n",
        "answer": "is disarmed automatically.\n",
        "choiceone": "unfolds and becomes inflated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unfolds but does not become inflated.\n",
        "choicethree": "becomes inflated in its packboard thus preventing its unfolding.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A tubeless tyre is a tyre: 1. which requires solid or branched wheels 2. whose valve can\nbe sheared in sudden accelerations 3. whose mounting rim must be flawless 4. which\nrequires no rim protection between rim flange and tire removing device 5. which does\nnot burst in the event of a tire puncture 6. which eliminates internal friction between the\ntube and the tire The combination regrouping all the correct statements is :\n",
        "answer": "1,5, 6.\n",
        "choiceone": "3, 4,5.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1, 2,5.\n",
        "choicethree": "2, 3, 6.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the preheating coil used in hot air balloons is to\n",
        "answer": "vaporize the fuel for more efficient burner operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "prevent ice from forming in the fuel lines.\n",
        "choicetwo": "warm the fuel tanks for more efficient fuel flow.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aeroplane utilising AC as primary power supplies,\nthe batteries are charged in flight from :\n\n",
        "answer": "a Transformer Rectifier Unit.\n",
        "choiceone": "a DC transformer and rectifier.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the AC bus via current limiters.\n",
        "choicethree": "a static inverter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The function of a constant speed drive (CSD) in an AC generating system is to :\n",
        "answer": "drive the generator at a constant speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "vary generator rpm in order to compensate for various AC loads.\n",
        "choicetwo": "directly maintain a constant proportion between the rpm of an engine and a\ngenerator.\n",
        "choicethree": "vary the engine rpm (within limits) to compensate for various AC loads.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft magneto is switched off by\n",
        "answer": "grounding the primary circuit\n",
        "choiceone": "opening the primary circuit\n",
        "choicetwo": "opening the secondary circuit\n",
        "choicethree": "grounding the secondary circuit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a piston engine, the purpose of an altitude mixture control is to:\n",
        "answer": "correct for variations in the fuel/air ratio due to decreased air density at altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "prevent a weak cut when the throttle is opened rapidly at altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "weaken the mixture because of reduced exhaust back pressure at altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "enrich the mixture due to decreased air density at altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct about the flow in a divergent jet engine inlet?\n|. The speed increases in flow direction.\nll. The total pressure increases in flow direction.\n",
        "answer": "lis incorrect, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "lis incorrect, Il is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lis correct, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "lis correct, Il is correct.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary reason for a limitation being imposed on the temperature of gas flow is to :\n",
        "answer": "ensure that the maximum acceptable temperature at the turbine blades is not\nexceeded.\n",
        "choiceone": "ensure that the maximum acceptable temperature within the combustion chamber is\nnot exceeded.\n",
        "choicetwo": "prevent damage to the jet pipe from overheating.\n",
        "choicethree": "prevent overheating and subsequent creep of the nozzle\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reason for having a low pressure fuel-cooled oil cooler in a recirculatory type oil\nsystem is to:\n",
        "answer": "cool the oil and heat the fuel.\n",
        "choiceone": "cool both the oil and the fuel.\n",
        "choicetwo": "heat the fuel only.\n",
        "choicethree": "cool the oil only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a bimetallic strip is used as a switch in a fire detection loop, a delay is\nincorporated after a fire alarm is triggered in order to:\n",
        "answer": "avoid false alarms in case of vibrations.\n",
        "choiceone": "allow temperatures to equalise.\n",
        "choicetwo": "delay the triggering of the fire extinguishers and increase their efficiency.\n",
        "choicethree": "wait for the triggering of the second fire detection loop in order to confirm the fire.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A passenger emergency mask is a:\n",
        "answer": "continuous flow mask and cannot be used if there is smoke in the cabin.\n",
        "choiceone": "continuous flow mask and can be used if there is smoke in the cabin.\n",
        "choicetwo": "mask with flow on request and can be used if there is smoke.\n",
        "choicethree": "mask with flow on request and cannot be used if there is smoke in the cabin.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Chemical oxygen generators are used to furnish oxygen to the :\n",
        "answer": "cabin only.\n",
        "choiceone": "cockpit only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "toilets only.\n",
        "choicethree": "cockpit and the cabin.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deviation error of the magnetic compass is caused by\n",
        "answer": "certain metals and electrical systems within the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "northerly turning error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the difference in location of true north and magnetic north.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the static pressure tubes are broken inside a pressurized cabin during a high-altitude\nflight, the altimeter would probably indicate\n",
        "answer": "lower than actual flight altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "sea level.\n",
        "choicetwo": "higher than actual flight altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true concerning gyroplane operations?\n",
        "answer": "Minimum level flight speed is established when all available power is used to\nmaintain constant altitude and airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rotor RPM will decrease during a vertical descent regardless of weight or density\naltitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A gyroplane can take off from any area in which it can safely land.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 87.) Where\nLake Charles?\n\nthe VOR COP when flying east on V306 from D:\n",
        "answer": "30 NM east of DAS.\n",
        "choiceone": "50 NM east of DAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "40 NM east of DAS.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a manifold pressure gauge consistently registers atmospheric pressure, the caus:\nprobably:\n",
        "answer": "leak in pressure gauge line.\n",
        "choiceone": "an aneroid capsule which is not properly calibrated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a very high atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "a very low atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mean sea level calibration constants used for pressure altimeters are:\n",
        "answer": "pressure 1013.2 mb, temperature +15\u00b0C, density 1225 gm/m3\n",
        "choiceone": "pressure 1013.2 mb, temperature +15\u00b0C, density 1225 gmim2\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure 30\" Hg, temperature +15\u00b0C, density 1225 gm/m3.\n",
        "choicethree": "pressure 1013.2 hg, temperature +15\u00b0C, density 1225 gm/m3\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The elevation of aerodrome A is 390 feet and aerodrome B 450 feet. The pilot of an\naeroplane at A, sets the altimeter to read aerodrome elevation and then flies to B without\nresetting the altimeter. Aerodrome pressure at A on departure was 1004 hPa. On\nlanding at B the altimeter reads 630 feet, and assuming 1 hPa is 30 feet, the QNH is\napproximately:\n",
        "answer": "1011 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "1013 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "1019 hPa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL230, temperature -41\u00b0 C, QNH 983 HPA, is at a true altitude of:\n",
        "answer": "21 050 feet\n",
        "choiceone": "22 200 feet\n",
        "choicetwo": "23 013 feet\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rectified Airspeed is:\n",
        "answer": "IAS corrected for instrument and pressure error.\n",
        "choiceone": "IAS corrected for density error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IAS corrected for density and compressibility errors.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a combined Machiairspeed indicator the purpose of the barber's pole is to indicate:\n",
        "answer": "Vmo, and this value increases at high altitudes\n",
        "choiceone": "Vmo, and this is a fixed value at all altitudes\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vmo, and this value decreases at high altitudes\n",
        "choicethree": "the maximum safe airspeed with the flaps/slats extended\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mach number is:\n",
        "answer": "the ratio of TAS to LSS at that temperature\n",
        "choiceone": "the ratio of IAS toLSS\n",
        "choicetwo": "the speed at which compressibility error must be calculated\n",
        "choicethree": "the ratio of EAS to LSS at that temperature\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an electrically driven artificial horizon, the axis wander about the pitch axis is\ncontrolled by:\n",
        "answer": "A mercury switch at right angles to the pitch axis inducing torque about the roll axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "A mercury switch parallel to the pitch axis inducing torque about the pitch axis.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A mercury switch at right angles to the roll axis inducing torque about the pitch axis.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One characteristic that a properly functioning gyro depends upon for operation is the:\n",
        "answer": "Resistance to deflection of the gyro rotor.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ability to resist precession at 90 degrees to an applied force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position of the gyro axis relative to the Earth's axis.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The gyroscope of a turn indicator has:\n\n(NB: the rotor spin axis is not counted for the number of degrees of freedom of the gyro)\n",
        "answer": "1 degree of freedom.\n",
        "choiceone": "0 degree of freedom.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 degrees of freedom.\n",
        "choicethree": "3 degrees of freedom.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a gyromagnetic compass, the flux valve feeds the:\n",
        "answer": "error detector.\n",
        "choiceone": "erecting system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "heading indicator.\n",
        "choicethree": "amplifier.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flight director indicates the:\n",
        "answer": "optimum instantaneous trajectory to reach selected radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "optimum trajectory at the moment it is entered to reach a selected radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "trajectory permitting reaching a selected radial in minimum time.\n",
        "choicethree": "trajectory permitting reaching a selected radial over a minimum distance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these signals are inputs, at least, in the stall warning computers?\n",
        "answer": "Angle of attack and flaps and slats deflection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Angle of attack, flaps deflection and EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Angle of attack, flaps deflection, EPR and N1.\n",
        "choicethree": "Angle of attack and flaps and spoilers deflection.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "2-cycle engine thrust and fuel efficiency can be greatly compromised when\n",
        "answer": "exhaust systems are installed that are not specifically tuned for an engine.\n",
        "choiceone": "carbon deposits build up on exhaust valves.\n",
        "choicetwo": "intake valve lifters fail to pressurize and provide adequate fuel to the combustion\nchamber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "the aircraft attitude remai\ncontrols have been neutralized.\n\nthe new position after the\n",
        "answer": "Neutral longitudinal static stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "Negative longitudinal static stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Neutral longitudinal dynamic stability.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a purpose of ground spoilers?\n",
        "answer": "Reduce the wings' lift upon landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aid in rolling an airplane into a turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increase the rate of descent without gaining airspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hydraulic fluids :\n",
        "answer": "Are irritating to eyes and skin.\n",
        "choiceone": "Do not require special care.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Are irritating to eyes and skin and cause high fire risk.\n",
        "choicethree": "Cause high fire risk.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The component that transforms the hydraulic pressure into a linear motion is called ...\n",
        "answer": "An actuator or jack.\n",
        "choiceone": "An accumulator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A Pressure regulator.\n",
        "choicethree": "A hydraulic pump.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cNose wheel shimmy\" may be described as :\n",
        "answer": "a possibly damaging vibration of the nose wheel when moving on the ground.\n",
        "choiceone": "the oscillatory movement of the nose wheel when extended prior to landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the amount of free movement of the nose wheel before steering takes effect.\n",
        "choicethree": "aircraft vibration caused by the nose wheel upon extension of the gear.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cConditioned\u201d air is air that has :\n",
        "answer": "been controlled in respect of temperature and pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "had any moisture removed from it.\n",
        "choicetwo": "had the oxygen content increased.\n",
        "choicethree": "had the oxygen content reduced.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a compensated capacitance type quantity indicating\nsystem, the contents gauge of a half-full fuel tank\n\\dicates a fuel mass of 8000 Ib. If a temperature rise\n\\creased the volume of fuel by 5 %, the indicated fuel\nweight would :\n\n",
        "answer": "remain the same.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase by 5 %.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease by 5 %.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase by 10 %.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Electrical bonding of an aircraft is used to:\n1. protect the aircraft against lightning effects.\n\n2. set the electrostatic potential of the aircraft to a value approximating to 0 volt.\n3. prevent radio interference on radio communication systems.\n\n4. set the different aircraft parts to a single potential.\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:\n",
        "answer": "1,3,4\n",
        "choiceone": "1, 2,3\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,3,4\n",
        "choicethree": "1,2,4\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On modern transport aircraft, cockpit windows are protected against icing by :\n",
        "answer": "Electric heating.\n",
        "choiceone": "Vinyl coating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Anti-icing fluid.\n",
        "choicethree": "Rain repellent system.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cFrequency wild\" in relation to a AC generation system means the generator :\n",
        "answer": "output frequency varies with engine speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "output frequency is too low.\n",
        "choicetwo": "output frequency is too high.\n",
        "choicethree": "voltage regulator is out of adjustment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A feeder fault on a direct current circuit results from a flux unbalance between the:\n",
        "answer": "voltage coil and the series winding turn.\n",
        "choiceone": "shunt exciter and the series winding turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "voltage coil and the series winding.\n",
        "choicethree": "generator and the series winding turn.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The crank assembly consists of\n",
        "answer": "crankshaft, connecting rods and pistons.\n",
        "choiceone": "propeller, crankshaft, pistons and connecting rods.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crankcase, crankshaft, connecting rods and pistons.\n",
        "choicethree": "crankshaft, camshaft, valves, valve springs and push rods.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Max. Exhaust Gas Temperature is theoretically associated with :\n",
        "answer": "Mass ratio of 1/15.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mixture ratio very close to idle cut-out.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cruising mixture setting.\n",
        "choicethree": "Full rich setting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding a jet engine:\n|. The maximum thrust decreases as the pressure altitude increases.\n\nIl. The specific fuel consumption is inversely proportional to pressure altitude, at\nconstant TAS.\n\n",
        "answer": "lis correct, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "lis incorrect, Il is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lis correct, Il is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "lis incorrect, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The control of free turbine engines on turboprops, is accomplished by: -a propeller\ncontrol lever used to select: 1- propeller RPM 2.-turbine temperature 3 - turbine RPM\n- a fuel control lever used to select: 4- propeller RPM 5 - torque 6 - turbine temperature\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is :\n",
        "answer": "1-5-6\n",
        "choiceone": "1-3-5\n",
        "choicetwo": "3-4-6\n",
        "choicethree": "2-4-5\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fuel flow information for gas turbine engines is:\n",
        "answer": "measured in the line between the fuel control unit and the engine burners.\n",
        "choiceone": "not used on aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "measured at the outlet of the high pressure fuel pump.\n",
        "choicethree": "measured in the line between the booster pump and the engine.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the \"Pressure Relief Valve\" in a high pressure oxygen system is to :\n",
        "answer": "relieve overpressure if the pressure reducing valve malfunctions\n",
        "choiceone": "act as a manual shut-off valve\n",
        "choicetwo": "maximize the charging pressure of the system\n",
        "choicethree": "reduce pressure in the oxygen reservoir to a suitable manifold pressure for the\nregulator\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify taxi leadoff lights associated with the centerline lighting system.\n",
        "answer": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to a point\non the exit.\n",
        "choiceone": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\ncenterline of the taxiway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\nedge of the taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the runway distance remaining markers.\n",
        "answer": "Signs with increments of 1,000 feet distance remaining.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red markers laterally placed across the runway at 3,000 feet from the end.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow marker laterally placed across the runway with signs on the side denoting\ndistance to end.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify touchdown zone lighting (TDZL).\n",
        "answer": "Two rows of transverse light bars disposed symmetrically about the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flush centerline lights spaced at 50-foot intervals extending through the touchdown\nzone.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate white and green centerline lights extending from 75 feet from the threshold\nthrough the touchdown zone.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "craft is flying from a cold air mass into a warm air mass. The TAS and true altitude\n\n",
        "answer": "Both increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "TAS increases, true altitude decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAS decreases, true altitude increases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Concerning the pitot and static system, the static pressure error:\n",
        "answer": "is caused by disturbed airflow around the static ports.\n",
        "choiceone": "is a direct effect of heating of the static ports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "affects the alternate static port only.\n",
        "choicethree": "is a direct effect of a blockage of the static port.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Transition level is obtained from:\n",
        "answer": "ATC or VOR ATIS.\n",
        "choiceone": "Jeppesen or Aerad flight guides.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1500 feet above airfield elevation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an altimeter indicates 3500 FT with the actual QNH of 1004, 7 hPa set, the approximate\npressure altitude i\n\n",
        "answer": "3745 FT\n",
        "choiceone": "3500 FT\n",
        "choicetwo": "3255 FT\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the static vent became blocked during a descent, the altimeter would:\n",
        "answer": "over-read the correct altitude\n",
        "choiceone": "act normally\n",
        "choicetwo": "under-read the correct altitude\n",
        "choicethree": "read zero altitude\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot opening is blocked, whi\nvent)?\n\nstruments would be affected (separate static\n",
        "answer": "ASI only.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and VSI.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ASI and VSI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The percentage error due to the positioning of the static vent\n",
        "answer": "the same in the Machmeter as in the ASI\n",
        "choiceone": "greater in the ASI than in the Machmeter\n",
        "choicetwo": "greater in the Machmeter than in the ASI\n",
        "choicethree": "either greater or smaller when comparing the ASI and the Machmeter,\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rotor of the DGI spins up and away from the pilot when 090 is ir\nlatitude compensation nut situated on the near right hand side of the inner gimbal from\nthe gyro axis, has been set to give zero drift on the ground at the equator. To\ncompensate for earth rotation at 30 S the latitude compensating nut:\n",
        "answer": "must be adjusted outwards;\n",
        "choiceone": "must be adjusted inwards;\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not adjusted since the latitude nut can only be used to correct for apparent\nwander in the northern hemisphere.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The deviations of a direct reading magnetic compass effected only by coefficients B and\nC are, 3 E on 230 (C) and 4 W on 130 (C), therefore the deviation on heading 315 (C) is:\n",
        "answer": "3,3E\n",
        "choiceone": "7,5W\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,3W\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of rigi\ninstruments:\n\nused for the operation of the following gyroscopic\n",
        "answer": "Directional Gyro and Artificial Horizon.\n",
        "choiceone": "Directional Gyro and Turn indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Artificial Horizon and Turn indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle of tilt of the rate gyro in a turn indicator is due to:\n",
        "answer": "primary precession which is generated by an aeroplanes rate of turn.\n",
        "choiceone": "the force in the horizontal plane generated by secondary precession balancing the\ntilt caused by primary precession;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the tension of the control spring opposing the angular tilt of the gyro;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate angle of bank for a rate one turn at 110 knots?\n",
        "answer": "18 degrees\n",
        "choiceone": "25 degrees\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 degrees\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 022-10217A)\nConsidering the diagram n\u00b0, the flight director command bars position indicates that\nyou should:\n",
        "answer": "bank your aircraft to the left and increase the pitch angle.\n",
        "choiceone": "bank your aircraft to the right and increase the pitch angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "bank your aircraft to the left and reduce the pitch angle.\n",
        "choicethree": "bank your aircraft to the right and reduce the pitch angle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When refueling aircraft, which precaution would be adequate for eli\npotential hazard of static electricity?\n\n",
        "answer": "Connect a ground wire between the aircraft, fuel truck, fuel nozzle, and ground.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ensure that battery and ignition switches are off.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Connect a ground wire from the fuel truck to ground.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Adding more oil to the fuel than specified by the manufacturer of a 2-cycle engine will\nresult in\n",
        "answer": "increased carbon buildup and engine fouling.\n",
        "choiceone": "increased engine performance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increased engine lubrication and optimal performance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After the ignition source is removed, which class of material will not propagate a flame\nbeyond safe limits?\n",
        "answer": "Flame resistant.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fireproof.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flash resistant.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of an elevator trim tab?\n",
        "answer": "Modify the downward tail load for various airspeeds in flight eliminating flight-control\npressures.\n",
        "choiceone": "Provide horizontal balance as airspeed is increased to allow hands-off flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Adjust the speed tail load for different airspeeds in flight allowing neutral control\nforces.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With regard to an aircraft structure, \u2018fail safe\u2019 is one:\n",
        "answer": "in which the load is carried by other components if a part of the structure fails.\n",
        "choiceone": "that is easily manufactured.\n",
        "choicetwo": "used for small aircraft only.\n",
        "choicethree": "that is only used for a limited time.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming cabin pressure decreases, the cabin rate of climb indicator should indicate :\n",
        "answer": "a rate of climb.\n",
        "choiceone": "a rate of descent of approximately 300 feet per minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "zero.\n",
        "choicethree": "a rate of descent dependent upon the cabin differential pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term \"Bootstrap\", when used to identify a cabin air conditioning and pressurisation\nsystem, refers to the :\n",
        "answer": "cold air unit (air cycle machine) arrangement.\n",
        "choiceone": "source of the charge air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "means by which pressurisation is controlled.\n",
        "choicethree": "charge air across the inter-cooler heat exchanger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why should special precautions be taken when filling propane bottles?\n",
        "answer": "Propane is very cold and may cause freeze burns.\n",
        "choiceone": "During transfer, propane reaches a high temperature and can cause severe burns.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propane is under high pressure when transferred from storage tanks to propane\nbottles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cross-feed fuel system enables:\n",
        "answer": "the supply of any jet engine from any fuel tank.\n",
        "choiceone": "the supply of the jet engines mounted on a wing from any fuel tank within that wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the supply of the outboard jet engines from any outboard\n",
        "choicethree": "only the transfer of fuel from the centre tank to the wing tanks.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The detection of a feeder fault on a direct current circuit\nresults i\n1. automatic disconnection of the generator from the\naircraft AC busbar\n\n2. opening of generator field current relay\n\n3. opening of the main relay of the generator breaker\n4. opening of balancing circuit connecting two\ngenerators\n\n5. lighting of an indicator lamp\n\nThe combination of correct statements i\n\n",
        "answer": "1,2,3,4,5\n",
        "choiceone": "2,3,4,5\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,4,5\n",
        "choicethree": "1,3,5\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency of the current provided by an alternator depends on...\n",
        "answer": "its rotation speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "the strength of the excitation current.\n",
        "choicetwo": "its load.\n",
        "choicethree": "its phase balance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The part of a piston engine that transforms reciprocating movement into rotary motion\nis termed as the :\n",
        "answer": "crankshaft\n",
        "choiceone": "reduction gear\n",
        "choicetwo": "piston\n",
        "choicethree": "camshaft\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true concerning the effect of the application of carburettor heat?\n",
        "answer": "it reduces the density of air entering the carburettor, thus enriching the fuel/air\nmixture\n",
        "choiceone": "it reduces the density of air entering the carburettor, thus leaning the fuel/air mixture\n",
        "choicetwo": "it reduces the volume of air entering the carburettor,thus enriching the fuel/air\nmixture\n",
        "choicethree": "it reduces the volume of air entering the carburettor,thus leaning the fuel/air mixture\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a \"bootstrap\" cooling system, the charge air is first compressed in the cold air unit to:\n",
        "answer": "ensure an adequate pressure and temperature drop across the cooling turbine.\n",
        "choiceone": "maintain a constant cabin mass air flow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase the cabin air supply pressure when the charge pressure is too low.\n",
        "choicethree": "ensure an adequate charge air flow across the inter-cooler heat exchanger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Turbine blade stages may be classed as either \"impulse\" or \u201creaction\u201d. In ai\nblade section :\n",
        "answer": "the pressure drops across the nozzle guide vanes and remains constant across the\nrotor blades .\n",
        "choiceone": "the pressure remains constant across the nozzle guide vanes and rises constant\nacross the rotor blades .\n",
        "choicetwo": "the pressure rises across the nozzle guide vanes and remains constant across the\nrotor blades .\n",
        "choicethree": "the pressure remains constant across the nozzle guide vanes and drops across the\nrotor blades .\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The control of free turbine engines on turboprops, is accomplished by: -a propeller\ncontrol lever used to select: 1- propeller RPM 2.-turbine temperature 3 - turbine RPM\n- a fuel control lever used to select: 4- propeller RPM 5 - torque 6 - turbine temperature\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is :\n",
        "answer": "1-5-6\n",
        "choiceone": "1-3-5\n",
        "choicetwo": "3-4-6\n",
        "choicethree": "2-4-5\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a fire detection system with single-loop continuous components (with no fault\nprotection), if the inner core contacts the outer casing:\n",
        "answer": "the fire alarm is triggered.\n",
        "choiceone": "the power supply is cut off automatically.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there will be no effect on the system\n",
        "choicethree": "the main engine fire extinguisher is automatically activated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the oxygen system of a large aeroplane is used, :\n",
        "answer": "with the setting on \"NORMAL\", the cockpit crew is supplied with a mixture of oxygen\nand cabin air.\n",
        "choiceone": "the same source of supply is used by the cockpit crew and passengers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same source of supply is used by the cockpit crew and cabin crew.\n",
        "choicethree": "with the setting on \"NORMAL\", the passengers are supplied with a mixture of oxygen\nand cabin air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A passenger emergency mask is a:\n",
        "answer": "continuous flow mask and cannot be used if there is smoke in the cabin.\n",
        "choiceone": "continuous flow mask and can be used if there is smoke in the cabin.\n",
        "choicetwo": "mask with flow on request and can be used if there is smoke.\n",
        "choicethree": "mask with flow on request and cannot be used if there is smoke in the cabin.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 87.) At STRUT intersection headed eastbound, ATC instructs you to\nhold west on the 10 DME fix west of LCH on V306, standard turns, what entry procedure\nis recommended?\n",
        "answer": "Direct.\n",
        "choiceone": "Teardrop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Parallel.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a lighted heliport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choiceone": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a pitot tube is clogged, which instrument would be affected?\n",
        "answer": "Airspeed indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altimeter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vertical speed indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should be the indication on the magnetic compass as you roll into a standard rate\nturn to the right from a south heading in the Northern Hemisphere?\n",
        "answer": "The compass will indicate a turn to the right, but at a faster rate than is actually\noccurring.\n",
        "choiceone": "The compass will initially indicate a turn to the left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The compass will remain on south for a short time, then gradually catch up to the\nmagnetic heading of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a military airport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choiceone": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choicetwo": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When making an airborne VOR check, what is the maximum allowable tolerance\nbetween the two indicators of a dual VOR system (units independent of each other\nexcept the antenna)?\n\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees between the two indicated bearings of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus or minus 4 degrees when set to identical radials of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 degrees between the two indicated radials of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the maximum tolerance for the VOI ication when the CDI is centered and\nthe aircraft is directly over the airborne checkpoint?\n",
        "answer": "Plus or minus 6 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus 6degrees or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Plus or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which instrument would be affected by excessively low pressure in the\nvacuum system?\n",
        "answer": "Heading indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airspeed indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pressure altimeter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VSI may suffer from error due to:\n",
        "answer": "time lag, instrument calibration, blockage\n",
        "choiceone": "compressibility, time lag, blockage\n",
        "choicetwo": "density, aircraft manoeuvre, position of the static vent\n",
        "choicethree": "pitot blockage, static blockage, aircraft manoeuvre\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Transition altitude is obtained from:\n",
        "answer": "Jeppesen or Aerad flight guides.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC or VOR ATIS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1500 feet above airfield elevation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QFE at an aerodrome (elevation) 1790 feet is 962 hPa and the QNH 1022 hPa. If the\ntransition level is FLO40 the physical level of the transition level above the aerodrome is\napproximately:\n",
        "answer": "2464 feet\n",
        "choiceone": "2150 feet\n",
        "choicetwo": "2280 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot opening is blocked, whi\nvent)?\n\nstruments would be affected (separate static\n",
        "answer": "ASI only.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and VSI.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ASI and VSI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aircraft climbs at a constant IAS in the standard atmosphere, the Mach number will:\n",
        "answer": "increase\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease\n",
        "choicetwo": "remain constant\n",
        "choicethree": "remain constant unless the aircraft flies through an inversion\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\\g at a constant Mach number in the standard atmosphere, the\n\n",
        "answer": "increase\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease\n",
        "choicetwo": "remain constant\n",
        "choicethree": "remain constant unless the aircraft flies through an inversion\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following figures appear on an aeroplane deviation card: FOR MAGNETIC (45----90),\nSTEER COMPASS (38----92). The compass heading to steer to maintain a heading of\n075\u00b0 (M) is:\n",
        "answer": "74\n",
        "choiceone": "72\n",
        "choicetwo": "76\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rotor of the DGI spins up and away from the pilot when 090 is ir\nlatitude compensation nut situated on the near right hand side of the inner gimbal from\nthe gyro axis, has been set to give zero drift on the ground at the equator. To\ncompensate for earth rotation at 30 S the latitude compensating nut:\n",
        "answer": "must be adjusted outwards;\n",
        "choiceone": "must be adjusted inwards;\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not adjusted since the latitude nut can only be used to correct for apparent\nwander in the northern hemisphere.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At a low bank angle, the measurement of rate-of-turn actually consists in measuring the:\n",
        "answer": "yaw rate of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "pitch rate of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "roll rate of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicethree": "bank of the aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stall warning computer uses the following dat\n\n1- mass of the aeroplane\n2- angle of attack\n\n3- wing flap deflection\n\n4- position of the landing gear\n5- TAT\n\n6- pressure altitude\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:\n",
        "answer": "2,3\n",
        "choiceone": "2,3,5\n",
        "choicetwo": "1, 2,3,4\n",
        "choicethree": "1, 2,3, 4,5,6\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the ground wire between the magneto and the ignition switch becomes disconnected,\nthe most noticeable result will be that the engine\n",
        "answer": "cannot be shut down by turning the switch to the OFF position.\n",
        "choiceone": "will run very rough.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cannot be started with the switch in the ON position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "2-cycle engine thrust and fuel efficiency can be greatly compromised when\n",
        "answer": "exhaust systems are installed that are not specifically tuned for an engine.\n",
        "choiceone": "carbon deposits build up on exhaust valves.\n",
        "choicetwo": "intake valve lifters fail to pressurize and provide adequate fuel to the combustion\nchamber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A typical two-cycle engine ignition coil is powered by\n",
        "answer": "a magneto.\n",
        "choiceone": "a battery.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a battery or an alternator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fan guard surrounds the propeller and\n",
        "answer": "protects the parachute suspension lines from damage.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases aerodynamic efficiency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "reduces 'P' factor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the relationship of the rate of turn with the radius of turn with a constant angle of\nbank but increasing airspeed?\n",
        "answer": "Rate will decrease and radius will increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rate will increase and radius will decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rate and radius will increase.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fuselage of an aircraft consists, among others, of stringers whose purpose is to:\n",
        "answer": "assist the skin in absorbing the longitudinal traction-compression stresses.\n",
        "choiceone": "withstand the shear stresses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "provide sound and thermal isolation.\n",
        "choicethree": "integrate the strains due to pressurization to which the skin is subjected and convert\nthem into a tensile stress.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aircraft hydraulic system is designed to produce:\n",
        "answer": "high pressure and large flow.\n",
        "choiceone": "high pressure and small flow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "small pressure and large flow.\n",
        "choicethree": "small pressure and small flow.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The hydraulic device similar to an electronic diode is a:\n",
        "answer": "check valve.\n",
        "choiceone": "flow control valve.\n",
        "choicetwo": "distribution valve.\n",
        "choicethree": "shutoff valve.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A tubeless tyre has : 1- a built-in-air tube. 2- no built-in-air tube. 3-acrossed\ncasing. 4- a radial side casing. The combination of correct statements is:\n\n",
        "answer": "2,4.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2, 3.\n",
        "choicethree": "1,3.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term \"Bootstrap\", when used to identify a cabin air conditioning and pressurisation\nsystem, refers to the :\n",
        "answer": "cold air unit (air cycle machine) arrangement.\n",
        "choiceone": "source of the charge air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "means by which pressurisation is controlled.\n",
        "choicethree": "charge air across the inter-cooler heat exchanger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main purpose of the mixture control is to:\n",
        "answer": "adjust the fuel flow to obtain the proper fuel/air ratio\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease the air supplied to the engine\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase the oxygen supplied to the engine\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease oxygen supplied to the engine\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During fuelling the automatic fuelling shut off valves will\n",
        "answer": "the fuel has reached a predetermined volume or mass.\n",
        "choiceone": "the surge vent tank is filled.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there is fire.\n",
        "choicethree": "fuelling system has reached a certain pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a turbine engine, the term self-sustaining speed means the engine\n",
        "answer": "will run without any external assistance.\n",
        "choiceone": "operates most efficiently in the cruise...\n",
        "choicetwo": "will enable the generators to supply bus-bar voltage.\n",
        "choicethree": "is designed to idle after starting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Electrical bonding of an aircraft is used to: 1. protect the aircraft against lightning effects.\n2. reset the electrostatic potential of the aircraft to a value approximating 0 volt 3. reduce\nradio interference on radiocommunication systems 4. set the aircraft to a single\npotential The combination regrouping all the correct statements\n",
        "answer": "1,3,4\n",
        "choiceone": "1,2,3\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,4\n",
        "choicethree": "2,4\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When changing power on engines equipped with constant-speed propeller, engine\noverload is avoided by accidental depressurization.\n",
        "answer": "increasing the RPM before increasing the manifold pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "adjusting Fuel Flow before the manifold pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "reducing the RPM before reducing the manifold pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "increasing the manifold pressure before increasing the RPM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The oil system for a piston engine incorporates an oil cooler that is fitted :\n",
        "answer": "in the return line to the oil tank after the oil has passed through the scavenge pump\n",
        "choiceone": "between the oil tank and the pressure pump\n",
        "choicetwo": "after the pressure pump but before the oil passes through the engine\n",
        "choicethree": "after the oil has passed through the engine and before it enters the sump\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The torque of an aeroplane engine can be measured at the:\n",
        "answer": "gear box which is located between the engine and the propeller.\n",
        "choiceone": "accessory gear box.\n",
        "choicetwo": "camshaft.\n",
        "choicethree": "propeller blades.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In general, in twin-engine aeroplanes with \u2018constant speed propeller\u2019\n",
        "answer": "the oil pressure turns the propeller blades towards smaller pitch angle.\n",
        "choiceone": "the aerodynamic force turns the propeller blades towards higher pitch angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the spring force turns the propeller blades towards smaller pitch angle.\n",
        "choicethree": "the oil pressure turns the propeller blades towards higher pitch angle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An impulse turbine is a turbine in which the expansion takes place:\n",
        "answer": "fully in the stator.\n",
        "choiceone": "in order to produce a degree of jet propulsion < 1/2.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fully in the rotor.\n",
        "choicethree": "in the stator and in the rotor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Continuous-Loop-Detector-System is a:\n",
        "answer": "Fire detection system\n",
        "choiceone": "Carbon dioxide warning system\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fire fighting system\n",
        "choicethree": "Smoke detection system\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true concerning gyroplane operations?\n",
        "answer": "Minimum level flight speed is established when all available power is used to\nmaintain constant altitude and airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rotor RPM will decrease during a vertical descent regardless of weight or density\naltitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A gyroplane can take off from any area in which it can safely land.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should be the indication on the magnetic compass as you roll into a standard rate\nturn to the right from a south heading in the Northern Hemisphere?\n",
        "answer": "The compass will indicate a turn to the right, but at a faster rate than is actually\noccurring.\n",
        "choiceone": "The compass will initially indicate a turn to the left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The compass will remain on south for a short time, then gradually catch up to the\nmagnetic heading of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a pitot tube is clogged, which instrument would be affected?\n",
        "answer": "Airspeed indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altimeter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vertical speed indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify touchdown zone lighting (TDZL).\n",
        "answer": "Two rows of transverse light bars disposed symmetrically about the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flush centerline lights spaced at 50-foot intervals extending through the touchdown\nzone.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate white and green centerline lights extending from 75 feet from the threshold\nthrough the touchdown zone.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify runway remaining lighting on centerline lighting systems.\n",
        "answer": "Alternate red and white lights from 3,000 feet to 1,000 feet, then red lights to the end.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber lights from 3,000 feet to 1,000 feet, then alternate red and white lights to the\nend.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate red and white lights from 3,000 feet to the end of the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, a magnetic compass will normally indicate a turn toward\n\nthe north if\n",
        "answer": "an aircraft is accelerated while on an east or west heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "a left turn is entered from a west heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an aircraft is decelerated while on an east or west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 140.) Which\nthe 1.9 NM pointis indicated?\n\nplacement from the localizer and glide slope at\n",
        "answer": "710 feet to the right of the localizer centerline and 140 feet above the glide slope.\n",
        "choiceone": "710 feet to the left of the localizer centerline and 140 feet below the glide slope.\n",
        "choicetwo": "430 feet to the right of the localizer centerline and 28 feet above the glide slope.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 141.) Which displacement from the localizer centerline and\nglide slope at the 1,300-foot point from the runway is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "21 feet above the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "21 feet below the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the right of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "28 feet above the glide slope and approximately 250 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the advantage of a three-bar VASI?\n",
        "answer": "A normal glide angle is afforded both high and low cockpit aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Pilots have a choice of glide angles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The three-bar VASI is much more visible and can be used at a greater height.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true about magnetic deviation of a compass?\n",
        "answer": "Deviation varies for different headings of the same aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Deviation is the same for all aircraft in the same locality.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deviation is different in a given aircraft in different localities.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot Head and Static Vent were blocked by ice, which instruments would be\naffected?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter, VSI and ASI would give inaccurate readings.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and Slip indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ASI would under read.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VSI may suffer from error due to:\n",
        "answer": "time lag, instrument calibration, blockage\n",
        "choiceone": "compressibility, time lag, blockage\n",
        "choicetwo": "density, aircraft manoeuvre, position of the static vent\n",
        "choicethree": "pitot blockage, static blockage, aircraft manoeuvre\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A simple pressure altimeter uses:\n",
        "answer": "static pressure fed into a gas tight casing, but outside a partially evacuated capsule\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure fed to an open capsule\n",
        "choicetwo": "pitot pressure fed to an open capsule\n",
        "choicethree": "static pressure fed outside a completely evacuated aneroid capsule.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Transition altitude is obtained from:\n",
        "answer": "Jeppesen or Aerad flight guides.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC or VOR ATIS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1500 feet above airfield elevation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The high Altitude Radio Altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicethree": "metric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "VFE is the maximum speed:\n",
        "answer": "with the flaps extended.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the flaps extended in the landing configuration.\n",
        "choicetwo": "with the flaps extended in the take-off configuration.\n",
        "choicethree": "at which the flaps can be operated when flying in turbulences.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot opening is blocked, whi\nvent)?\n\nstruments would be affected (separate static\n",
        "answer": "ASI only.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and VSI.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ASI and VSI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rectified Airspeed is:\n",
        "answer": "IAS corrected for instrument and pressure error.\n",
        "choiceone": "IAS corrected for density error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IAS corrected for density and compressibility errors.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a stabilised climbing turn at a constant rate, the instruments which indicate the\n\ncorrect pitch and bank are the:\n",
        "answer": "attitude indicator and turn-and-slip indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "vertical-speed indicator and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true regarding fouling of the spark plugs of an aircraft engine?\n",
        "answer": "Spark plug fouling results from operating with an excessively rich mixture.\n",
        "choiceone": "Carbon fouling of the spark plugs is caused primarily by operating an engine at\nexcessively high cylinder head temperatures.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Excessive heat in the combustion chamber of a cylinder causes oil to form on the\ncenter electrode of a spark plug and this fouls the plug.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of a kill switch is to\n",
        "answer": "ground the lead wire to the ignition coil shutting down the powerplant.\n",
        "choiceone": "shut off the fuel to the carburetor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ground the battery eliminating current for the ignition system.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which stroke of a reciprocating engine is the gaseous mixture expanding within\nthe cylinder?\n",
        "answer": "Power.\n",
        "choiceone": "Intake.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Compression.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formation of ice in a carburetor's throat is indicated by\n",
        "answer": "a drop in RPM, followed by rough engine operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "rough engine operation, followed by a decrease in oil pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a rapid increase in RPM, followed by rough engine operation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Many 4-cycle engines utilize what type of lubrication system?\n",
        "answer": "Forced.\n",
        "choiceone": "Gravity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fuel/oil mixture.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a steep turn to the left, when using spoilers ...\n",
        "answer": "The right aileron will descend, the left one will ascend, the right spoiler will retract\nand the left one will extend.\n",
        "choiceone": "The right aileron will descend, the left one will ascend, the right spoiler will extend\nand the left one will retract.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The right aileron will ascend, the left one will descend, the right spoiler will extend\nand the left one will retract.\n",
        "choicethree": "The right aileron will ascend, the left one will descend, the right spoiler will retract\nand the left one will extend.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the different types of aircraft structures, the shell structures efficiently transmit\nthe: 1. normal bending stresses 2. tangent bending stresses 3. torsional moment 4.\nshear stresses The combination regrouping all the correct statements is :\n\n",
        "answer": "1,2,3\n",
        "choiceone": "2,3,4\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,2,4\n",
        "choicethree": "1,3,4\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Upon which factor does wing loading during a level coordinated turn in smooth air\ndepend?\n",
        "answer": "Angle of bank.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rate of turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "True airspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aircraft hydraulic system is designed to produce:\n",
        "answer": "high pressure and large flow.\n",
        "choiceone": "high pressure and small flow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "small pressure and large flow.\n",
        "choicethree": "small pressure and small flow.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The hydraulic oil, entering the hydraulic pump, is slightly pressurised to :\n",
        "answer": "prevent cavitation in the pump\n",
        "choiceone": "prevent overheating of the pump.\n",
        "choicetwo": "prevent vapour locking.\n",
        "choicethree": "ensure sufficient pump output\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A tubeless tyre is a tyre: 1. which requires solid or branched wheels 2. whose valve can\nbe sheared in sudden accelerations 3. whose mounting rim must be flawless 4. which\nrequires no rim protection between rim flange and tire removing device 5. which does\nnot burst in the event of a tire puncture 6. which eliminates internal friction between the\ntube and the tire The combination regrouping all the correct statements is :\n",
        "answer": "1,5, 6.\n",
        "choiceone": "3, 4,5.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1, 2,5.\n",
        "choicethree": "2, 3, 6.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming cabin pressure decreases, the cabin rate of climb indicator should indicate :\n",
        "answer": "a rate of climb.\n",
        "choiceone": "a rate of descent of approximately 300 feet per minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "zero.\n",
        "choicethree": "a rate of descent dependent upon the cabin differential pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the cabin altitude rises (aircraft in level flight), the differential pressure:\n",
        "answer": "decreases\n",
        "choiceone": "increases\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains constant\n",
        "choicethree": "may exceed the maximum permitted differential unless immediate preventative\naction is taken.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pneumatic system accumulator is useful :\n",
        "answer": "to eliminate the fluid pressure variations.\n",
        "choiceone": "to offset for the starting of some devices.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in emergency cases.\n",
        "choicethree": "to eliminate the fluid flow variations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why should special precautions be taken when filling propane bottles?\n",
        "answer": "Propane is very cold and may cause freeze burns.\n",
        "choiceone": "During transfer, propane reaches a high temperature and can cause severe burns.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propane is under high pressure when transferred from storage tanks to propane\nbottles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the combustion gases pass through a turbine the :\n",
        "answer": "pressure drops.\n",
        "choiceone": "pressure rises.\n",
        "choicetwo": "velocity decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "temperature increases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a current is passed through a conductor,\n",
        "answer": "a force will be exerted on the conductor.\n",
        "choiceone": "the current will increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there will be no effect unless the conductor is moved.\n",
        "choicethree": "the intensity of the magnetic field will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reason for using inverters in an electrical system is\n",
        "answer": "To change DC into AC.\n",
        "choiceone": "To avoid a short circuit.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To change the DC voltage.\n",
        "choicethree": "To change AC into DC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "operated at FL 450, with 180 passenger seats, what\nwill be the number of masks available for use\n",
        "answer": "198 (110% of the seating capacity).\n",
        "choiceone": "210 (one additional mask per seat row).\n",
        "choicetwo": "270 (150% of the seating capacity).\n",
        "choicethree": "240 (one additional mask per seat block).\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The state in which the breathing oxygen for the cockpit of jet transport aeroplanes is\nstored is :\n",
        "answer": "Gaseous.\n",
        "choiceone": "Chemical compound.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Liquid.\n",
        "choicethree": "Gaseous or chemical compound..\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an altimeter is changed from 30.11\" Hg to 29.96\" Hg,\nindicated altitude change and by what value?\n\nwhich direction will the\n\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter will indicate 150 feet lower.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altimeter will indicate 15 feet lower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altimeter will indicate 150 feet higher.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a lighted heliport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choiceone": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A gyroplane will have the greatest tendency to roll during\n",
        "answer": "horizontal flight at high speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "climbing flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "descending flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deviation error of the magnetic compass is caused by\n",
        "answer": "certain metals and electrical systems within the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "northerly turning error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the difference in location of true north and magnetic north.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, a magnetic compass will normally indicate a turn toward\n\nthe north if\n",
        "answer": "an aircraft is accelerated while on an east or west heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "a left turn is entered from a west heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an aircraft is decelerated while on an east or west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which procedure is recommended to prevent or overcome spatial disorientation?\n",
        "answer": "Rely entirely on the indications of the flight instruments.\n",
        "choiceone": "Avoid steep turns and rough control movements.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Reduce head and eye movements to the greatest extent possible.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which instrument would be affected by excessively low pressure in the\nvacuum system?\n",
        "answer": "Heading indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airspeed indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pressure altimeter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a military airport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choiceone": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choicetwo": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should be the indication on the magnetic compass as you roll into a standard rate\nturn to the right from a south heading in the Northern Hemisphere?\n",
        "answer": "The compass will indicate a turn to the right, but at a faster rate than is actually\noccurring.\n",
        "choiceone": "The compass will initially indicate a turn to the left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The compass will remain on south for a short time, then gradually catch up to the\nmagnetic heading of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the maximum tolerance for the VOI ication when the CDI is centered and\nthe aircraft is directly over the airborne checkpoint?\n",
        "answer": "Plus or minus 6 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus 6degrees or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Plus or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the indications of the pulsating VASI?\n",
        "answer": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - steady white, slightly below glide slope steady\nred, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choiceone": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - green, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High - pulsing white, on course and on glidepath - steady white, off course but on\nglidepath - pulsing white and red; low - pulsing red.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify taxi leadoff lights associated with the centerline lighting system.\n",
        "answer": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to a point\non the exit.\n",
        "choiceone": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\ncenterline of the taxiway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\nedge of the taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true about magnetic deviation of a compass?\n",
        "answer": "Deviation varies for different headings of the same aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Deviation is the same for all aircraft in the same locality.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deviation is different in a given aircraft in different localities.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify touchdown zone lighting (TDZL).\n",
        "answer": "Two rows of transverse light bars disposed symmetrically about the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flush centerline lights spaced at 50-foot intervals extending through the touchdown\nzone.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate white and green centerline lights extending from 75 feet from the threshold\nthrough the touchdown zone.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot Head and Static Vent were blocked by ice, which instruments would be\naffected?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter, VSI and ASI would give inaccurate readings.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and Slip indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ASI would under read.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A simple pressure altimeter uses:\n",
        "answer": "static pressure fed into a gas tight casing, but outside a partially evacuated capsule\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure fed to an open capsule\n",
        "choicetwo": "pitot pressure fed to an open capsule\n",
        "choicethree": "static pressure fed outside a completely evacuated aneroid capsule.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot opening is blocked, whi\nvent)?\n\nstruments would be affected (separate static\n",
        "answer": "ASI only.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and VSI.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ASI and VSI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rectified Airspeed is:\n",
        "answer": "IAS corrected for instrument and pressure error.\n",
        "choiceone": "IAS corrected for density error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IAS corrected for density and compressibility errors.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "VFE is the maximum speed:\n",
        "answer": "with the flaps extended.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the flaps extended in the landing configuration.\n",
        "choicetwo": "with the flaps extended in the take-off configuration.\n",
        "choicethree": "at which the flaps can be operated when flying in turbulences.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The uncontrolled firing of the fuel/air charge in advance of normal spark ignition is\nknown as\n",
        "answer": "pre-ignition.\n",
        "choiceone": "instantaneous combustion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "detonation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first indication of carburetor ice in an aircraft with a fixed-pitch propeller is\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in RPM.\n",
        "choiceone": "a decrease in manifold pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase in manifold pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Detonation occurs at high power settings when the\n",
        "answer": "fuel mixture explodes instead of burning progressively and evenly.\n",
        "choiceone": "fuel mixture is ignited too early by red-hot carbon deposits in the cylinder.\n",
        "choicetwo": "intake valve opens before the previous charge of fuel has finished burning in the\ncylinder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An electrical system failure (battery and alternator) occurs during flight. In this situation,\nyou would\n",
        "answer": "perience avionics equipment failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "probably experience failure of the engine ignition system, fuel gauges, aircraft\nlighting system, and avionics equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "probably experience engine failure due to the loss of the engine-driven fuel pump\nand also experience failure of the radio equipment, lights, and all instruments that\nrequire alternating current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of an elevator trim tab?\n",
        "answer": "Modify the downward tail load for various airspeeds in flight eliminating flight-control\npressures.\n",
        "choiceone": "Provide horizontal balance as airspeed is increased to allow hands-off flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Adjust the speed tail load for different airspeeds in flight allowing neutral control\nforces.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aeroplane, spoilers are :\n",
        "answer": "upper wing surface devices, their deflection is symmetrical or asymmetrical.\n",
        "choiceone": "lower wing surface devices, their deflection is always asymmetrical.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lower wing surface devices, their deflection is symmetrical or asymmetrical.\n",
        "choicethree": "upper wing surface devices, their deflection is always asymmetrical.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is considered an auxiliary flight control?\n",
        "answer": "Leading-edge flaps.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ruddervator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Upper rudder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "By changing the angle of attack of a wing, the pilot can control the airplane's\n",
        "answer": "lift, airspeed, and drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "lift, gross weight, and drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lift and airspeed, but not drag.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is load factor?\n",
        "answer": "Lift divided by the total weight.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lift multiplied by the total weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Lift subtracted from the total weight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aircraft landing gear, an under-inflated tyre:\n",
        "answer": "will wear at the shoulders\n",
        "choiceone": "it's tread will deteriorate faster\n",
        "choicetwo": "will have an increased critical hydroplanning speed\n",
        "choicethree": "will be more subject to viscosity aquaplaning on dry runway\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A tubeless tyre has : 1- a built-in-air tube. 2- no built-in-air tube. 3-acrossed\ncasing. 4- a radial side casing. The combination of correct statements is:\n\n",
        "answer": "2,4.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2, 3.\n",
        "choicethree": "1,3.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pressure in the cabin tends to become lower than the outside ambient air pressure\nthe:\n",
        "answer": "negative pressure relief valve will open.\n",
        "choiceone": "outflow valve open completely.\n",
        "choicetwo": "air cycle machine will stop.\n",
        "choicethree": "negative pressure relief valve will close\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a bootstrap cooling system the supply air is first :\n",
        "answer": "compressed, passed through a secondary heat exchanger, and then across an\nexpansion turbine.\n",
        "choiceone": "passed across an expansion turbine, then directly to the heat exchanger.\n",
        "choicetwo": "used to increase the cabin air supply pressure when the charge pressure is too low.\n",
        "choicethree": "passed across an expansion turbine, then compressed and passed through a\nsecondary heat exchanger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term \"Bootstrap\", when used to identify a cabin air conditioning and pressurisation\nsystem, refers to the :\n",
        "answer": "cold air unit (air cycle machine) arrangement.\n",
        "choiceone": "source of the charge air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "means by which pressurisation is controlled.\n",
        "choicethree": "charge air across the inter-cooler heat exchanger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cVapor lock\" is the phenomenon by which:\n",
        "answer": "heat produces vapour plugs in the fuel line.\n",
        "choiceone": "burnt gas plugs forming and remaining in the exhaust manifold following an\noverheat and thereby disturbing the exhaust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "water vapour plugs are formed in the intake fuel line following the condensation of\nwater in fuel tanks which have not been drained for sometime.\n",
        "choicethree": "abrupt and abnormal enrichment of the fuel/air mixture following an inappropriate\nuse of carburettor heat.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a current is passed through a conductor,\n",
        "answer": "a force will be exerted on the conductor.\n",
        "choiceone": "the current will increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there will be no effect unless the conductor is moved.\n",
        "choicethree": "the intensity of the magnetic field will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The part of a piston engine that transforms reciprocating movement into rotary motion\nis termed as the :\n",
        "answer": "crankshaft\n",
        "choiceone": "reduction gear\n",
        "choicetwo": "piston\n",
        "choicethree": "camshaft\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The turbine in a cold air unit (air cycle machine):\n",
        "answer": "drives the compressor in the unit, creating a temperature drop in the conditioning\nair.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases the pressure of the air supply to the cabin.\n",
        "choicetwo": "drives the compressor in the unit and causes a pressure increase in the\nconditioning air.\n",
        "choicethree": "drives the compressor which provides pressurisation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a fire detection system with single-loop continuous\n",
        "answer": "the fire alarm is triggered.\n",
        "choiceone": "the power supply is cut off automatically.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there will be no effect on the system\n",
        "choicethree": "the engine fire extinguisher striker is automatically activated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The state in which the breathing oxygen for the cockpit of jet transport aeroplanes is\nstored is :\n",
        "answer": "Gaseous.\n",
        "choiceone": "Chemical compound.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Liquid.\n",
        "choicethree": "Gaseous or chemical compound..\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to starting the engine, the manifold pressure gauge usually\napproximately 29\" Hg. This is because the\n",
        "answer": "pressure within the manifold is the same as atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "pointer on the gauge is stuck at the full-power indication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "throttle is closed, trapping high air pressure in the manifold.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify touchdown zone lighting (TDZL).\n",
        "answer": "Two rows of transverse light bars disposed symmetrically about the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flush centerline lights spaced at 50-foot intervals extending through the touchdown\nzone.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate white and green centerline lights extending from 75 feet from the threshold\nthrough the touchdown zone.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a military airport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choiceone": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choicetwo": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 140.) Which\nthe 1.9 NM pointis indicated?\n\nplacement from the localizer and glide slope at\n",
        "answer": "710 feet to the right of the localizer centerline and 140 feet above the glide slope.\n",
        "choiceone": "710 feet to the left of the localizer centerline and 140 feet below the glide slope.\n",
        "choicetwo": "430 feet to the right of the localizer centerline and 28 feet above the glide slope.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a lighted heliport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choiceone": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true concerning gyroplane operations?\n",
        "answer": "Minimum level flight speed is established when all available power is used to\nmaintain constant altitude and airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rotor RPM will decrease during a vertical descent regardless of weight or density\naltitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A gyroplane can take off from any area in which it can safely land.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the maximum tolerance for the VOI ication when the CDI is centered and\nthe aircraft is directly over the airborne checkpoint?\n",
        "answer": "Plus or minus 6 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus 6degrees or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Plus or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true about magnetic deviation of a compass?\n",
        "answer": "Deviation varies for different headings of the same aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Deviation is the same for all aircraft in the same locality.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deviation is different in a given aircraft in different localities.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When making an airborne VOR check, what is the maximum allowable tolerance\nbetween the two indicators of a dual VOR system (units independent of each other\nexcept the antenna)?\n\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees between the two indicated bearings of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus or minus 4 degrees when set to identical radials of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 degrees between the two indicated radials of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, a magnetic compass will normally indicate a turn toward\n\nthe north if\n",
        "answer": "an aircraft is accelerated while on an east or west heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "a left turn is entered from a west heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an aircraft is decelerated while on an east or west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the advantage of a three-bar VASI?\n",
        "answer": "A normal glide angle is afforded both high and low cockpit aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Pilots have a choice of glide angles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The three-bar VASI is much more visible and can be used at a greater height.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, if an aircrat\ncompass will normally indicate\n\naccelerated or decelerated, the magnetic\n",
        "answer": "correctly when on a north or south heading while either accelerating or decelerating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a turn momentarily, with changes in airspeed on any heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a turn toward the south while accelerating on a west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A possible result of using the emergency alternate source of static pressure inside the\ncabin of an unpressurized airplane is the\n",
        "answer": "altimeter may indicate an altitude higher than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "airspeed indicator may indicate less than normal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter may indicate an altitude lower than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot Head and Static Vent were blocked by ice, which instruments would be\naffected?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter, VSI and ASI would give inaccurate readings.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and Slip indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ASI would under read.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VSI may suffer from error due to:\n",
        "answer": "time lag, instrument calibration, blockage\n",
        "choiceone": "compressibility, time lag, blockage\n",
        "choicetwo": "density, aircraft manoeuvre, position of the static vent\n",
        "choicethree": "pitot blockage, static blockage, aircraft manoeuvre\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ASI consists of a gas tight casing which has:\n",
        "answer": "pitot pressure fed into an open capsule and static pressure fed outside the capsule\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule and pitot pressure fed into a second\nopen capsule\n",
        "choicetwo": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule\n",
        "choicethree": "static pressure fed through a restrictive choke\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rectified Airspeed is:\n",
        "answer": "IAS corrected for instrument and pressure error.\n",
        "choiceone": "IAS corrected for density error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IAS corrected for density and compressibility errors.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a stabilised climbing turn at a constant rate, the instruments which indicate the\n\ncorrect pitch and bank are the:\n",
        "answer": "attitude indicator and turn-and-slip indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "vertical-speed indicator and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the engine oil temperature and cylinder head temperature gauges have exceeded their\nnormal operating range, you may have been\n",
        "answer": "operating with too much power and with the mixture set too lean.\n",
        "choiceone": "operating with the mixture set too rich.\n",
        "choicetwo": "using fuel that has a higher-than-specified fuel rating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the ground wire between the magneto and the ignition switch becomes disconnected,\nthe most noticeable result will be that the engine\n",
        "answer": "cannot be shut down by turning the switch to the OFF position.\n",
        "choiceone": "will run very rough.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cannot be started with the switch in the ON position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the CFR Part 1 definition of critical engine?\n",
        "answer": "The engine whose failure would most adversely affect airplane performance or\nhandling qualities.\n",
        "choiceone": "The outboard engine whose failure would most adversely affect safety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The engine still running which would most adversely affect performance if it should\nfail.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One advantage of fuel injection systems over carburetor systems is\n",
        "answer": "better fuel distribution to the cylinders.\n",
        "choiceone": "easier hot-engine starting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "less difficulty with hot weather vapor locks during ground operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An electrical system failure (battery and alternator) occurs during flight. In this situation,\nyou would\n",
        "answer": "perience avionics equipment failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "probably experience failure of the engine ignition system, fuel gauges, aircraft\nlighting system, and avionics equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "probably experience engine failure due to the loss of the engine-driven fuel pump\nand also experience failure of the radio equipment, lights, and all instruments that\nrequire alternating current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Air cooled engines dissipate heat\n",
        "answer": "through cooling fins on the cylinder and head.\n",
        "choiceone": "by air flowing through the radiator fins.\n",
        "choicetwo": "through the cylinder head temperature probe.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "constant angle of bank and altitude?\n",
        "answer": "The rate of turn will decrease resulting in no changes in load factor.\n",
        "choiceone": "The rate of turn will decrease resulting in a decreased load factor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The rate of turn will increase resulting in an increased load factor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the relationship of the rate of turn with the radius of turn with a constant angle of\nbank but increasing airspeed?\n",
        "answer": "Rate will decrease and radius will increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rate will increase and radius will decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rate and radius will increase.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a steep turn to the left, when using spoilers ...\n",
        "answer": "The right aileron will descend, the left one will ascend, the right spoiler will retract\nand the left one will extend.\n",
        "choiceone": "The right aileron will descend, the left one will ascend, the right spoiler will extend\nand the left one will retract.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The right aileron will ascend, the left one will descend, the right spoiler will extend\nand the left one will retract.\n",
        "choicethree": "The right aileron will ascend, the left one will descend, the right spoiler will retract\nand the left one will extend.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a hydraulic braking system, the accumulator is:\n",
        "answer": "an accumulator designed to restore brake energy in the event of a hydraulic failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "a damping type accumulator designed to take up the pressure fluctuations of the\nautomatic braking system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "designed to take up the hydraulic energy filtered by the anti-skid system in order to\nprevent wheel blocking.\n",
        "choicethree": "a buffer accumulator whose function is to assist the hydraulic system during high\nintensity braking.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thermal plugs are installed in:\n",
        "answer": "wheel rims.\n",
        "choiceone": "cabin windows.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cargo compartments.\n",
        "choicethree": "fire warning systems.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cConditioned\u201d air is air that has :\n",
        "answer": "been controlled in respect of temperature and pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "had any moisture removed from it.\n",
        "choicetwo": "had the oxygen content increased.\n",
        "choicethree": "had the oxygen content reduced.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cabin altitude means the:\n",
        "answer": "cabin pressure expressed as altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight level the aircraft is flying at.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight level altitude at maximum differential pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "difference in height between the cabin floor and ceiling.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the preheating coil used in hot air balloons is to\n",
        "answer": "vaporize the fuel for more efficient burner operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "prevent ice from forming in the fuel lines.\n",
        "choicetwo": "warm the fuel tanks for more efficient fuel flow.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Electrical bonding of an aircraft is used to: 1. protect the aircraft against lightning effects.\n2. reset the electrostatic potential of the aircraft to a value approximating 0 volt 3. reduce\nradio interference on radiocommunication systems 4. set the aircraft to a single\npotential The combination regrouping all the correct statements\n",
        "answer": "1,3,4\n",
        "choiceone": "1,2,3\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,4\n",
        "choicethree": "2,4\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the ground wire between the magneto and the ignition switch becomes disconnected,\nthe most noticeable result will be that the engine\n",
        "answer": "cannot be shut down by turning the switch to the OFF position.\n",
        "choiceone": "will not operate at the right magneto:\n",
        "choicetwo": "cannot be started with the switch in the ON position\n",
        "choicethree": "will not operate at the left magneto\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The oil system for a piston engine incorporates an oil cooler that is fitted :\n",
        "answer": "in the return line to the oil tank after the oil has passed through the scavenge pump\n",
        "choiceone": "between the oil tank and the pressure pump\n",
        "choicetwo": "after the pressure pump but before the oil passes through the engine\n",
        "choicethree": "after the oil has passed through the engine and before it enters the sump\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When altitude increases without adjustment of the mixture ratio, the piston engine\nperformance is affected because of a:\n",
        "answer": "decrease of air density for a constant quantity of fuel.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease of air density for a smaller quantity of fuel.\n",
        "choicetwo": "constant air density for a bigger quantity of fuel.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase of air density for smaller quantity of fuel.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "in a piston engine turbo-supercharger centrifugal compressor :\n",
        "answer": "enters the eye of the impeller and leaves at a tangent to the periphery.\n",
        "choiceone": "enters at the periphery and leaves via the eye of the impeller.\n",
        "choicetwo": "enters at a tangent to the rotor and leaves via the stator.\n",
        "choicethree": "enters via the diffuser and is fed to the impeller at the optimum angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The disadvantages of a chemical oxygen source for the passenger cabin are : 1. a flow\nwhich cannot be modulated, 2. a heavy and bulky system, 3. non reversible functioning,\n4. risks of explosion, 5. poor autonomy. The combination regrouping all the correct\n\nstatements is:\n",
        "answer": "1,3,5\n",
        "choiceone": "1,2,3,4,5\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,4\n",
        "choicethree": "1,2,3,5\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to starting the engine, the manifold pressure gauge usually\napproximately 29\" Hg. This is because the\n",
        "answer": "pressure within the manifold is the same as atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "pointer on the gauge is stuck at the full-power indication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "throttle is closed, trapping high air pressure in the manifold.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the indications of the pulsating VASI?\n",
        "answer": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - steady white, slightly below glide slope steady\nred, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choiceone": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - green, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High - pulsing white, on course and on glidepath - steady white, off course but on\nglidepath - pulsing white and red; low - pulsing red.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the static pressure tubes are broken inside a pressurized cabin during a high-altitude\nflight, the altimeter would probably indicate\n",
        "answer": "lower than actual flight altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "sea level.\n",
        "choicetwo": "higher than actual flight altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 141.) Which displacement from the localizer centerline and\nglide slope at the 1,300-foot point from the runway is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "21 feet above the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "21 feet below the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the right of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "28 feet above the glide slope and approximately 250 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true about magnetic deviation of a compass?\n",
        "answer": "Deviation varies for different headings of the same aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Deviation is the same for all aircraft in the same locality.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deviation is different in a given aircraft in different localities.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the maximum tolerance for the VOI ication when the CDI is centered and\nthe aircraft is directly over the airborne checkpoint?\n",
        "answer": "Plus or minus 6 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus 6degrees or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Plus or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot head is blocked, what airspeed indication can he expected?\n",
        "answer": "No change of IAS in level flight, even with large power changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "A decrease of IAS during a climb.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Constant IAS during a descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true concerning gyroplane operations?\n",
        "answer": "Minimum level flight speed is established when all available power is used to\nmaintain constant altitude and airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rotor RPM will decrease during a vertical descent regardless of weight or density\naltitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A gyroplane can take off from any area in which it can safely land.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A gyroplane will have the greatest tendency to roll during\n",
        "answer": "horizontal flight at high speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "climbing flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "descending flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which procedure is recommended to prevent or overcome spatial disorientation?\n",
        "answer": "Rely entirely on the indications of the flight instruments.\n",
        "choiceone": "Avoid steep turns and rough control movements.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Reduce head and eye movements to the greatest extent possible.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deviation error of the magnetic compass is caused by\n",
        "answer": "certain metals and electrical systems within the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "northerly turning error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the difference in location of true north and magnetic north.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A possible result of using the emergency alternate source of static pressure inside the\ncabin of an unpressurized airplane is the\n",
        "answer": "altimeter may indicate an altitude higher than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "airspeed indicator may indicate less than normal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter may indicate an altitude lower than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an altimeter is changed from 30.11\" Hg to 29.96\" Hg,\nindicated altitude change and by what value?\n\nwhich direction will the\n\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter will indicate 150 feet lower.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altimeter will indicate 15 feet lower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altimeter will indicate 150 feet higher.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot Head and Static Vent were blocked by ice, which instruments would be\naffected?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter, VSI and ASI would give inaccurate readings.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and Slip indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ASI would under read.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VSI may suffer from error due to:\n",
        "answer": "time lag, instrument calibration, blockage\n",
        "choiceone": "compressibility, time lag, blockage\n",
        "choicetwo": "density, aircraft manoeuvre, position of the static vent\n",
        "choicethree": "pitot blockage, static blockage, aircraft manoeuvre\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A simple pressure altimeter uses:\n",
        "answer": "static pressure fed into a gas tight casing, but outside a partially evacuated capsule\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure fed to an open capsule\n",
        "choicetwo": "pitot pressure fed to an open capsule\n",
        "choicethree": "static pressure fed outside a completely evacuated aneroid capsule.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "VFE is the maximum speed:\n",
        "answer": "with the flaps extended.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the flaps extended in the landing configuration.\n",
        "choicetwo": "with the flaps extended in the take-off configuration.\n",
        "choicethree": "at which the flaps can be operated when flying in turbulences.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot opening is blocked, whi\nvent)?\n\nstruments would be affected (separate static\n",
        "answer": "ASI only.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and VSI.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ASI and VSI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a stabilised climbing turn at a constant rate, the instruments which indicate the\n\ncorrect pitch and bank are the:\n",
        "answer": "attitude indicator and turn-and-slip indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "vertical-speed indicator and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which stroke of a reciprocating engine is the gaseous mixture expanding within\nthe cylinder?\n",
        "answer": "Power.\n",
        "choiceone": "Intake.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Compression.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first indication of carburetor ice in an aircraft with a four-cycle engine and fixed-\npitch propeller is\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in RPM.\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase in RPM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a decrease in oil pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Detonation occurs at high power settings when the\n",
        "answer": "fuel mixture explodes instead of burning progressively and evenly.\n",
        "choiceone": "fuel mixture is ignited too early by red-hot carbon deposits in the cylinder.\n",
        "choicetwo": "intake valve opens before the previous charge of fuel has finished burning in the\ncylinder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "2-cycle engine thrust and fuel efficiency can be greatly compromised when\n",
        "answer": "exhaust systems are installed that are not specifically tuned for an engine.\n",
        "choiceone": "carbon deposits build up on exhaust valves.\n",
        "choicetwo": "intake valve lifters fail to pressurize and provide adequate fuel to the combustion\nchamber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a characteristic of longitudinal instability?\n",
        "answer": "Pitch oscillations becoming progressively greater.\n",
        "choiceone": "Bank oscillations becoming progressively greater.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft constantly tries to pitch down.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are considered primary flight controls?\n",
        "answer": "Outboard ailerons.\n",
        "choiceone": "Tabs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flaps.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can turbulent air cause an increase in stalling speed of an airfoil?\n",
        "answer": "An abrupt change in relative wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "A decrease in angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sudden decrease in load factor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An artificial feel unit is necessary in the pitch channel when:\n",
        "answer": "the elevators are actuated by irreversible servo-control units.\n",
        "choiceone": "the elevators are actuated by reversible servo-control units.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elevators are fitted with servo-tabs or trim tabs.\n",
        "choicethree": "there is a trimmable stabilizer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why must the angle of attack be increased during a turn to maintain altitude?\n",
        "answer": "Compensate for loss of vertical component of lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increase the horizontal component of lift equal to the vertical component.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Compensate for increase in drag.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can the pilot increase the rate of turn and decrease the radius at the same time?\n",
        "answer": "Steepen the bank and decrease airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Steepen the bank and increase airspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Shallow the bank and increase airspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The part of the flight that will cause the highest loads on tyre\n",
        "answer": "Taxiing with a small turning radius.\n",
        "choiceone": "Touch down with crosswind\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gear down selection\n",
        "choicethree": "Braking with an inoperative anti skid system.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The type of brake unit found on most transport aeroplanes is a:\n",
        "answer": "Multiple disk brake.\n",
        "choiceone": "Drum type brake.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Single disk brake.\n",
        "choicethree": "Belt brake.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pressure in the cabin tends to become lower than the outside ambient air pressure\nthe:\n",
        "answer": "negative pressure relief valve will open.\n",
        "choiceone": "outflow valve open completely.\n",
        "choicetwo": "air cycle machine will stop.\n",
        "choicethree": "negative pressure relief valve will close\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pressurization of tanks is maintained by the fuel:\n",
        "answer": "vent system.\n",
        "choiceone": "tank drains.\n",
        "choicetwo": "top off unit.\n",
        "choicethree": "dump system.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The function of the Generator Breaker is to close when the voltage of the :\n",
        "answer": "generator is greater than battery voltage\n",
        "choiceone": "alternator is greater than the battery voltage and to open\n",
        "choicetwo": "battery is greater than the alternator voltage and to open\n",
        "choicethree": "battery is greater than the generator voltage and to open\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A feeder fault on a direct current circuit results from a flux unbalance between the:\n",
        "answer": "voltage coil and the series winding turn.\n",
        "choiceone": "shunt exciter and the series winding turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "voltage coil and the series winding.\n",
        "choicethree": "generator and the series winding turn.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The output of a generator is controlled by :\n",
        "answer": "varying the field strength.\n",
        "choiceone": "varying the length of wire in the armature windings.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the reverse current relay circuit breaker.\n",
        "choicethree": "varying the speed of the engine.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The part of a piston engine that transforms reciprocating movement into rotary motion\nis termed as the :\n",
        "answer": "crankshaft\n",
        "choiceone": "reduction gear\n",
        "choicetwo": "piston\n",
        "choicethree": "camshaft\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In general, in twin-engine aeroplanes with \u2018constant speed propeller\u2019\n",
        "answer": "the oil pressure turns the propeller blades towards smaller pitch angle.\n",
        "choiceone": "the aerodynamic force turns the propeller blades towards higher pitch angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the spring force turns the propeller blades towards smaller pitch angle.\n",
        "choicethree": "the oil pressure turns the propeller blades towards higher pitch angle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "in a piston engine turbo-supercharger centrifugal compressor :\n",
        "answer": "enters the eye of the impeller and leaves at a tangent to the periphery.\n",
        "choiceone": "enters at the periphery and leaves via the eye of the impeller.\n",
        "choicetwo": "enters at a tangent to the rotor and leaves via the stator.\n",
        "choicethree": "enters via the diffuser and is fed to the impeller at the optimum angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which may lead to a power push-over in a gyroplane?\n",
        "answer": "Rotor force is removed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decreasing power too quickly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the static pressure tubes are broken inside a pressurized cabin during a high-altitude\nflight, the altimeter would probably indicate\n",
        "answer": "lower than actual flight altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "sea level.\n",
        "choicetwo": "higher than actual flight altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify touchdown zone lighting (TDZL).\n",
        "answer": "Two rows of transverse light bars disposed symmetrically about the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flush centerline lights spaced at 50-foot intervals extending through the touchdown\nzone.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate white and green centerline lights extending from 75 feet from the threshold\nthrough the touchdown zone.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a pitot tube is clogged, which instrument would be affected?\n",
        "answer": "Airspeed indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altimeter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vertical speed indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A gyroplane will have the greatest tendency to roll during\n",
        "answer": "horizontal flight at high speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "climbing flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "descending flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When making an airborne VOR check, what is the maximum allowable tolerance\nbetween the two indicators of a dual VOR system (units independent of each other\nexcept the antenna)?\n\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees between the two indicated bearings of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus or minus 4 degrees when set to identical radials of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 degrees between the two indicated radials of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the advantage of a three-bar VASI?\n",
        "answer": "A normal glide angle is afforded both high and low cockpit aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Pilots have a choice of glide angles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The three-bar VASI is much more visible and can be used at a greater height.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 141.) Which displacement from the localizer centerline and\nglide slope at the 1,300-foot point from the runway is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "21 feet above the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "21 feet below the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the right of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "28 feet above the glide slope and approximately 250 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify runway remaining lighting on centerline lighting systems.\n",
        "answer": "Alternate red and white lights from 3,000 feet to 1,000 feet, then red lights to the end.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber lights from 3,000 feet to 1,000 feet, then alternate red and white lights to the\nend.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate red and white lights from 3,000 feet to the end of the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify taxi leadoff lights associated with the centerline lighting system.\n",
        "answer": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to a point\non the exit.\n",
        "choiceone": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\ncenterline of the taxiway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\nedge of the taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, which would be correct about starting the rollout from a\nturn using a magnetic compass? Start the rollout\n",
        "answer": "after the compass indication passes south by a number of degrees approximately\nequal to the latitude minus the normal rollout lead.\n",
        "choiceone": "before the compass indication reaches south by a number of degrees approximately\nequal to the latitude over which the turn is made plus the pilot's normal lead.\n",
        "choicetwo": "after the compass indication passes south by a number of degrees approximately\nequal to the magnetic variation of the area over which the turn is made plus the\npilot's normal lead.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot Head and Static Vent were blocked by ice, which instruments would be\naffected?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter, VSI and ASI would give inaccurate readings.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and Slip indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ASI would under read.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pitot line is blocked, the VSI will:\n",
        "answer": "read normally\n",
        "choiceone": "read zero ftmm rate of climb/descent\n",
        "choicetwo": "over-read\n",
        "choicethree": "under-read\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A simple pressure altimeter uses:\n",
        "answer": "static pressure fed into a gas tight casing, but outside a partially evacuated capsule\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure fed to an open capsule\n",
        "choicetwo": "pitot pressure fed to an open capsule\n",
        "choicethree": "static pressure fed outside a completely evacuated aneroid capsule.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "QNH is the sub-scale setting which will cause the altimeter to read:\n",
        "answer": "vertical displacement above mean sea level\n",
        "choiceone": "the altitude at which any given pressure exists in the standard atmosphere\n",
        "choicetwo": "vertical displacement above the airfield pressure datum\n",
        "choicethree": "pressure altitude\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Transition altitude is obtained from:\n",
        "answer": "Jeppesen or Aerad flight guides.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC or VOR ATIS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1500 feet above airfield elevation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "VFE is the maximum speed:\n",
        "answer": "with the flaps extended.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the flaps extended in the landing configuration.\n",
        "choicetwo": "with the flaps extended in the take-off configuration.\n",
        "choicethree": "at which the flaps can be operated when flying in turbulences.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a stabilised climbing turn at a constant rate, the instruments which indicate the\n\ncorrect pitch and bank are the:\n",
        "answer": "attitude indicator and turn-and-slip indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "vertical-speed indicator and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (27).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of a kill switch is to\n",
        "answer": "ground the lead wire to the ignition coil shutting down the powerplant.\n",
        "choiceone": "shut off the fuel to the carburetor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ground the battery eliminating current for the ignition system.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first indication of carburetor ice in an aircraft with a fixed-pitch propeller is\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in RPM.\n",
        "choiceone": "a decrease in manifold pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase in manifold pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the CFR Part 1 definition of critical engine?\n",
        "answer": "The engine whose failure would most adversely affect airplane performance or\nhandling qualities.\n",
        "choiceone": "The outboard engine whose failure would most adversely affect safety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The engine still running which would most adversely affect performance if it should\nfail.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Adding more oil to the fuel than specified by the manufacturer of a 2-cycle engine will\nresult in\n",
        "answer": "increased carbon buildup and engine fouling.\n",
        "choiceone": "increased engine performance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increased engine lubrication and optimal performance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Running a fuel tank dry before switching tanks is not a good practice because\n",
        "answer": "the engine-driven fuel pump or electric fuel boost pump draw air into the fuel system\nand cause vapor lock.\n",
        "choiceone": "any foreign matter in the tank will be pumped into the fuel system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the engine-driven fuel pump is lubricated by fuel and operating on a dry tank may\ncause pump failure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the fuel tank vent system is to\n",
        "answer": "allow air to enter the tank as fuel is consumed.\n",
        "choiceone": "remove dangerous vapors from the aircraft and prevent an explosion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ensure a proper fuel to air ratio.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of carburetor ice in an aircraft equipped with a fixed-pitch propeller can be\nverified by applying carburetor heat and noting\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in RPM and then a gradual increase in RPM.\n",
        "choiceone": "a decrease in RPM and then a constant RPM indication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase in RPM and then a gradual decrease in RPM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A high-frequency vibration that suddenly occurs during flight could be an indication of a\ndefective\n",
        "answer": "transmission.\n",
        "choiceone": "ignition system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "freewheeling unit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "By changing the angle of attack of a wing, the pilot can control the airplane's\n",
        "answer": "lift, airspeed, and drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "lift, gross weight, and drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lift and airspeed, but not drag.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is considered a primary flight control?\n",
        "answer": "Elevator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Slats.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dorsal fin.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a steep turn to the left, when using spoilers ...\n",
        "answer": "The right aileron will descend, the left one will ascend, the right spoiler will retract\nand the left one will extend.\n",
        "choiceone": "The right aileron will descend, the left one will ascend, the right spoiler will extend\nand the left one will retract.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The right aileron will ascend, the left one will descend, the right spoiler will extend\nand the left one will retract.\n",
        "choicethree": "The right aileron will ascend, the left one will descend, the right spoiler will retract\nand the left one will extend.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What affects indicated stall speed?\n",
        "answer": "Weight, load factor, and power.\n",
        "choiceone": "Load factor, angle of attack, and power.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Angle of attack, weight, and air density.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fuselage of an aircraft consists, among others, of stringers whose purpose is to:\n",
        "answer": "assist the skin in absorbing the longitudinal traction-compression stresses.\n",
        "choiceone": "withstand the shear stresses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "provide sound and thermal isolation.\n",
        "choicethree": "integrate the strains due to pressurization to which the skin is subjected and convert\nthem into a tensile stress.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A tubeless tyre has : 1- a built-in-air tube. 2- no built-in-air tube. 3-acrossed\ncasing. 4- a radial side casing. The combination of correct statements is:\n\n",
        "answer": "2,4.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2, 3.\n",
        "choicethree": "1,3.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the cabin altitude rises (aircraft in level flight), the differential pressure:\n",
        "answer": "decreases\n",
        "choiceone": "increases\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains constant\n",
        "choicethree": "may exceed the maximum permitted differential unless immediate preventative\naction is taken.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming cabin pressure decreases, the cabin rate of climb indicator should indicate :\n",
        "answer": "a rate of climb.\n",
        "choiceone": "a rate of descent of approximately 300 feet per minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "zero.\n",
        "choicethree": "a rate of descent dependent upon the cabin differential pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During fuelling the automatic fuelling shut off valves will\n",
        "answer": "the fuel has reached a predetermined volume or mass.\n",
        "choiceone": "the surge vent tank is filled.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there is fire.\n",
        "choicethree": "fuelling system has reached a certain pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cVapor lock\" is the phenomenon by which:\n",
        "answer": "heat produces vapour plugs in the fuel line.\n",
        "choiceone": "burnt gas plugs forming and remaining in the exhaust manifold following an\noverheat and thereby disturbing the exhaust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "water vapour plugs are formed in the intake fuel line following the condensation of\nwater in fuel tanks which have not been drained for sometime.\n",
        "choicethree": "abrupt and abnormal enrichment of the fuel/air mixture following an inappropriate\nuse of carburettor heat.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the ground wire between the magnetos and the ig\ndisconnected the most noticeable result will be that:\n",
        "answer": "the engine cannot be shut down by turning the ignition switch to the \"OFF\" position\n",
        "choiceone": "a still operating engine will run down\n",
        "choicetwo": "the engine cannot be started with the ignition switch in the \"ON\" position\n",
        "choicethree": "the power developed by the engine will be strongly reduced\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The control of free turbine engines on turboprops, is accomplished by: -a propeller\ncontrol lever used to select: 1- propeller RPM 2.-turbine temperature 3 - turbine RPM\n- a fuel control lever used to select: 4- propeller RPM 5 - torque 6 - turbine temperature\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is :\n",
        "answer": "1-5-6\n",
        "choiceone": "1-3-5\n",
        "choicetwo": "3-4-6\n",
        "choicethree": "2-4-5\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to starting the engine, the manifold pressure gauge usually\napproximately 29\" Hg. This is because the\n",
        "answer": "pressure within the manifold is the same as atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "pointer on the gauge is stuck at the full-power indication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "throttle is closed, trapping high air pressure in the manifold.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which pul\nbe found?\n\nition can the VOR receiver ground checkpoint(s) for a particular\n",
        "answer": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "En Route Low Altitude Chart.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A possible result of using the emergency alternate source of static pressure inside the\ncabin of an unpressurized airplane is the\n",
        "answer": "altimeter may indicate an altitude higher than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "airspeed indicator may indicate less than normal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter may indicate an altitude lower than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 141.) Which displacement from the localizer centerline and\nglide slope at the 1,300-foot point from the runway is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "21 feet above the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "21 feet below the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the right of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "28 feet above the glide slope and approximately 250 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true concerning gyroplane operations?\n",
        "answer": "Minimum level flight speed is established when all available power is used to\nmaintain constant altitude and airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rotor RPM will decrease during a vertical descent regardless of weight or density\naltitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A gyroplane can take off from any area in which it can safely land.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When making an airborne VOR check, what is the maximum allowable tolerance\nbetween the two indicators of a dual VOR system (units independent of each other\nexcept the antenna)?\n\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees between the two indicated bearings of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus or minus 4 degrees when set to identical radials of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 degrees between the two indicated radials of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a lighted heliport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choiceone": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the runway distance remaining markers.\n",
        "answer": "Signs with increments of 1,000 feet distance remaining.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red markers laterally placed across the runway at 3,000 feet from the end.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow marker laterally placed across the runway with signs on the side denoting\ndistance to end.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deviation error of the magnetic compass is caused by\n",
        "answer": "certain metals and electrical systems within the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "northerly turning error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the difference in location of true north and magnetic north.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which procedure is recommended to prevent or overcome spatial disorientation?\n",
        "answer": "Rely entirely on the indications of the flight instruments.\n",
        "choiceone": "Avoid steep turns and rough control movements.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Reduce head and eye movements to the greatest extent possible.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How will the airspeed icator react if the ram ai\nice, but the drain hole and static port are not?\n\nput to the pitot head is blocked by\n",
        "answer": "Indication will drop to zero.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indication will rise to the top of the scale.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indication will remain constant but will increase in a climb.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "nificance of the blue radial line on the airspeed\nmultiengine airplane and when is it to be used? It indicates the\n\n",
        "answer": "speed which will provide the maximum altitude gain in a given time when one engine\nis inoperative and should be used for climb and final approach during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "choiceone": "minimum speed at which the airplane is controllable when the critical engine is\nsuddenly made inoperative and should be used at all altitudes when an engine is\ninoperative.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed which will provide the greatest height for a given distance of forward travel\nwhen one engine is inoperative and should be used for all climbs during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true about magnetic deviation of a compass?\n",
        "answer": "Deviation varies for different headings of the same aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Deviation is the same for all aircraft in the same locality.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deviation is different in a given aircraft in different localities.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the advantage of a three-bar VASI?\n",
        "answer": "A normal glide angle is afforded both high and low cockpit aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Pilots have a choice of glide angles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The three-bar VASI is much more visible and can be used at a greater height.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which may lead to a power push-over in a gyroplane?\n",
        "answer": "Rotor force is removed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decreasing power too quickly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VSI may suffer from error due to:\n",
        "answer": "time lag, instrument calibration, blockage\n",
        "choiceone": "compressibility, time lag, blockage\n",
        "choicetwo": "density, aircraft manoeuvre, position of the static vent\n",
        "choicethree": "pitot blockage, static blockage, aircraft manoeuvre\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The high Altitude Radio Altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicethree": "metric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "VFE is the maximum speed:\n",
        "answer": "with the flaps extended.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the flaps extended in the landing configuration.\n",
        "choicetwo": "with the flaps extended in the take-off configuration.\n",
        "choicethree": "at which the flaps can be operated when flying in turbulences.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ASI consists of a gas tight casing which has:\n",
        "answer": "pitot pressure fed into an open capsule and static pressure fed outside the capsule\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule and pitot pressure fed into a second\nopen capsule\n",
        "choicetwo": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule\n",
        "choicethree": "static pressure fed through a restrictive choke\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rectified Airspeed is:\n",
        "answer": "IAS corrected for instrument and pressure error.\n",
        "choiceone": "IAS corrected for density error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IAS corrected for density and compressibility errors.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which stroke of a reciprocating engine is the gaseous mixture expanding within\nthe cylinder?\n",
        "answer": "Power.\n",
        "choiceone": "Intake.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Compression.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the ground wire between the magneto and the ignition switch becomes disconnected,\nthe most noticeable result will be that the engine\n",
        "answer": "cannot be shut down by turning the switch to the OFF position.\n",
        "choiceone": "will run very rough.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cannot be started with the switch in the ON position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true regarding fouling of the spark plugs of an aircraft engine?\n",
        "answer": "Spark plug fouling results from operating with an excessively rich mixture.\n",
        "choiceone": "Carbon fouling of the spark plugs is caused primarily by operating an engine at\nexcessively high cylinder head temperatures.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Excessive heat in the combustion chamber of a cylinder causes oil to form on the\ncenter electrode of a spark plug and this fouls the plug.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fuel vents on many powered parachutes and weight shift control aircraft are located\n",
        "answer": "in the fuel cap.\n",
        "choiceone": "adjacent to the crankcase breather.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in the fuel tank pressure relief valve.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A typical two-cycle engine ignition coil is powered by\n",
        "answer": "a magneto.\n",
        "choiceone": "a battery.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a battery or an alternator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When refueling aircraft, which precaution would be adequate for eli\npotential hazard of static electricity?\n\n",
        "answer": "Connect a ground wire between the aircraft, fuel truck, fuel nozzle, and ground.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ensure that battery and ignition switches are off.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Connect a ground wire from the fuel truck to ground.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The low temperature that causes carburetor ice in an engine equipped with a float-type\ncarburetor is normally the result of the\n",
        "answer": "vaporization of fuel and expansion of air in the carburetor.\n",
        "choiceone": "compression of air at the carburetor venturi.\n",
        "choicetwo": "freezing temperature of the air entering the carburetor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can turbulent air cause an increase in stalling speed of an airfoil?\n",
        "answer": "An abrupt change in relative wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "A decrease in angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sudden decrease in load factor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "constant angle of bank and altitude?\n",
        "answer": "The rate of turn will decrease resulting in no changes in load factor.\n",
        "choiceone": "The rate of turn will decrease resulting in a decreased load factor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The rate of turn will increase resulting in an increased load factor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is load factor?\n",
        "answer": "Lift divided by the total weight.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lift multiplied by the total weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Lift subtracted from the total weight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aircraft hydraulic system is designed to produce:\n",
        "answer": "high pressure and large flow.\n",
        "choiceone": "high pressure and small flow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "small pressure and large flow.\n",
        "choicethree": "small pressure and small flow.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The type of brake unit found on most transport aeroplanes is a:\n",
        "answer": "Multiple disk brake.\n",
        "choiceone": "Drum type brake.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Single disk brake.\n",
        "choicethree": "Belt brake.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thermal plugs are installed in:\n",
        "answer": "wheel rims.\n",
        "choiceone": "cabin windows.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cargo compartments.\n",
        "choicethree": "fire warning systems.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the cabin altitude rises (aircraft in level flight), the differential pressure:\n",
        "answer": "decreases\n",
        "choiceone": "increases\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains constant\n",
        "choicethree": "may exceed the maximum permitted differential unless immediate preventative\naction is taken.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main purpose of the mixture control is to:\n",
        "answer": "adjust the fuel flow to obtain the proper fuel/air ratio\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease the air supplied to the engine\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase the oxygen supplied to the engine\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease oxygen supplied to the engine\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During fuelling the automatic fuelling shut off valves will\n",
        "answer": "the fuel has reached a predetermined volume or mass.\n",
        "choiceone": "the surge vent tank is filled.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there is fire.\n",
        "choicethree": "fuelling system has reached a certain pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the ground wire between the magneto and the ignition switch becomes disconnected,\nthe most noticeable result will be that the engine\n",
        "answer": "cannot be shut down by turning the switch to the OFF position.\n",
        "choiceone": "will not operate at the right magneto:\n",
        "choicetwo": "cannot be started with the switch in the ON position\n",
        "choicethree": "will not operate at the left magneto\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "in a piston engine turbo-supercharger centrifugal compressor :\n",
        "answer": "enters the eye of the impeller and leaves at a tangent to the periphery.\n",
        "choiceone": "enters at the periphery and leaves via the eye of the impeller.\n",
        "choicetwo": "enters at a tangent to the rotor and leaves via the stator.\n",
        "choicethree": "enters via the diffuser and is fed to the impeller at the optimum angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Asynchronous four-pole motor is fed at a speed of\n",
        "answer": "12000 revolutions per minute.\n",
        "choiceone": "800 revolutions per minute.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1600 revolutions per minute.\n",
        "choicethree": "6000 revolutions per minute.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a fire detection system with single-loop continuous\n",
        "answer": "the fire alarm is triggered.\n",
        "choiceone": "the power supply is cut off automatically.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there will be no effect on the system\n",
        "choicethree": "the engine fire extinguisher striker is automatically activated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a pitot tube is clogged, which instrument would be affected?\n",
        "answer": "Airspeed indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altimeter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vertical speed indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true about magnetic deviation of a compass?\n",
        "answer": "Deviation varies for different headings of the same aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Deviation is the same for all aircraft in the same locality.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deviation is different in a given aircraft in different localities.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deviation error of the magnetic compass is caused by\n",
        "answer": "certain metals and electrical systems within the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "northerly turning error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the difference in location of true north and magnetic north.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the indications of the pulsating VASI?\n",
        "answer": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - steady white, slightly below glide slope steady\nred, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choiceone": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - green, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High - pulsing white, on course and on glidepath - steady white, off course but on\nglidepath - pulsing white and red; low - pulsing red.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A gyroplane will have the greatest tendency to roll during\n",
        "answer": "horizontal flight at high speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "climbing flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "descending flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which may lead to a power push-over in a gyroplane?\n",
        "answer": "Rotor force is removed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decreasing power too quickly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which pul\nbe found?\n\nition can the VOR receiver ground checkpoint(s) for a particular\n",
        "answer": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "En Route Low Altitude Chart.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, which would be correct about starting the rollout from a\nturn using a magnetic compass? Start the rollout\n",
        "answer": "after the compass indication passes south by a number of degrees approximately\nequal to the latitude minus the normal rollout lead.\n",
        "choiceone": "before the compass indication reaches south by a number of degrees approximately\nequal to the latitude over which the turn is made plus the pilot's normal lead.\n",
        "choicetwo": "after the compass indication passes south by a number of degrees approximately\nequal to the magnetic variation of the area over which the turn is made plus the\npilot's normal lead.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 140.) Which\nthe 1.9 NM pointis indicated?\n\nplacement from the localizer and glide slope at\n",
        "answer": "710 feet to the right of the localizer centerline and 140 feet above the glide slope.\n",
        "choiceone": "710 feet to the left of the localizer centerline and 140 feet below the glide slope.\n",
        "choicetwo": "430 feet to the right of the localizer centerline and 28 feet above the glide slope.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, a magnetic compass will normally indicate a turn toward\n\nthe north if\n",
        "answer": "an aircraft is accelerated while on an east or west heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "a left turn is entered from a west heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an aircraft is decelerated while on an east or west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the runway distance remaining markers.\n",
        "answer": "Signs with increments of 1,000 feet distance remaining.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red markers laterally placed across the runway at 3,000 feet from the end.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow marker laterally placed across the runway with signs on the side denoting\ndistance to end.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reported QNH ofa given station is the:\n",
        "answer": "Station's barometric pressure corrected to mean sea level pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "actual barometric pressure measured at the station;\n",
        "choicetwo": "actual barometric pressure measured at sea level;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "QNH is the sub-scale setting which will cause the altimeter to read:\n",
        "answer": "vertical displacement above mean sea level\n",
        "choiceone": "the altitude at which any given pressure exists in the standard atmosphere\n",
        "choicetwo": "vertical displacement above the airfield pressure datum\n",
        "choicethree": "pressure altitude\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The high Altitude Radio Altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicethree": "metric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ASI consists of a gas tight casing which has:\n",
        "answer": "pitot pressure fed into an open capsule and static pressure fed outside the capsule\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule and pitot pressure fed into a second\nopen capsule\n",
        "choicetwo": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule\n",
        "choicethree": "static pressure fed through a restrictive choke\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb, the static line becomes blocked, the ASI will:\n",
        "answer": "under-read\n",
        "choiceone": "read normally\n",
        "choicetwo": "over-read\n",
        "choicethree": "read zero\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot opening is blocked, whi\nvent)?\n\nstruments would be affected (separate static\n",
        "answer": "ASI only.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and VSI.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ASI and VSI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is maintal\nprobable cause is:\n\n1g FL 120 in cloud. The ASI reading falls to zero. The most\n",
        "answer": "ASI malfunction.\n",
        "choiceone": "Static vent blocked by ice.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pitot head and static vent blocked by ice.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (29).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formation of ice in a carburetor's throat is indicated by\n",
        "answer": "a drop in RPM, followed by rough engine operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "rough engine operation, followed by a decrease in oil pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a rapid increase in RPM, followed by rough engine operation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fuel vents on many powered parachutes and weight shift control aircraft are located\n",
        "answer": "in the fuel cap.\n",
        "choiceone": "adjacent to the crankcase breather.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in the fuel tank pressure relief valve.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What effect does the leading edge slot in the wing have on performance?\n",
        "answer": "Changes the stalling angle of attack to a higher angle.\n",
        "choiceone": "Decreases profile drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decelerates the upper surface boundary layer air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Ram Air Turbine (RAT) provides emergency hydraulic power for :\n",
        "answer": "flight controls in the event of loss of engine driven hydraulic power.\n",
        "choiceone": "undercarriage selection and automatic brake system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flap extension only.\n",
        "choicethree": "nose wheel steering after the aeroplane has landed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hydraulic fluids used in systems of large modern airliners are:\n",
        "answer": "Phosphate ester base fluids.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mineral base fluids.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Water base fluids.\n",
        "choicethree": "Vegetable base fluids.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the cabin altitude rises (aircraft in level flight), the differential pressure:\n",
        "answer": "decreases\n",
        "choiceone": "increases\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains constant\n",
        "choicethree": "may exceed the maximum permitted differential unless immediate preventative\naction is taken.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum quantity of fuel that can be dumped with the jettisoning system is:\n",
        "answer": "All up to a defined reserve quantity.\n",
        "choiceone": "All fuel until the maximum landing weight is reached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 tons.\n",
        "choicethree": "All fuel.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fuel pumps submerged in the fuel tanks of a large aeroplane are:\n",
        "answer": "centrifugal low pressure type pumps.\n",
        "choiceone": "low pressure variable swash plate pumps.\n",
        "choicetwo": "centrifugal high pressure pumps.\n",
        "choicethree": "high pressure swash plate pumps.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The torque of an aeroplane engine can be measured at the:\n",
        "answer": "gear box which is located between the engine and the propeller.\n",
        "choiceone": "accessory gear box.\n",
        "choicetwo": "camshaft.\n",
        "choicethree": "propeller blades.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On modern carburettors, the variations of mixture ratios are obtained by the adjustment\nof :\n",
        "answer": "fuel flow.\n",
        "choiceone": "fuel flow and air flow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fuel flow, air flow and temperature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When applying carburettor heating :\n",
        "answer": "the mixture becomes richer.\n",
        "choiceone": "the mixture becomes leaner.\n",
        "choicetwo": "no change occurs in the mixture ratio.\n",
        "choicethree": "a decrease in RPM results from the lean mixture.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary reason for a limitation being imposed on the temperature of gas flow is to :\n",
        "answer": "ensure that the maximum acceptable temperature at the turbine blades is not\nexceeded.\n",
        "choiceone": "ensure that the maximum acceptable temperature within the combustion chamber is\nnot exceeded.\n",
        "choicetwo": "prevent damage to the jet pipe from overheating.\n",
        "choicethree": "prevent overheating and subsequent creep of the nozzle\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airplane whose maximum approved passenger seating configuration is 401 to 500\n\nseats must be equipped with at least:\n",
        "answer": "6 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment.\n",
        "choicethree": "8 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the cockpit of a transport airplane, at least one\nmanual fire-extinguisher must be conveniently located\ncontaining :\n\n",
        "answer": "halon.\n",
        "choiceone": "powder.\n",
        "choicetwo": "water.\n",
        "choicethree": "special fluids.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airplane whose maximum approved passenger seating configuration is 201 to 300\nseats must be equipped with at least:\n",
        "answer": "4 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment.\n",
        "choicethree": "6 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Continuous loop fire detector systems operate on the principle that an increase in\ntemperature produces:\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in resistance\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase in resistance\n",
        "choicetwo": "a decrease in the reference current\n",
        "choicethree": "a decrease in pressure\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A diluter demand oxygen regulator :\n",
        "answer": "delivers oxygen flow when inhaling.\n",
        "choiceone": "mixes air and oxygen in a passenger oxygen mask.\n",
        "choicetwo": "delivers oxygen flow only above FL 100.\n",
        "choicethree": "is only recommended for use with smoke in the cockpit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The equipment of an oxygen supply installation must be kept absolutely free of oil or\ngrease traces as:\n",
        "answer": "these substances catch fire spontaneously in the presence of oxygen under\npressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "these substances mixed with oxygen could catch fire in the presence of a spark.\n",
        "choicetwo": "these substances could plug the oxygen masks filters.\n",
        "choicethree": "the oxygen system would be contaminated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the oxygen system of a large aeroplane is used, :\n",
        "answer": "with the setting on \"NORMAL\", the cockpit crew is supplied with a mixture of oxygen\nand cabin air.\n",
        "choiceone": "the same source of supply is used by the cockpit crew and passengers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same source of supply is used by the cockpit crew and cabin crew.\n",
        "choicethree": "with the setting on \"NORMAL\", the passengers are supplied with a mixture of oxygen\nand cabin air.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 87.) At STRUT intersection headed eastbound, ATC instructs you to\nhold west on the 10 DME fix west of LCH on V306, standard turns, what entry procedure\nis recommended?\n",
        "answer": "Direct.\n",
        "choiceone": "Teardrop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Parallel.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the runway distance remaining markers.\n",
        "answer": "Signs with increments of 1,000 feet distance remaining.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red markers laterally placed across the runway at 3,000 feet from the end.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow marker laterally placed across the runway with signs on the side denoting\ndistance to end.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the maximum tolerance for the VOI ication when the CDI is centered and\nthe aircraft is directly over the airborne checkpoint?\n",
        "answer": "Plus or minus 6 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus 6degrees or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Plus or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the indications of the pulsating VASI?\n",
        "answer": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - steady white, slightly below glide slope steady\nred, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choiceone": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - green, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High - pulsing white, on course and on glidepath - steady white, off course but on\nglidepath - pulsing white and red; low - pulsing red.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How should you preflight check the altimeter prior to an IFR flight?\n",
        "answer": "Set the altimeter to the current altimeter setting. The indication should be within 75\nfeet of the actual elevation for acceptable accuracy.\n",
        "choiceone": "Set the altimeter to 29.92\" Hg. With current temperature and the altimeter indication,\ndetermine the true altitude to compare with the field elevation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Set the altimeter first with 29.92\" Hg and then the current altimeter setting. The\nchange in altitude should correspond to the change in setting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a manifold pressure gauge consistently registers atmospheric pressure, the caus:\nprobably:\n",
        "answer": "leak in pressure gauge line.\n",
        "choiceone": "an aneroid capsule which is not properly calibrated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a very high atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "a very low atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When compared with the volumetric fuel flowmeter, the mass fuel flowmeter takes into\naccount the fuel:\n",
        "answer": "density.\n",
        "choiceone": "permittivity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "turbulent flow in the line.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mean sea level calibration constants used for pressure altimeters are:\n",
        "answer": "pressure 1013.2 mb, temperature +15\u00b0C, density 1225 gm/m3\n",
        "choiceone": "pressure 1013.2 mb, temperature +15\u00b0C, density 1225 gmim2\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure 30\" Hg, temperature +15\u00b0C, density 1225 gm/m3.\n",
        "choicethree": "pressure 1013.2 hg, temperature +15\u00b0C, density 1225 gm/m3\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QFE at an aerodrome (elevation) 1790 feet is 962 hPa and the QNH 1022 hPa. If the\ntransition level is FLO40 the physical level of the transition level above the aerodrome is\napproximately:\n",
        "answer": "2464 feet\n",
        "choiceone": "2150 feet\n",
        "choicetwo": "2280 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Transition altitude is obtained from:\n",
        "answer": "Jeppesen or Aerad flight guides.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC or VOR ATIS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1500 feet above airfield elevation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "QNH is the sub-scale setting which will cause the altimeter to read:\n",
        "answer": "vertical displacement above mean sea level\n",
        "choiceone": "the altitude at which any given pressure exists in the standard atmosphere\n",
        "choicetwo": "vertical displacement above the airfield pressure datum\n",
        "choicethree": "pressure altitude\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Transition level is obtained from:\n",
        "answer": "ATC or VOR ATIS.\n",
        "choiceone": "Jeppesen or Aerad flight guides.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1500 feet above airfield elevation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot opening is blocked, whi\nvent)?\n\nstruments would be affected (separate static\n",
        "answer": "ASI only.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and VSI.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ASI and VSI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\\g at a constant Mach number in the standard atmosphere, the\n\n",
        "answer": "increase\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease\n",
        "choicetwo": "remain constant\n",
        "choicethree": "remain constant unless the aircraft flies through an inversion\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One characteristic that a properly functioning gyro depends upon for operation is the:\n",
        "answer": "Resistance to deflection of the gyro rotor.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ability to resist precession at 90 degrees to an applied force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position of the gyro axis relative to the Earth's axis.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When, in flight, the needle of a needle-and-ball indicator is on the right and the ball on\nthe left, the aeroplane is:\n",
        "answer": "turning right with too much right rudder pedal.\n",
        "choiceone": "turning right with not enough right rudder pedal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "turning left with too much right rudder pedal.\n",
        "choicethree": "turning left with not enough right rudder pedal.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The radio altimeter is required to indicate zero height AGL as the main wheels touch\ndown on the runway. For this reason, it is necessary to:\n",
        "answer": "compensate for residual height and cable length.\n",
        "choiceone": "adjust the gross height according to the aeroplane instantaneous pitch.\n",
        "choicetwo": "change the display scale in short final, in order to have a precise readout.\n",
        "choicethree": "have a specific radio altimeter dedicated to automatic landing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Detonation in an aircraft engine is most likely to occur whenever the\n",
        "answer": "engine is operated under conditions which cause the fuel mixture to burn\ninstantaneously.\n",
        "choiceone": "fuel/air ratio is such that the mixture burns extremely slow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fuel being used is of a higher grade than recommended by the engine manufacturer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should help prevent aircraft induced oscillation on a gyroplane?-\n",
        "answer": "Adding a horizontal stabilizer.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increasing cyclic control sensitivity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Lowering the center of gravity below the thrust line.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Air cooled engines dissipate heat\n",
        "answer": "through cooling fins on the cylinder and head.\n",
        "choiceone": "by air flowing through the radiator fins.\n",
        "choicetwo": "through the cylinder head temperature probe.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to improve engine efficiency, two-cycle engine exhaust systems are tuned to\n",
        "answer": "stop the fuel mixture from exiting the cylinder before combustion.\n",
        "choiceone": "close the exhaust valve to stop the fuel mixture from exiting the cylinder.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use a reed valve to stop the fuel mixture from exiting the cylinder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formation of ice in a carburetor's throat is indicated by\n",
        "answer": "a drop in RPM, followed by rough engine operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "rough engine operation, followed by a decrease in oil pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a rapid increase in RPM, followed by rough engine operation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A high-frequency vibration that suddenly occurs during flight could be an indication of a\ndefective\n",
        "answer": "transmission.\n",
        "choiceone": "ignition system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "freewheeling unit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One advantage of fuel injection systems over carburetor systems is\n",
        "answer": "better fuel distribution to the cylinders.\n",
        "choiceone": "easier hot-engine starting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "less difficulty with hot weather vapor locks during ground operations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Concerning carburetor icing, which statement is true?\n",
        "answer": "Carburetor icing would most likely form when the air temperature is between -\n7degrees C and 21 degrees C and visible moisture or high humidity is present.\n",
        "choiceone": "The first indication of carburetor icing, in an aircraft equipped with a fixed-pitch\npropeller, is a decrease in manifold pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Carburetor icing will form in a carburetor whenever the ambient temperature is\nbelow freezing with a reduced or closed throttle setting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An artificial feel unit is necessary in the pitch channel when:\n",
        "answer": "the elevators are actuated by irreversible servo-control units.\n",
        "choiceone": "the elevators are actuated by reversible servo-control units.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elevators are fitted with servo-tabs or trim tabs.\n",
        "choicethree": "there is a trimmable stabilizer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the relationship of the rate of turn with the radius of turn with a constant angle of\nbank but increasing airspeed?\n",
        "answer": "Rate will decrease and radius will increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rate will increase and radius will decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rate and radius will increase.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can turbulent air cause an increase in stalling speed of an airfoil?\n",
        "answer": "An abrupt change in relative wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "A decrease in angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sudden decrease in load factor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a characteristic of longitudinal instability?\n",
        "answer": "Pitch oscillations becoming progressively greater.\n",
        "choiceone": "Bank oscillations becoming progressively greater.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft constantly tries to pitch down.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aircraft hydraulic system is designed to produce:\n",
        "answer": "high pressure and large flow.\n",
        "choiceone": "high pressure and small flow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "small pressure and large flow.\n",
        "choicethree": "small pressure and small flow.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The secondary Surveillance Radar (SSR) uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "centimetric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicethree": "myriametric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pressure in the cabin tends to become lower than the outside ambient air pressure\nthe:\n",
        "answer": "negative pressure relief valve will open.\n",
        "choiceone": "outflow valve open completely.\n",
        "choicetwo": "air cycle machine will stop.\n",
        "choicethree": "negative pressure relief valve will close\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main purpose of the mixture control is to:\n",
        "answer": "adjust the fuel flow to obtain the proper fuel/air ratio\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease the air supplied to the engine\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase the oxygen supplied to the engine\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease oxygen supplied to the engine\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A feeder fault on a direct current circuit results from a flux unbalance between the:\n",
        "answer": "voltage coil and the series winding turn.\n",
        "choiceone": "shunt exciter and the series winding turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "voltage coil and the series winding.\n",
        "choicethree": "generator and the series winding turn.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A unit that converts electrical DC into AC is:\n",
        "answer": "an inverter.\n",
        "choiceone": "a thermistor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an AC generator.\n",
        "choicethree": "a transformer rectifier unit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An impulse turbine is a turbine in which the expansion takes place:\n",
        "answer": "fully in the stator.\n",
        "choiceone": "in order to produce a degree of jet propulsion < 1/2.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fully in the rotor.\n",
        "choicethree": "in the stator and in the rotor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "nificance of the blue radial line on the airspeed\nmultiengine airplane and when is it to be used? It indicates the\n\n",
        "answer": "speed which will provide the maximum altitude gain in a given time when one engine\nis inoperative and should be used for climb and final approach during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "choiceone": "minimum speed at which the airplane is controllable when the critical engine is\nsuddenly made inoperative and should be used at all altitudes when an engine is\ninoperative.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed which will provide the greatest height for a given distance of forward travel\nwhen one engine is inoperative and should be used for all climbs during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A possible result of using the emergency alternate source of static pressure inside the\ncabin of an unpressurized airplane is the\n",
        "answer": "altimeter may indicate an altitude higher than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "airspeed indicator may indicate less than normal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter may indicate an altitude lower than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an altimeter is changed from 30.11\" Hg to 29.96\" Hg,\nindicated altitude change and by what value?\n\nwhich direction will the\n\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter will indicate 150 feet lower.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altimeter will indicate 15 feet lower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altimeter will indicate 150 feet higher.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When making an airborne VOR check, what is the maximum allowable tolerance\nbetween the two indicators of a dual VOR system (units independent of each other\nexcept the antenna)?\n\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees between the two indicated bearings of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus or minus 4 degrees when set to identical radials of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 degrees between the two indicated radials of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify taxi leadoff lights associated with the centerline lighting system.\n",
        "answer": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to a point\non the exit.\n",
        "choiceone": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\ncenterline of the taxiway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\nedge of the taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deviation error of the magnetic compass is caused by\n",
        "answer": "certain metals and electrical systems within the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "northerly turning error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the difference in location of true north and magnetic north.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot head is blocked, what airspeed indication can he expected?\n",
        "answer": "No change of IAS in level flight, even with large power changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "A decrease of IAS during a climb.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Constant IAS during a descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the indications of the pulsating VASI?\n",
        "answer": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - steady white, slightly below glide slope steady\nred, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choiceone": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - green, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High - pulsing white, on course and on glidepath - steady white, off course but on\nglidepath - pulsing white and red; low - pulsing red.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, if an aircrat\ncompass will normally indicate\n\naccelerated or decelerated, the magnetic\n",
        "answer": "correctly when on a north or south heading while either accelerating or decelerating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a turn momentarily, with changes in airspeed on any heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a turn toward the south while accelerating on a west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 141.) Which displacement from the localizer centerline and\nglide slope at the 1,300-foot point from the runway is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "21 feet above the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "21 feet below the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the right of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "28 feet above the glide slope and approximately 250 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to starting the engine, the manifold pressure gauge usually\napproximately 29\" Hg. This is because the\n",
        "answer": "pressure within the manifold is the same as atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "pointer on the gauge is stuck at the full-power indication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "throttle is closed, trapping high air pressure in the manifold.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify runway remaining lighting on centerline lighting systems.\n",
        "answer": "Alternate red and white lights from 3,000 feet to 1,000 feet, then red lights to the end.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber lights from 3,000 feet to 1,000 feet, then alternate red and white lights to the\nend.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate red and white lights from 3,000 feet to the end of the runway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How will the airspeed icator react if the ram ai\nice, but the drain hole and static port are not?\n\nput to the pitot head is blocked by\n",
        "answer": "Indication will drop to zero.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indication will rise to the top of the scale.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indication will remain constant but will increase in a climb.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VSI may suffer from error due to:\n",
        "answer": "time lag, instrument calibration, blockage\n",
        "choiceone": "compressibility, time lag, blockage\n",
        "choicetwo": "density, aircraft manoeuvre, position of the static vent\n",
        "choicethree": "pitot blockage, static blockage, aircraft manoeuvre\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot Head and Static Vent were blocked by ice, which instruments would be\naffected?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter, VSI and ASI would give inaccurate readings.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and Slip indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ASI would under read.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The high Altitude Radio Altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicethree": "metric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "VFE is the maximum speed:\n",
        "answer": "with the flaps extended.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the flaps extended in the landing configuration.\n",
        "choicetwo": "with the flaps extended in the take-off configuration.\n",
        "choicethree": "at which the flaps can be operated when flying in turbulences.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb, the static line becomes blocked, the ASI will:\n",
        "answer": "under-read\n",
        "choiceone": "read normally\n",
        "choicetwo": "over-read\n",
        "choicethree": "read zero\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot opening is blocked, whi\nvent)?\n\nstruments would be affected (separate static\n",
        "answer": "ASI only.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and VSI.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ASI and VSI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The low temperature that causes carburetor ice in an engine equipped with a float-type\ncarburetor is normally the result of the\n",
        "answer": "vaporization of fuel and expansion of air in the carburetor.\n",
        "choiceone": "compression of air at the carburetor venturi.\n",
        "choicetwo": "freezing temperature of the air entering the carburetor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of a kill switch is to\n",
        "answer": "ground the lead wire to the ignition coil shutting down the powerplant.\n",
        "choiceone": "shut off the fuel to the carburetor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ground the battery eliminating current for the ignition system.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The uncontrolled firing of the fuel/air charge in advance of normal spark ignition is\nknown as\n",
        "answer": "pre-ignition.\n",
        "choiceone": "instantaneous combustion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "detonation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the ground wire between the magneto and the ignition switch becomes disconnected,\nthe most noticeable result will be that the engine\n",
        "answer": "cannot be shut down by turning the switch to the OFF position.\n",
        "choiceone": "will run very rough.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cannot be started with the switch in the ON position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of oxygen should be used to replenish an aircraft oxygen system?\n",
        "answer": "Aviation.\n",
        "choiceone": "Medical.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Industrial.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "constant angle of bank and altitude?\n",
        "answer": "The rate of turn will decrease resulting in no changes in load factor.\n",
        "choiceone": "The rate of turn will decrease resulting in a decreased load factor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The rate of turn will increase resulting in an increased load factor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If no corrective action is taken by the pilot as angle of ban!\nvertical component of lift and sink rate affected?\n\ncreased, how is the\n",
        "answer": "Lift decreases and the sink rate increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lift increases and the sink rate increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Lift decreases and the sink rate decreases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How should a balloon fuel system be checked for leaks prior to flight?\n",
        "answer": "Look, listen, and smell.\n",
        "choiceone": "Check for unusual discoloration on burner coils.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cover all fittings and hoses with soapy water and look for small bubbles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "By changing the angle of attack of a wing, the pilot can control the airplane's\n",
        "answer": "lift, airspeed, and drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "lift, gross weight, and drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lift and airspeed, but not drag.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What can be the consequence during a descent with a fully open throttle if the waste\ngate is seized ?\n",
        "answer": "The manifold air pressure (MAP) value may exceed the maximum allowed value.\n",
        "choiceone": "The turbine blades will separate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The power of the motor will decrease.\n",
        "choicethree": "The turbine shaft will break.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pressurization of tanks is maintained by the fuel:\n",
        "answer": "vent system.\n",
        "choiceone": "tank drains.\n",
        "choicetwo": "top off unit.\n",
        "choicethree": "dump system.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main purpose of the mixture control is to:\n",
        "answer": "adjust the fuel flow to obtain the proper fuel/air ratio\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease the air supplied to the engine\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase the oxygen supplied to the engine\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease oxygen supplied to the engine\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On modern transport aircraft, cockpit windows are protected against icing by :\n",
        "answer": "Electric heating.\n",
        "choiceone": "Vinyl coating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Anti-icing fluid.\n",
        "choicethree": "Rain repellent system.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a current is passed through a conductor,\n",
        "answer": "a force will be exerted on the conductor.\n",
        "choiceone": "the current will increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there will be no effect unless the conductor is moved.\n",
        "choicethree": "the intensity of the magnetic field will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The function of the Generator Breaker is to close when the voltage of the :\n",
        "answer": "generator is greater than battery voltage\n",
        "choiceone": "alternator is greater than the battery voltage and to open\n",
        "choicetwo": "battery is greater than the alternator voltage and to open\n",
        "choicethree": "battery is greater than the generator voltage and to open\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A unit that converts electrical DC into AC is:\n",
        "answer": "an inverter.\n",
        "choiceone": "a thermistor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an AC generator.\n",
        "choicethree": "a transformer rectifier unit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When changing power on engines equipped with constant-speed propeller, engine\noverload is avoided by accidental depressurization.\n",
        "answer": "increasing the RPM before increasing the manifold pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "adjusting Fuel Flow before the manifold pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "reducing the RPM before reducing the manifold pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "increasing the manifold pressure before increasing the RPM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The part of a piston engine that transforms reciprocating movement into rotary motion\nis termed as the :\n",
        "answer": "crankshaft\n",
        "choiceone": "reduction gear\n",
        "choicetwo": "piston\n",
        "choicethree": "camshaft\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The useful work area in an ideal Otto engine indicator diagram is enclosed by the\nfollowing gas state change lines\n",
        "answer": "2 adiabatic and 2 isochoric lines.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 adiabatic, 1 isochoric and 1 isobaric lines.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 adiabatic and 1 isothermic lines.\n",
        "choicethree": "2 adiabatic and 2 isobaric lines.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When making an airborne VOR check, what is the maximum allowable tolerance\nbetween the two indicators of a dual VOR system (units independent of each other\nexcept the antenna)?\n\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees between the two indicated bearings of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus or minus 4 degrees when set to identical radials of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 degrees between the two indicated radials of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the indications of the pulsating VASI?\n",
        "answer": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - steady white, slightly below glide slope steady\nred, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choiceone": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - green, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High - pulsing white, on course and on glidepath - steady white, off course but on\nglidepath - pulsing white and red; low - pulsing red.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the runway distance remaining markers.\n",
        "answer": "Signs with increments of 1,000 feet distance remaining.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red markers laterally placed across the runway at 3,000 feet from the end.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow marker laterally placed across the runway with signs on the side denoting\ndistance to end.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deviation error of the magnetic compass is caused by\n",
        "answer": "certain metals and electrical systems within the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "northerly turning error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the difference in location of true north and magnetic north.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which procedure is recommended to prevent or overcome spatial disorientation?\n",
        "answer": "Rely entirely on the indications of the flight instruments.\n",
        "choiceone": "Avoid steep turns and rough control movements.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Reduce head and eye movements to the greatest extent possible.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which pul\nbe found?\n\nition can the VOR receiver ground checkpoint(s) for a particular\n",
        "answer": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "En Route Low Altitude Chart.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true about magnetic deviation of a compass?\n",
        "answer": "Deviation varies for different headings of the same aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Deviation is the same for all aircraft in the same locality.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deviation is different in a given aircraft in different localities.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 141.) Which displacement from the localizer centerline and\nglide slope at the 1,300-foot point from the runway is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "21 feet above the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "21 feet below the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the right of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "28 feet above the glide slope and approximately 250 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the advantage of a three-bar VASI?\n",
        "answer": "A normal glide angle is afforded both high and low cockpit aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Pilots have a choice of glide angles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The three-bar VASI is much more visible and can be used at a greater height.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to starting the engine, the manifold pressure gauge usually\napproximately 29\" Hg. This is because the\n",
        "answer": "pressure within the manifold is the same as atmospheric pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "pointer on the gauge is stuck at the full-power indication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "throttle is closed, trapping high air pressure in the manifold.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which may lead to a power push-over in a gyroplane?\n",
        "answer": "Rotor force is removed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decreasing power too quickly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the maximum tolerance for the VOI ication when the CDI is centered and\nthe aircraft is directly over the airborne checkpoint?\n",
        "answer": "Plus or minus 6 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus 6degrees or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Plus or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify taxi leadoff lights associated with the centerline lighting system.\n",
        "answer": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to a point\non the exit.\n",
        "choiceone": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\ncenterline of the taxiway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\nedge of the taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A possible result of using the emergency alternate source of static pressure inside the\ncabin of an unpressurized airplane is the\n",
        "answer": "altimeter may indicate an altitude higher than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "airspeed indicator may indicate less than normal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter may indicate an altitude lower than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot head is blocked, what airspeed indication can he expected?\n",
        "answer": "No change of IAS in level flight, even with large power changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "A decrease of IAS during a climb.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Constant IAS during a descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The high Altitude Radio Altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicethree": "metric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb, the static line becomes blocked, the ASI will:\n",
        "answer": "under-read\n",
        "choiceone": "read normally\n",
        "choicetwo": "over-read\n",
        "choicethree": "read zero\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ASI consists of a gas tight casing which has:\n",
        "answer": "pitot pressure fed into an open capsule and static pressure fed outside the capsule\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule and pitot pressure fed into a second\nopen capsule\n",
        "choicetwo": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule\n",
        "choicethree": "static pressure fed through a restrictive choke\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a stabilised climbing turn at a constant rate, the instruments which indicate the\n\ncorrect pitch and bank are the:\n",
        "answer": "attitude indicator and turn-and-slip indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "vertical-speed indicator and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (31).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With regard to an aircraft structure, \u2018fail safe\u2019 is one:\n",
        "answer": "in which the load is carried by other components if a part of the structure fails.\n",
        "choiceone": "that is easily manufactured.\n",
        "choicetwo": "used for small aircraft only.\n",
        "choicethree": "that is only used for a limited time.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fuselage of an aircraft consists, among others, of stringers whose purpose is to:\n",
        "answer": "assist the skin in absorbing the longitudinal traction-compression stresses.\n",
        "choiceone": "withstand the shear stresses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "provide sound and thermal isolation.\n",
        "choicethree": "integrate the strains due to pressurization to which the skin is subjected and convert\nthem into a tensile stress.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ina hydraulic system, the reservoir is pressurized in order to:\n",
        "answer": "prevent pump cavitation\n",
        "choiceone": "seal the system\n",
        "choicetwo": "keep the hydraulic fluid at optimum temperature\n",
        "choicethree": "reduce fluid combustibility\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The function of a hydraulic selector valve is to:\n",
        "answer": "direct system pressure to either side of the piston of an actuator.\n",
        "choiceone": "select the system to which the hydraulic pump should supply pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "automatically activate the hydraulic system.\n",
        "choicethree": "discharge some hydraulic fluid if the system pressure is too high.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the pneumatic supply system of a modern transport aircraft, the air pressure is\nregulated. This pressure regulation occurs just before the manifold by the :\n",
        "answer": "low pressure bleed air valve\n",
        "choiceone": "fan bleed air valve\n",
        "choicetwo": "intermediate pressure check-valve\n",
        "choicethree": "high pressure bleed air valve\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On most modern airliners the cabin pressure is controlled by regulating the:\n",
        "answer": "Airflow leaving the cabin.\n",
        "choiceone": "Bleed air valve.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airflow entering the cabin.\n",
        "choicethree": "RPM of the engine.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cabin rate of descent is:\n",
        "answer": "a cabin pressure increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "a cabin pressure decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not possible at constant airplane altitudes.\n",
        "choicethree": "always the same as the airplane's rate of descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming cabin differential pressure has attained the required value in normal flight\nconditions, if flight altitude is maintained:\n",
        "answer": "a constant mass air flow is permitted through the cabin.\n",
        "choiceone": "the pressurisation system ceases to function until leakage reduces the pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the outflow valves will move to the fully closed position.\n",
        "choicethree": "the outflow valves will move to the fully open position.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On most transpor aircraft, the low pressure pumps of the fuel system are:\n",
        "answer": "Centrifugal pumps.\n",
        "choiceone": "Piston pumps.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Diaphragm pumps.\n",
        "choicethree": "Gear type pumps.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cross-feed fuel system enables:\n",
        "answer": "the supply of any jet engine from any fuel tank.\n",
        "choiceone": "the supply of the jet engines mounted on a wing from any fuel tank within that wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the supply of the outboard jet engines from any outboard\n",
        "choicethree": "only the transfer of fuel from the centre tank to the wing tanks.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a transport type aircraft the fuel tank system is vented through:\n",
        "answer": "Ram air scoops on the underside of the wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "A pressure regulator in the wing tip.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Bleed air from the engines.\n",
        "choicethree": "The return lines of the fuel pumps.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Constant Speed Drive aims at ensuring\n",
        "answer": "that the electric generator produces a constant frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "equal AC voltage from all generators.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that the starter-motor maintains a constant RPM not\n",
        "choicethree": "that the CSD remains at a constant RPM not withstanding the generator RPM\nwithstanding the acceleration of the engine.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a conductor cuts the flux of a magnetic field :\n",
        "answer": "an electromotive force (EMF) is induced in the conductor.\n",
        "choiceone": "there will be no effect on the conductor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the field will collapse.\n",
        "choicethree": "current will flow in accordance with Flemings left hand rule.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order that DC generators will act\nis necessary to ensure that :\n\nve equal load sharing when operating in parallel, it\n",
        "answer": "their voltages are almost equal.\n",
        "choiceone": "the synchronising bus-bar is disconnected from the busbar system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "equal loads are connected to each generator busbar before paralleling.\n",
        "choicethree": "adequate voltage differences exists.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On modern carburettors, the variations of mixture ratios are obtained by the adjustment\nof :\n",
        "answer": "fuel flow.\n",
        "choiceone": "fuel flow and air flow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fuel flow, air flow and temperature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The power of a piston engine which will be measured by using a friction brake is :\n",
        "answer": "Brake horse power.\n",
        "choiceone": "Heat loss power.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicated horse power.\n",
        "choicethree": "Friction horse power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the ground wire between the magnetos and the ig\ndisconnected the most noticeable result will be that:\n",
        "answer": "the engine cannot be shut down by turning the ignition switch to the \"OFF\" position\n",
        "choiceone": "a still operating engine will run down\n",
        "choicetwo": "the engine cannot be started with the ignition switch in the \"ON\" position\n",
        "choicethree": "the power developed by the engine will be strongly reduced\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does V(NE) speed vary with altitude?\n",
        "answer": "Varies inversely with altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Varies directly with altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Remains the same at all altitudes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The bypass ratio:\n|. is the ratio of bypass air mass flow to HP compressor mass flow.\nIl. can be determined from the inlet air mass flow and the HP compressor mass flow.\n",
        "answer": "lis correct, Il is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "lis correct, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lis incorrect, Il is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "lis incorrect, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the flight deck oxygen supply system. The\npurpose of the oxygen regulator (as a function of\ndemand and altitude) is to:\n\n1. decrease oxygen pressure from 1800 PSI (in the\nbottles) down to about 50-75 PSI (low pressure system)\n2. supply pure oxygen\n\n3. supply diluted oxygen\n\n4. supply oxygen at normal pressure\n\n5. supply oxygen at emergency/positive pressure\n\n6. trigger the continuous cabin altitude warning at 10000\nft cabin altitude\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements\n\n",
        "answer": "2,3,4,5\n",
        "choiceone": "3,4, 5,6\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,2,3,4\n",
        "choicethree": "1,3,4,6\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "nificance of the blue radial line on the airspeed\nmultiengine airplane and when is it to be used? It indicates the\n\n",
        "answer": "speed which will provide the maximum altitude gain in a given time when one engine\nis inoperative and should be used for climb and final approach during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "choiceone": "minimum speed at which the airplane is controllable when the critical engine is\nsuddenly made inoperative and should be used at all altitudes when an engine is\ninoperative.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed which will provide the greatest height for a given distance of forward travel\nwhen one engine is inoperative and should be used for all climbs during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deviation error of the magnetic compass is caused by\n",
        "answer": "certain metals and electrical systems within the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "northerly turning error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the difference in location of true north and magnetic north.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a lighted heliport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choiceone": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 85.) Of the following, which is the minimum acceptable rate of climb (feet\nper minute) to 9,000 feet required for the WASH2 WAGGE departure at a GS of 150\nknots?\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet per minute.\n",
        "choiceone": "750 feet per minute.\n",
        "choicetwo": "825 feet per minute.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which instrument would be affected by excessively low pressure in the\nvacuum system?\n",
        "answer": "Heading indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airspeed indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pressure altimeter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a pitot tube is clogged, which instrument would be affected?\n",
        "answer": "Airspeed indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altimeter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vertical speed indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify taxi leadoff lights associated with the centerline lighting system.\n",
        "answer": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to a point\non the exit.\n",
        "choiceone": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\ncenterline of the taxiway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\nedge of the taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true about magnetic deviation of a compass?\n",
        "answer": "Deviation varies for different headings of the same aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Deviation is the same for all aircraft in the same locality.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deviation is different in a given aircraft in different localities.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should be the indication on the magnetic compass as you roll into a standard rate\nturn to the right from a south heading in the Northern Hemisphere?\n",
        "answer": "The compass will indicate a turn to the right, but at a faster rate than is actually\noccurring.\n",
        "choiceone": "The compass will initially indicate a turn to the left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The compass will remain on south for a short time, then gradually catch up to the\nmagnetic heading of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pressure Altitude at an airfield\nscale is set to:\n\nindicated by an altimeter when the barometric sub-\n",
        "answer": "1013.25 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "QNH\n",
        "choicetwo": "QFE\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "craft is flying from a cold air mass into a warm air mass. The TAS and true altitude\n\n",
        "answer": "Both increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "TAS increases, true altitude decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAS decreases, true altitude increases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Transition altitude is obtained from:\n",
        "answer": "Jeppesen or Aerad flight guides.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC or VOR ATIS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1500 feet above airfield elevation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "QNH is the sub-scale setting which will cause the altimeter to read:\n",
        "answer": "vertical displacement above mean sea level\n",
        "choiceone": "the altitude at which any given pressure exists in the standard atmosphere\n",
        "choicetwo": "vertical displacement above the airfield pressure datum\n",
        "choicethree": "pressure altitude\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When ambient temperature is warmer than standard at a particular altitude, the altimeter\nwill indicate:\n",
        "answer": "lower than true altitude;\n",
        "choiceone": "higher than true altitude;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same as true altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the static vent became blocked during a descent, the altimeter would:\n",
        "answer": "over-read the correct altitude\n",
        "choiceone": "act normally\n",
        "choicetwo": "under-read the correct altitude\n",
        "choicethree": "read zero altitude\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a compass swing the following reading were noted: MAGNETIC HEADING(0-89-\n178-269), COMPASS HEADING(358-92-182-268). After correction for coefficients B and C,\nthe compass reading on the westerly heading was:\n",
        "answer": "270\n",
        "choiceone": "266\n",
        "choicetwo": "271\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When, in flight, the needle of a needle-and-ball indicator is on the left and the ball on the\nright, the aeroplane is:\n",
        "answer": "turning left with too much left rudder pedal.\n",
        "choiceone": "turning left with not enough left rudder pedal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "turning right with too much left rudder pedal.\n",
        "choicethree": "turning right with not enough left rudder pedal.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When, in flight, the needle of a needle-and-ball indicator is on the right and the ball on\nthe left, the aeroplane is:\n",
        "answer": "turning right with too much right rudder pedal.\n",
        "choiceone": "turning right with not enough right rudder pedal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "turning left with too much right rudder pedal.\n",
        "choicethree": "turning left with not enough right rudder pedal.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A stall warning system is based on measuring the:\n",
        "answer": "angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "TAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "attitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (32).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should help prevent aircraft induced oscillation on a gyroplane?-\n",
        "answer": "Adding a horizontal stabilizer.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increasing cyclic control sensitivity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Lowering the center of gravity below the thrust line.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Detonation in an aircraft engine is most likely to occur whenever the\n",
        "answer": "engine is operated under conditions which cause the fuel mixture to burn\ninstantaneously.\n",
        "choiceone": "fuel/air ratio is such that the mixture burns extremely slow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fuel being used is of a higher grade than recommended by the engine manufacturer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of a kill switch is to\n",
        "answer": "ground the lead wire to the ignition coil shutting down the powerplant.\n",
        "choiceone": "shut off the fuel to the carburetor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ground the battery eliminating current for the ignition system.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A high-frequency vibration that suddenly occurs during flight could be an indication of a\ndefective\n",
        "answer": "transmission.\n",
        "choiceone": "ignition system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "freewheeling unit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of carburetor ice in an aircraft equipped with a fixed-pitch propeller can be\nverified by applying carburetor heat and noting\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in RPM and then a gradual increase in RPM.\n",
        "choiceone": "a decrease in RPM and then a constant RPM indication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase in RPM and then a gradual decrease in RPM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of oxygen system is most commonly found in general aviation aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "Continuous flow.\n",
        "choiceone": "Demand.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pressure demand.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Running a fuel tank dry before switching tanks is not a good practice because\n",
        "answer": "the engine-driven fuel pump or electric fuel boost pump draw air into the fuel system\nand cause vapor lock.\n",
        "choiceone": "any foreign matter in the tank will be pumped into the fuel system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the engine-driven fuel pump is lubricated by fuel and operating on a dry tank may\ncause pump failure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fuel enters a two-cycle engine through an\n",
        "answer": "intake port and intake valve.\n",
        "choiceone": "intake port and reed valve.\n",
        "choicetwo": "intake valve and reed valve.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aeroplane, spoilers are :\n",
        "answer": "upper wing surface devices, their deflection is symmetrical or asymmetrical.\n",
        "choiceone": "lower wing surface devices, their deflection is always asymmetrical.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lower wing surface devices, their deflection is symmetrical or asymmetrical.\n",
        "choicethree": "upper wing surface devices, their deflection is always asymmetrical.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can the pilot increase the rate of turn and decrease the radius at the same time?\n",
        "answer": "Steepen the bank and decrease airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Steepen the bank and increase airspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Shallow the bank and increase airspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "constant angle of bank and altitude?\n",
        "answer": "The rate of turn will decrease resulting in no changes in load factor.\n",
        "choiceone": "The rate of turn will decrease resulting in a decreased load factor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The rate of turn will increase resulting in an increased load factor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The hydraulic oil, entering the hydraulic pump, is slightly pressurised to :\n",
        "answer": "prevent cavitation in the pump\n",
        "choiceone": "prevent overheating of the pump.\n",
        "choicetwo": "prevent vapour locking.\n",
        "choicethree": "ensure sufficient pump output\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The type of brake unit found on most transport aeroplanes is a:\n",
        "answer": "Multiple disk brake.\n",
        "choiceone": "Drum type brake.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Single disk brake.\n",
        "choicethree": "Belt brake.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A tubeless tyre is a tyre: 1. which requires solid or branched wheels 2. whose valve can\nbe sheared in sudden accelerations 3. whose mounting rim must be flawless 4. which\nrequires no rim protection between rim flange and tire removing device 5. which does\nnot burst in the event of a tire puncture 6. which eliminates internal friction between the\ntube and the tire The combination regrouping all the correct statements is :\n",
        "answer": "1,5, 6.\n",
        "choiceone": "3, 4,5.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1, 2,5.\n",
        "choicethree": "2, 3, 6.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the preheating coil used in hot air balloons is to\n",
        "answer": "vaporize the fuel for more efficient burner operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "prevent ice from forming in the fuel lines.\n",
        "choicetwo": "warm the fuel tanks for more efficient fuel flow.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main purpose of the mixture control is to:\n",
        "answer": "adjust the fuel flow to obtain the proper fuel/air ratio\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease the air supplied to the engine\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase the oxygen supplied to the engine\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease oxygen supplied to the engine\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The function of the Generator Breaker is to close when the voltage of the :\n",
        "answer": "generator is greater than battery voltage\n",
        "choiceone": "alternator is greater than the battery voltage and to open\n",
        "choicetwo": "battery is greater than the alternator voltage and to open\n",
        "choicethree": "battery is greater than the generator voltage and to open\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The output of a generator is controlled by :\n",
        "answer": "varying the field strength.\n",
        "choiceone": "varying the length of wire in the armature windings.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the reverse current relay circuit breaker.\n",
        "choicethree": "varying the speed of the engine.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The control of free turbine engines on turboprops, is accomplished by: -a propeller\ncontrol lever used to select: 1- propeller RPM 2.-turbine temperature 3 - turbine RPM\n- a fuel control lever used to select: 4- propeller RPM 5 - torque 6 - turbine temperature\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is :\n",
        "answer": "1-5-6\n",
        "choiceone": "1-3-5\n",
        "choicetwo": "3-4-6\n",
        "choicethree": "2-4-5\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of a diluter demand regulator in an oxygen system is to :\n",
        "answer": "deliver oxygen flow when inhaling.\n",
        "choiceone": "deliver oxygen flow only above FL 100.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is only recommended with smoke in the cockpit.\n",
        "choicethree": "mix air and oxygen in a passenger oxygen mask.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot head is blocked, what airspeed indication can he expected?\n",
        "answer": "No change of IAS in level flight, even with large power changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "A decrease of IAS during a climb.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Constant IAS during a descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an altimeter is changed from 30.11\" Hg to 29.96\" Hg,\nindicated altitude change and by what value?\n\nwhich direction will the\n\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter will indicate 150 feet lower.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altimeter will indicate 15 feet lower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altimeter will indicate 150 feet higher.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 141.) Which displacement from the localizer centerline and\nglide slope at the 1,300-foot point from the runway is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "21 feet above the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "21 feet below the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the right of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "28 feet above the glide slope and approximately 250 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a military airport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choiceone": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choicetwo": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "nificance of the blue radial line on the airspeed\nmultiengine airplane and when is it to be used? It indicates the\n\n",
        "answer": "speed which will provide the maximum altitude gain in a given time when one engine\nis inoperative and should be used for climb and final approach during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "choiceone": "minimum speed at which the airplane is controllable when the critical engine is\nsuddenly made inoperative and should be used at all altitudes when an engine is\ninoperative.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed which will provide the greatest height for a given distance of forward travel\nwhen one engine is inoperative and should be used for all climbs during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the runway distance remaining markers.\n",
        "answer": "Signs with increments of 1,000 feet distance remaining.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red markers laterally placed across the runway at 3,000 feet from the end.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow marker laterally placed across the runway with signs on the side denoting\ndistance to end.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How will the airspeed icator react if the ram ai\nice, but the drain hole and static port are not?\n\nput to the pitot head is blocked by\n",
        "answer": "Indication will drop to zero.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indication will rise to the top of the scale.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indication will remain constant but will increase in a climb.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A possible result of using the emergency alternate source of static pressure inside the\ncabin of an unpressurized airplane is the\n",
        "answer": "altimeter may indicate an altitude higher than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "airspeed indicator may indicate less than normal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter may indicate an altitude lower than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, if an aircrat\ncompass will normally indicate\n\naccelerated or decelerated, the magnetic\n",
        "answer": "correctly when on a north or south heading while either accelerating or decelerating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a turn momentarily, with changes in airspeed on any heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a turn toward the south while accelerating on a west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the advantage of a three-bar VASI?\n",
        "answer": "A normal glide angle is afforded both high and low cockpit aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Pilots have a choice of glide angles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The three-bar VASI is much more visible and can be used at a greater height.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the static pressure tubes are broken inside a pressurized cabin during a high-altitude\nflight, the altimeter would probably indicate\n",
        "answer": "lower than actual flight altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "sea level.\n",
        "choicetwo": "higher than actual flight altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When making an airborne VOR check, what is the maximum allowable tolerance\nbetween the two indicators of a dual VOR system (units independent of each other\nexcept the antenna)?\n\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees between the two indicated bearings of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus or minus 4 degrees when set to identical radials of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 degrees between the two indicated radials of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VSI may suffer from error due to:\n",
        "answer": "time lag, instrument calibration, blockage\n",
        "choiceone": "compressibility, time lag, blockage\n",
        "choicetwo": "density, aircraft manoeuvre, position of the static vent\n",
        "choicethree": "pitot blockage, static blockage, aircraft manoeuvre\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reported QNH ofa given station is the:\n",
        "answer": "Station's barometric pressure corrected to mean sea level pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "actual barometric pressure measured at the station;\n",
        "choicetwo": "actual barometric pressure measured at sea level;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The high Altitude Radio Altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicethree": "metric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "QNH is the sub-scale setting which will cause the altimeter to read:\n",
        "answer": "vertical displacement above mean sea level\n",
        "choiceone": "the altitude at which any given pressure exists in the standard atmosphere\n",
        "choicetwo": "vertical displacement above the airfield pressure datum\n",
        "choicethree": "pressure altitude\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is maintal\nprobable cause is:\n\n1g FL 120 in cloud. The ASI reading falls to zero. The most\n",
        "answer": "ASI malfunction.\n",
        "choiceone": "Static vent blocked by ice.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pitot head and static vent blocked by ice.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "VFE is the maximum speed:\n",
        "answer": "with the flaps extended.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the flaps extended in the landing configuration.\n",
        "choicetwo": "with the flaps extended in the take-off configuration.\n",
        "choicethree": "at which the flaps can be operated when flying in turbulences.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rectified Airspeed is:\n",
        "answer": "IAS corrected for instrument and pressure error.\n",
        "choiceone": "IAS corrected for density error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IAS corrected for density and compressibility errors.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a stabilised climbing turn at a constant rate, the instruments which indicate the\n\ncorrect pitch and bank are the:\n",
        "answer": "attitude indicator and turn-and-slip indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "vertical-speed indicator and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter and turn-and-slip indicator;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true regarding fouling of the spark plugs of an aircraft engine?\n",
        "answer": "Spark plug fouling results from operating with an excessively rich mixture.\n",
        "choiceone": "Carbon fouling of the spark plugs is caused primarily by operating an engine at\nexcessively high cylinder head temperatures.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Excessive heat in the combustion chamber of a cylinder causes oil to form on the\ncenter electrode of a spark plug and this fouls the plug.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When refueling aircraft, which precaution would be adequate for eli\npotential hazard of static electricity?\n\n",
        "answer": "Connect a ground wire between the aircraft, fuel truck, fuel nozzle, and ground.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ensure that battery and ignition switches are off.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Connect a ground wire from the fuel truck to ground.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What energy source is used to drive the turbine of a turbocharged airplane?\n",
        "answer": "Engine exhaust gases.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ignition system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Engine compressor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first indication of carburetor ice in an aircraft with a fixed-pitch propeller is\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in RPM.\n",
        "choiceone": "a decrease in manifold pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase in manifold pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Concerning the advantages of an\nstatement.\n\nraft generator or alternator, select the true\n",
        "answer": "An alternator provides more electrical power at lower engine RPM than a generator.\n",
        "choiceone": "A generator always provides more electrical current than an alternator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A generator charges the battery during low engine RPM; therefore, the battery has\nless chance to become fully discharged, as often occurs with an alternator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the engine oil temperature and cylinder head temperature gauges have exceeded their\nnormal operating range, you may have been\n",
        "answer": "operating with too much power and with the mixture set too lean.\n",
        "choiceone": "operating with the mixture set too rich.\n",
        "choicetwo": "using fuel that has a higher-than-specified fuel rating.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low speed blade flap on a gyroplane is a result of\n",
        "answer": "taxiing too fast.\n",
        "choiceone": "rotor blade pitch set too high.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the rotor blades being too heavy.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to improve engine efficiency, two-cycle engine exhaust systems are tuned to\n",
        "answer": "stop the fuel mixture from exiting the cylinder before combustion.\n",
        "choiceone": "close the exhaust valve to stop the fuel mixture from exiting the cylinder.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use a reed valve to stop the fuel mixture from exiting the cylinder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of carburetor ice in an aircraft equipped with a fixed-pitch propeller can be\nverified by applying carburetor heat and noting\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in RPM and then a gradual increase in RPM.\n",
        "choiceone": "a decrease in RPM and then a constant RPM indication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase in RPM and then a gradual decrease in RPM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How should a balloon fuel system be checked for leaks prior to flight?\n",
        "answer": "Look, listen, and smell.\n",
        "choiceone": "Check for unusual discoloration on burner coils.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cover all fittings and hoses with soapy water and look for small bubbles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is considered a primary flight control?\n",
        "answer": "Elevator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Slats.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dorsal fin.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thermal plugs are installed in:\n",
        "answer": "wheel rims.\n",
        "choiceone": "cabin windows.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cargo compartments.\n",
        "choicethree": "fire warning systems.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the cabin altitude rises (aircraft in level flight), the differential pressure:\n",
        "answer": "decreases\n",
        "choiceone": "increases\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains constant\n",
        "choicethree": "may exceed the maximum permitted differential unless immediate preventative\naction is taken.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming cabin pressure decreases, the cabin rate of climb indicator should indicate :\n",
        "answer": "a rate of climb.\n",
        "choiceone": "a rate of descent of approximately 300 feet per minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "zero.\n",
        "choicethree": "a rate of descent dependent upon the cabin differential pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why should special precautions be taken when filling propane bottles?\n",
        "answer": "Propane is very cold and may cause freeze burns.\n",
        "choiceone": "During transfer, propane reaches a high temperature and can cause severe burns.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propane is under high pressure when transferred from storage tanks to propane\nbottles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cVapor lock\" is the phenomenon by which:\n",
        "answer": "heat produces vapour plugs in the fuel line.\n",
        "choiceone": "burnt gas plugs forming and remaining in the exhaust manifold following an\noverheat and thereby disturbing the exhaust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "water vapour plugs are formed in the intake fuel line following the condensation of\nwater in fuel tanks which have not been drained for sometime.\n",
        "choicethree": "abrupt and abnormal enrichment of the fuel/air mixture following an inappropriate\nuse of carburettor heat.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a turbine engine, the term self-sustaining speed means the engine\n",
        "answer": "will run without any external assistance.\n",
        "choiceone": "operates most efficiently in the cruise...\n",
        "choicetwo": "will enable the generators to supply bus-bar voltage.\n",
        "choicethree": "is designed to idle after starting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An impulse turbine is a turbine in which the expansion takes place:\n",
        "answer": "fully in the stator.\n",
        "choiceone": "in order to produce a degree of jet propulsion < 1/2.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fully in the rotor.\n",
        "choicethree": "in the stator and in the rotor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Asynchronous four-pole motor is fed at a speed of\n",
        "answer": "12000 revolutions per minute.\n",
        "choiceone": "800 revolutions per minute.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1600 revolutions per minute.\n",
        "choicethree": "6000 revolutions per minute.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airplane whose maximum approved passenger seating configuration is 401 to 500\n\nseats must be equipped with at least:\n",
        "answer": "6 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment.\n",
        "choicethree": "8 hand fire-extinguishers conveniently located in the passenger compartment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A gyroplane will have the greatest tendency to roll during\n",
        "answer": "horizontal flight at high speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "climbing flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "descending flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should be the indication on the magnetic compass as you roll into a standard rate\nturn to the right from a south heading in the Northern Hemisphere?\n",
        "answer": "The compass will indicate a turn to the right, but at a faster rate than is actually\noccurring.\n",
        "choiceone": "The compass will initially indicate a turn to the left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The compass will remain on south for a short time, then gradually catch up to the\nmagnetic heading of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A possible result of using the emergency alternate source of static pressure inside the\ncabin of an unpressurized airplane is the\n",
        "answer": "altimeter may indicate an altitude higher than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "airspeed indicator may indicate less than normal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter may indicate an altitude lower than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot head is blocked, what airspeed indication can he expected?\n",
        "answer": "No change of IAS in level flight, even with large power changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "A decrease of IAS during a climb.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Constant IAS during a descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which procedure is recommended to prevent or overcome spatial disorientation?\n",
        "answer": "Rely entirely on the indications of the flight instruments.\n",
        "choiceone": "Avoid steep turns and rough control movements.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Reduce head and eye movements to the greatest extent possible.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true about magnetic deviation of a compass?\n",
        "answer": "Deviation varies for different headings of the same aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Deviation is the same for all aircraft in the same locality.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deviation is different in a given aircraft in different localities.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the runway distance remaining markers.\n",
        "answer": "Signs with increments of 1,000 feet distance remaining.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red markers laterally placed across the runway at 3,000 feet from the end.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow marker laterally placed across the runway with signs on the side denoting\ndistance to end.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which may lead to a power push-over in a gyroplane?\n",
        "answer": "Rotor force is removed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decreasing power too quickly.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, which would be correct about starting the rollout from a\nturn using a magnetic compass? Start the rollout\n",
        "answer": "after the compass indication passes south by a number of degrees approximately\nequal to the latitude minus the normal rollout lead.\n",
        "choiceone": "before the compass indication reaches south by a number of degrees approximately\nequal to the latitude over which the turn is made plus the pilot's normal lead.\n",
        "choicetwo": "after the compass indication passes south by a number of degrees approximately\nequal to the magnetic variation of the area over which the turn is made plus the\npilot's normal lead.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 140.) Which\nthe 1.9 NM pointis indicated?\n\nplacement from the localizer and glide slope at\n",
        "answer": "710 feet to the right of the localizer centerline and 140 feet above the glide slope.\n",
        "choiceone": "710 feet to the left of the localizer centerline and 140 feet below the glide slope.\n",
        "choicetwo": "430 feet to the right of the localizer centerline and 28 feet above the glide slope.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "nificance of the blue radial line on the airspeed\nmultiengine airplane and when is it to be used? It indicates the\n\n",
        "answer": "speed which will provide the maximum altitude gain in a given time when one engine\nis inoperative and should be used for climb and final approach during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "choiceone": "minimum speed at which the airplane is controllable when the critical engine is\nsuddenly made inoperative and should be used at all altitudes when an engine is\ninoperative.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed which will provide the greatest height for a given distance of forward travel\nwhen one engine is inoperative and should be used for all climbs during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How will the airspeed icator react if the ram ai\nice, but the drain hole and static port are not?\n\nput to the pitot head is blocked by\n",
        "answer": "Indication will drop to zero.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indication will rise to the top of the scale.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indication will remain constant but will increase in a climb.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify touchdown zone lighting (TDZL).\n",
        "answer": "Two rows of transverse light bars disposed symmetrically about the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flush centerline lights spaced at 50-foot intervals extending through the touchdown\nzone.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate white and green centerline lights extending from 75 feet from the threshold\nthrough the touchdown zone.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot Head and Static Vent were blocked by ice, which instruments would be\naffected?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter, VSI and ASI would give inaccurate readings.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and Slip indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ASI would under read.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VSI may suffer from error due to:\n",
        "answer": "time lag, instrument calibration, blockage\n",
        "choiceone": "compressibility, time lag, blockage\n",
        "choicetwo": "density, aircraft manoeuvre, position of the static vent\n",
        "choicethree": "pitot blockage, static blockage, aircraft manoeuvre\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "VFE is the maximum speed:\n",
        "answer": "with the flaps extended.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the flaps extended in the landing configuration.\n",
        "choicetwo": "with the flaps extended in the take-off configuration.\n",
        "choicethree": "at which the flaps can be operated when flying in turbulences.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb, the static line becomes blocked, the ASI will:\n",
        "answer": "under-read\n",
        "choiceone": "read normally\n",
        "choicetwo": "over-read\n",
        "choicethree": "read zero\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ASI consists of a gas tight casing which has:\n",
        "answer": "pitot pressure fed into an open capsule and static pressure fed outside the capsule\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule and pitot pressure fed into a second\nopen capsule\n",
        "choicetwo": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule\n",
        "choicethree": "static pressure fed through a restrictive choke\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (34).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true regarding fouling of the spark plugs of an aircraft engine?\n",
        "answer": "Spark plug fouling results from operating with an excessively rich mixture.\n",
        "choiceone": "Carbon fouling of the spark plugs is caused primarily by operating an engine at\nexcessively high cylinder head temperatures.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Excessive heat in the combustion chamber of a cylinder causes oil to form on the\ncenter electrode of a spark plug and this fouls the plug.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fuel vents on many powered parachutes and weight shift control aircraft are located\n",
        "answer": "in the fuel cap.\n",
        "choiceone": "adjacent to the crankcase breather.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in the fuel tank pressure relief valve.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The presence of carburetor ice in an aircraft equipped with a fixed-pitch propeller can be\nverified by applying carburetor heat and noting\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in RPM and then a gradual increase in RPM.\n",
        "choiceone": "a decrease in RPM and then a constant RPM indication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase in RPM and then a gradual decrease in RPM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of oxygen should be used to replenish an aircraft oxygen system?\n",
        "answer": "Aviation.\n",
        "choiceone": "Medical.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Industrial.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a purpose of leading-edge slats on high-performance wings?\n",
        "answer": "Increase lift at relative slow speeds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Improve aileron control during low angles of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct air from the low pressure area under the leading edge along the top of the\nwing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can the pilot increase the rate of turn and decrease the radius at the same time?\n",
        "answer": "Steepen the bank and decrease airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Steepen the bank and increase airspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Shallow the bank and increase airspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are considered primary flight controls?\n",
        "answer": "Outboard ailerons.\n",
        "choiceone": "Tabs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flaps.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which direction from the primary control surface does a servo tab move?\n",
        "answer": "Opposite direction.\n",
        "choiceone": "Same direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Remains fixed for all positions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to energy storage, the accumulator of the hydraulic system is used :\n",
        "answer": "for damping pressure surges in the system.\n",
        "choiceone": "for pressure storage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "as a pressure relief valve.\n",
        "choicethree": "for fluid storage.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hydraulic fluids used in systems of large modern airliners are:\n",
        "answer": "Phosphate ester base fluids.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mineral base fluids.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Water base fluids.\n",
        "choicethree": "Vegetable base fluids.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The part of the flight that will cause the highest loads on tyre\n",
        "answer": "Taxiing with a small turning radius.\n",
        "choiceone": "Touch down with crosswind\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gear down selection\n",
        "choicethree": "Braking with an inoperative anti skid system.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of a shuttle valve is to:\n",
        "answer": "Supply an operating unit with the most appropriate system pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Protect a hydraulic system from overpressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Relieve excess pressure in hydraulic systems.\n",
        "choicethree": "Prevent overloading of the hydraulic pump.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cabin rate of descent is:\n",
        "answer": "a cabin pressure increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "a cabin pressure decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not possible at constant airplane altitudes.\n",
        "choicethree": "always the same as the airplane's rate of descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an alternator rotor coil you can find :\n",
        "answer": "AC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only induced current.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dc.\n",
        "choicethree": "Three-phase AC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a battery is almost fully discharged there is a tendency for the :\n",
        "answer": "voltage to decrease under load.\n",
        "choiceone": "electrolyte to \"boil\".\n",
        "choicetwo": "voltage to increase due to the current available.\n",
        "choicethree": "current produced to increase due to the reduced voltage.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An impulse magneto coupling\n",
        "answer": "gives a retarded spark at starting\n",
        "choiceone": "gives an automatic spark increase during high speed operation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "reduces magneto speed during engine warm-up\n",
        "choicethree": "advances ignition timing and gives a hotter spark at starting\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does V(NE) speed vary with altitude?\n",
        "answer": "Varies inversely with altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Varies directly with altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Remains the same at all altitudes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What effect, if any, does altitude have on V(MC) for an\nengines?\n\nplane with unsupercharged\n",
        "answer": "Decreases with altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "None.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increases with altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a fire detection system with single-loop continuous components (with no fault\nprotection), if the inner core contacts the outer casing:\n",
        "answer": "the fire alarm is triggered.\n",
        "choiceone": "the power supply is cut off automatically.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there will be no effect on the system\n",
        "choicethree": "the main engine fire extinguisher is automatically activated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The safety precautions to be taken whenever using\noxygen are:\n\n1. refrain from smoking, avoid sparkes.\n\n2. Avoid operation of radio communication equipment.\n\n3. Slowly operate oxygen system valves.\n\n4. Avoid greasy matter.\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :\n",
        "answer": "1,3, 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "1, 2,3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2, 3,4.\n",
        "choicethree": "1,2,4.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 141.) Which displacement from the localizer centerline and\nglide slope at the 1,300-foot point from the runway is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "21 feet above the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "21 feet below the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the right of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "28 feet above the glide slope and approximately 250 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When making an airborne VOR check, what is the maximum allowable tolerance\nbetween the two indicators of a dual VOR system (units independent of each other\nexcept the antenna)?\n\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees between the two indicated bearings of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus or minus 4 degrees when set to identical radials of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 degrees between the two indicated radials of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 85.) Of the following, which is the minimum acceptable rate of climb (feet\nper minute) to 9,000 feet required for the WASH2 WAGGE departure at a GS of 150\nknots?\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet per minute.\n",
        "choiceone": "750 feet per minute.\n",
        "choicetwo": "825 feet per minute.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, if an aircrat\ncompass will normally indicate\n\naccelerated or decelerated, the magnetic\n",
        "answer": "correctly when on a north or south heading while either accelerating or decelerating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a turn momentarily, with changes in airspeed on any heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a turn toward the south while accelerating on a west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a lighted heliport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choiceone": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Concerning the pitot and static system, the static pressure error:\n",
        "answer": "is caused by disturbed airflow around the static ports.\n",
        "choiceone": "is a direct effect of heating of the static ports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "affects the alternate static port only.\n",
        "choicethree": "is a direct effect of a blockage of the static port.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The limits of the green scale of an airspeed indicator are:\n",
        "answer": "VS1 and VNO.\n",
        "choiceone": "VS1 and VMO.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VSO and VNE.\n",
        "choicethree": "VS1 and VNE.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ASI consists of a gas tight casing which has:\n",
        "answer": "pitot pressure fed into an open capsule and static pressure fed outside the capsule\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule and pitot pressure fed into a second\nopen capsule\n",
        "choicetwo": "static pressure fed outside a sealed capsule\n",
        "choicethree": "static pressure fed through a restrictive choke\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mach number is:\n",
        "answer": "the ratio of TAS to LSS at that temperature\n",
        "choiceone": "the ratio of IAS toLSS\n",
        "choicetwo": "the speed at which compressibility error must be calculated\n",
        "choicethree": "the ratio of EAS to LSS at that temperature\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a CADC the output of vertical speed is achieved by means of:\n",
        "answer": "a measurement of the rate of change of altitude as sensed by the static pressure\ntransducer\n",
        "choiceone": "a dedicated vertical speed transducer\n",
        "choicetwo": "an integration of the CAS transducer output\n",
        "choicethree": "a combination of the outputs of the dynamic and static pressure transducers\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\\g at a constant Mach number in the standard atmosphere, the\n\n",
        "answer": "increase\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease\n",
        "choicetwo": "remain constant\n",
        "choicethree": "remain constant unless the aircraft flies through an inversion\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rotor of the DGI spins up and away from the pilot when 090 is ir\nlatitude compensation nut situated on the near right hand side of the inner gimbal from\nthe gyro axis, has been set to give zero drift on the ground at the equator. To\ncompensate for earth rotation at 30 S the latitude compensating nut:\n",
        "answer": "must be adjusted outwards;\n",
        "choiceone": "must be adjusted inwards;\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not adjusted since the latitude nut can only be used to correct for apparent\nwander in the northern hemisphere.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following figures appear on an aeroplane deviation card: FOR MAGNETIC (45----90),\nSTEER COMPASS (38----92). The compass heading to steer to maintain a heading of\n075\u00b0 (M) is:\n",
        "answer": "74\n",
        "choiceone": "72\n",
        "choicetwo": "76\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of rigi\ninstruments:\n\nused for the operation of the following gyroscopic\n",
        "answer": "Directional Gyro and Artificial Horizon.\n",
        "choiceone": "Directional Gyro and Turn indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Artificial Horizon and Turn indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One characteristic that a properly functioning gyro depends upon for operation is the:\n",
        "answer": "Resistance to deflection of the gyro rotor.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ability to resist precession at 90 degrees to an applied force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position of the gyro axis relative to the Earth's axis.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A warning flag appears on an electrical Turn and Slip indicator, this means:\n",
        "answer": "Turn indicator failure. Slip indicator serviceable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Total instrument failure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turn indicator underreads, slip not affected.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When, in flight, the needle of a needle-and-ball indicator is on the right and the ball on\nthe left, the aeroplane is:\n",
        "answer": "turning right with too much right rudder pedal.\n",
        "choiceone": "turning right with not enough right rudder pedal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "turning left with too much right rudder pedal.\n",
        "choicethree": "turning left with not enough right rudder pedal.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What indications should you get from the Turn and Slip indicator during taxi?\n",
        "answer": "The ball moves opposite to the turn and the needle deflects in the direction of the\nturn.\n",
        "choiceone": "The needle and ball should move freely in the direction of the turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ball deflects opposite to the turn and the needle remains central.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which stroke of a reciprocating engine is the gaseous mixture expanding within\nthe cylinder?\n",
        "answer": "Power.\n",
        "choiceone": "Intake.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Compression.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The low temperature that causes carburetor ice in an engine equipped with a float-type\ncarburetor is normally the result of the\n",
        "answer": "vaporization of fuel and expansion of air in the carburetor.\n",
        "choiceone": "compression of air at the carburetor venturi.\n",
        "choicetwo": "freezing temperature of the air entering the carburetor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At which speed will increasing the pitch attitude cause an airplane to climb?\n",
        "answer": "High speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any speed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a hydraulic braking system, the accumulator is:\n",
        "answer": "an accumulator designed to restore brake energy in the event of a hydraulic failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "a damping type accumulator designed to take up the pressure fluctuations of the\nautomatic braking system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "designed to take up the hydraulic energy filtered by the anti-skid system in order to\nprevent wheel blocking.\n",
        "choicethree": "a buffer accumulator whose function is to assist the hydraulic system during high\nintensity braking.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The function of a fusible plug is to\n",
        "answer": "protect the tyre against explosion due to excessive temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "protect the brake against brake disk fusion due to excessive temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "function as a special circuit breaker in the electric system\n",
        "choicethree": "protect against excessive pressure in the pneumatic system.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On most modern airliners the cabin pressure is controlled by regulating the:\n",
        "answer": "Airflow leaving the cabin.\n",
        "choiceone": "Bleed air valve.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airflow entering the cabin.\n",
        "choicethree": "RPM of the engine.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the cabin altitude rises (aeroplane in level flight), the differential pressure:\n",
        "answer": "decreases\n",
        "choiceone": "increases\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains constant\n",
        "choicethree": "may exceed the maximum permitted differential unless immediate preventative action\nis taken.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the baffles in an aircraft's integral fuel tank is to:\n",
        "answer": "Restrict the fuel from flowing to the wing tips during abnormal manoeuvre (side\nslipping...).\n",
        "choiceone": "Prevent the fuel from flowing in the vent lines.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prevent mixture of the fuel and hydraulic fluid.\n",
        "choicethree": "Prevent overpressure in the tank.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a conductor cuts the field lines of a magnetic field:\n",
        "answer": "an Lorentz force is induced in the conductor.\n",
        "choiceone": "there will be no effect on the conductor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the field will collapse.\n",
        "choicethree": "the current will stop.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A static inverter is a:\n",
        "answer": "transistorized unit used to convert DC into AC.\n",
        "choiceone": "device for reversing the polarity of the static charge.\n",
        "choicetwo": "static discharger.\n",
        "choicethree": "filter against radio interference.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an aircraft electrical system where AC generators are not paralleled mounted, the\nchangover relay allows :\n",
        "answer": "power supply to the faulty AC generators busbar.\n",
        "choiceone": "connection of the Auxiliary Power Unit (APU) to its main busbar.\n",
        "choicetwo": "connection of the AC generator to its distribution busbar.\n",
        "choicethree": "connection of the ground power truck to its distribution busbar.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft magneto is switched off by\n",
        "answer": "grounding the primary circuit\n",
        "choiceone": "opening the primary circuit\n",
        "choicetwo": "opening the secondary circuit\n",
        "choicethree": "grounding the secondary circuit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an engine fails to stop with the magneto switch in OFF position, the cause may be:\n",
        "answer": "excessive carbon formation in cylinder head.\n",
        "choiceone": "switch wire grounded\n",
        "choicetwo": "defective condenser\n",
        "choicethree": "fouled spark plugs\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the advantages of a turbosupercharger is that :\n",
        "answer": "it uses the exhaust gas energy which normally is lost.\n",
        "choiceone": "it has a better propulsive efficiency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there is no torsion at the crankshaft.\n",
        "choicethree": "there is no danger of knocking.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kind of compressor normally used as a turbocharger is:\n",
        "answer": "a radial compressor.\n",
        "choiceone": "an axial compressor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a hybrid compressor.\n",
        "choicethree": "a piston compressor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Turbine blade stages may be classed as either \"impulse\" or \u201creaction\u201d. In ai\nblade section :\n",
        "answer": "the pressure drops across the nozzle guide vanes and remains constant across the\nrotor blades .\n",
        "choiceone": "the pressure remains constant across the nozzle guide vanes and rises constant\nacross the rotor blades .\n",
        "choicetwo": "the pressure rises across the nozzle guide vanes and remains constant across the\nrotor blades .\n",
        "choicethree": "the pressure remains constant across the nozzle guide vanes and drops across the\nrotor blades .\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct about the flow in a divergent jet engine inlet?\n|. The speed increases in flow direction.\nll. The total pressure increases in flow direction.\n",
        "answer": "lis incorrect, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "lis incorrect, Il is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lis correct, Il is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "lis correct, Il is correct.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most common extinguishing agent used in gas turbine engine fire protection system\nis:\n",
        "answer": "Freon.\n",
        "choiceone": "Water.\n",
        "choicetwo": "co2.\n",
        "choicethree": "Powder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Continuous loop fire detector systems operate on the principle that an increase in\ntemperature produces:\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in resistance\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase in resistance\n",
        "choicetwo": "a decrease in the reference current\n",
        "choicethree": "a decrease in pressure\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 85.) What route should you take if cleared for the Washoe Two\nDeparture and your assigned route is V6?\n",
        "answer": "Climb on the LOC south course to WAGGE where you will be vectored to V6.\n",
        "choiceone": "Climb on the LOC south course to cross WAGGE at 9,000, turn left and fly direct to\nFMG VORTAC and cross at or above 10,000, and proceed on FMG R-241.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Climb on the LOC south course to WAGGE, turn left and fly direct to FMG VORTAC. If\nat 10,000 turn left and proceed on FMG R-241; if not at 10,000 enter depicted holding\npattern and climb to 10,000 before proceeding on FMG R-241.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 141.) Which displacement from the localizer centerline and\nglide slope at the 1,300-foot point from the runway is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "21 feet above the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "21 feet below the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the right of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "28 feet above the glide slope and approximately 250 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify taxi leadoff lights associated with the centerline lighting system.\n",
        "answer": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to a point\non the exit.\n",
        "choiceone": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\ncenterline of the taxiway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate green and yellow lights curving from the centerline of the runway to the\nedge of the taxiway.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, if an aircrat\ncompass will normally indicate\n\naccelerated or decelerated, the magnetic\n",
        "answer": "correctly when on a north or south heading while either accelerating or decelerating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a turn momentarily, with changes in airspeed on any heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a turn toward the south while accelerating on a west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The RPM indicator of a piston engine can include a small red arc within the arc normally\nused (green arc).\nIn the RPM range corresponding to this small red arc the:\n",
        "answer": "propeller generates vibration, continuous rating is forbidden\n",
        "choiceone": "rating is the maximum possible in continuous mode\n",
        "choicetwo": "rating is the minimum usable in cruise\n",
        "choicethree": "propeller efficiency is minimum at this rating\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot Head and Static Vent were blocked by ice, which instruments would be\naffected?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter, VSI and ASI would give inaccurate readings.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and Slip indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ASI would under read.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ASI compressibility error will increase with increase of TAS and:\n",
        "answer": "Increase with altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Decrease with altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increase with increase of density.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The high Altitude Radio Altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicethree": "metric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft leaves FL 160 for an approach and landing at an airfield. The pilot will set\nQNH at the:\n",
        "answer": "Transition level.\n",
        "choiceone": "Transition Layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transition Altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a servo-assisted altimeter, the secondary winding from the E bar provides an\nelectrical current direct to the:\n",
        "answer": "amplifier\n",
        "choiceone": "capsule stack\n",
        "choicetwo": "two phase motor\n",
        "choicethree": "AC input lines of the primary winding\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot opening is blocked, whi\nvent)?\n\nstruments would be affected (separate static\n",
        "answer": "ASI only.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and VSI.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ASI and VSI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the northern hemisphere, an aircraft takes-off on a runway with an alignment of 045\u00b0.\nDuring the rake-off run, the compass indicates:\n",
        "answer": "a value below 045\u00b0.\n",
        "choiceone": "045\u00b0.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a value above 045\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "225\u00b0.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Errors in both pitch and bank indication on an attitude indicator are usually ata\nmaximum as the aircraft rolls out of a:\n",
        "answer": "180 degree turn;\n",
        "choiceone": "90 degree turn;\n",
        "choicetwo": "270 degree turn.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The gyroscope of a turn indicator has:\n\n(NB: the rotor spin axis is not counted for the number of degrees of freedom of the gyro)\n",
        "answer": "1 degree of freedom.\n",
        "choiceone": "0 degree of freedom.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 degrees of freedom.\n",
        "choicethree": "3 degrees of freedom.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate angle of bank for a rate one turn at 110 knots?\n",
        "answer": "18 degrees\n",
        "choiceone": "25 degrees\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 degrees\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the CFR Part 1 definition of critical engine?\n",
        "answer": "The engine whose failure would most adversely affect airplane performance or\nhandling qualities.\n",
        "choiceone": "The outboard engine whose failure would most adversely affect safety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The engine still running which would most adversely affect performance if it should\nfail.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A sandwich structural part:\n",
        "answer": "consists of two thin sheets separated by a light core material.\n",
        "choiceone": "always uses honeycomb as core material.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is a so-called integral construction.\n",
        "choicethree": "is unsuitable for fuel tanks.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are outboard ailerons normally used?\n",
        "answer": "Low-speed flight only.\n",
        "choiceone": "High-speed flight only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low-speed and high-speed flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An artificial feel unit is necessary in the pitch channel when:\n",
        "answer": "the elevators are actuated by irreversible servo-control units.\n",
        "choiceone": "the elevators are actuated by reversible servo-control units.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elevators are fitted with servo-tabs or trim tabs.\n",
        "choicethree": "there is a trimmable stabilizer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aircraft with a gross weight of 2,000 pounds were subjected to a total load of 6,000\npounds in flight, the load factor would be\n",
        "answer": "3 Gs.\n",
        "choiceone": "2Gs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9Gs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a hydraulic braking system, the accumulator is:\n",
        "answer": "an accumulator designed to restore brake energy in the event of a hydraulic failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "a damping type accumulator designed to take up the pressure fluctuations of the\nautomatic braking system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "designed to take up the hydraulic energy filtered by the anti-skid system in order to\nprevent wheel blocking.\n",
        "choicethree": "a buffer accumulator whose function is to assist the hydraulic system during high\nintensity braking.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A main landing gear is said to be \u201clocked down\" when:\n",
        "answer": "the strut is locked by an overcentre mechanism.\n",
        "choiceone": "itis in the down position.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the actuating cylinder is at the end of it's travel.\n",
        "choicethree": "the corresponding indicator lamp is amber.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a ditching situation, the passenger life jackets will be inflated :\n",
        "answer": "when leaving the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "immediately on the opening of the exits.\n",
        "choicetwo": "immediately on ditching.\n",
        "choicethree": "once the passengers are in the water.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cabin altitude means the:\n",
        "answer": "cabin pressure expressed as altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight level the aircraft is flying at.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight level altitude at maximum differential pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "difference in height between the cabin floor and ceiling.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term \"Bootstrap\", when used to identify a cabin air conditioning and pressurisation\nsystem, refers to the :\n",
        "answer": "cold air unit (air cycle machine) arrangement.\n",
        "choiceone": "source of the charge air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "means by which pressurisation is controlled.\n",
        "choicethree": "charge air across the inter-cooler heat exchanger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The types of fuel tanks used on most modern transport aircraft are:\n",
        "answer": "Integral tanks.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cell tanks.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Combined fuel tanks.\n",
        "choicethree": "Fixed built-in tanks.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order that DC generators will act\nis necessary to ensure that :\n\nve equal load sharing when operating in parallel, it\n",
        "answer": "their voltages are almost equal.\n",
        "choiceone": "the synchronising bus-bar is disconnected from the busbar system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "equal loads are connected to each generator busbar before paralleling.\n",
        "choicethree": "adequate voltage differences exists.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As regards three-phase AC generators, the following conditions must be met for\nparalleling AC generators: 1. Equal voltage 2.Equal current 3.Equal frequencies 4.\nSame 5. Voltages of same phase The combination regrouping all the correct\nstatementsphase rotation is :\n",
        "answer": "1,3,4,5\n",
        "choiceone": "1,4,5\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,2,3,4\n",
        "choicethree": "1,3,5\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In general, in twin-engine aeroplanes with \u2018constant speed propeller\u2019\n",
        "answer": "the oil pressure turns the propeller blades towards smaller pitch angle.\n",
        "choiceone": "the aerodynamic force turns the propeller blades towards higher pitch angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the spring force turns the propeller blades towards smaller pitch angle.\n",
        "choicethree": "the oil pressure turns the propeller blades towards higher pitch angle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the advantages of a turbosupercharger is that :\n",
        "answer": "it uses the exhaust gas energy which normally is lost.\n",
        "choiceone": "it has a better propulsive efficiency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there is no torsion at the crankshaft.\n",
        "choicethree": "there is no danger of knocking.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What effect, if any, does altitude have on V(MC) for an\nengines?\n\nplane with unsupercharged\n",
        "answer": "Decreases with altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "None.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increases with altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to fire detention/protection, most auxiliary power units (APUs) have\nautomatic controls for starting, stopping and maintaining operation within safe limits.\n\nThese starting cycle as well as protection against :controls provide correct sequencing\nof the\n",
        "answer": "high turbine gas temperature (TGT), overspeed, and loss of oil.\n",
        "choiceone": "high TGT and loss of oil pressure only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "overspeed and high oil temperature only.\n",
        "choicethree": "high TGT only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A public transport passengers aircraft, with a seating configuration of more than 61\nseats, must have in its passenger compartment{s), at least 3 portable fire- extinguishers\nincluding:\n",
        "answer": "2 halon fire-extinguishers.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 halon fire-extinguisher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 halon fire-extinguishers.\n",
        "choicethree": "no halon fire-extinguisher.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a multi-engined aircraft a fire detection system includes :\n",
        "answer": "a warning light for each engine and a single alarm bell common to all engines\n",
        "choiceone": "a single warning light and a single alarm bell\n",
        "choicetwo": "both a warning light and an alarm bell unique to each engine\n",
        "choicethree": "a single warning light but a separate alarm bell for each engine\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Continuous-Loop-Detector-System is a:\n",
        "answer": "Fire detection system\n",
        "choiceone": "Carbon dioxide warning system\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fire fighting system\n",
        "choicethree": "Smoke detection system\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When making an airborne VOR check, what is the maximum allowable tolerance\nbetween the two indicators of a dual VOR system (units independent of each other\nexcept the antenna)?\n\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees between the two indicated bearings of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus or minus 4 degrees when set to identical radials of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 degrees between the two indicated radials of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which procedure is recommended to prevent or overcome spatial disorientation?\n",
        "answer": "Rely entirely on the indications of the flight instruments.\n",
        "choiceone": "Avoid steep turns and rough control movements.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Reduce head and eye movements to the greatest extent possible.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should be the indication on the magnetic compass as you roll into a standard rate\nturn to the right from a south heading in the Northern Hemisphere?\n",
        "answer": "The compass will indicate a turn to the right, but at a faster rate than is actually\noccurring.\n",
        "choiceone": "The compass will initially indicate a turn to the left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The compass will remain on south for a short time, then gradually catch up to the\nmagnetic heading of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deviation error of the magnetic compass is caused by\n",
        "answer": "certain metals and electrical systems within the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "northerly turning error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the difference in location of true north and magnetic north.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A gyroplane will have the greatest tendency to roll during\n",
        "answer": "horizontal flight at high speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "climbing flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "descending flight in which forward airspeed decreases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 85.) What route should you take if cleared for the Washoe Two\nDeparture and your assigned route is V6?\n",
        "answer": "Climb on the LOC south course to WAGGE where you will be vectored to V6.\n",
        "choiceone": "Climb on the LOC south course to cross WAGGE at 9,000, turn left and fly direct to\nFMG VORTAC and cross at or above 10,000, and proceed on FMG R-241.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Climb on the LOC south course to WAGGE, turn left and fly direct to FMG VORTAC. If\nat 10,000 turn left and proceed on FMG R-241; if not at 10,000 enter depicted holding\npattern and climb to 10,000 before proceeding on FMG R-241.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an altimeter indicates 3500 FT with the actual QNH of 1004, 7 hPa set, the approximate\npressure altitude i\n\n",
        "answer": "3745 FT\n",
        "choiceone": "3500 FT\n",
        "choicetwo": "3255 FT\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Transition altitude is obtained from:\n",
        "answer": "Jeppesen or Aerad flight guides.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC or VOR ATIS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1500 feet above airfield elevation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the static source of an altimeter becomes blocked during a descent th\nwill:\n",
        "answer": "continue to display the reading at which the blockage occurred.\n",
        "choiceone": "gradually indicate zero.\n",
        "choicetwo": "under-read.\n",
        "choicethree": "indicate a height with the subscale setting on QNH.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The percentage error due to the positioning of the static vent\n",
        "answer": "the same in the Machmeter as in the ASI\n",
        "choiceone": "greater in the ASI than in the Machmeter\n",
        "choicetwo": "greater in the Machmeter than in the ASI\n",
        "choicethree": "either greater or smaller when comparing the ASI and the Machmeter,\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A RMI (Radio Magnetic Indicator) displays a warning flag which\nfailure. The radio bearing pointers:\n\n",
        "answer": "can be used to home to an NDB;\n",
        "choiceone": "are not to be used;\n",
        "choicetwo": "can be used to home to an NDB and a VOR station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Errors in both pitch and bank indication on an attitude indicator are usually ata\nmaximum as the aircraft rolls out of a:\n",
        "answer": "180 degree turn;\n",
        "choiceone": "90 degree turn;\n",
        "choicetwo": "270 degree turn.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The gyroscope of a turn indicator has:\n\n(NB: the rotor spin axis is not counted for the number of degrees of freedom of the gyro)\n",
        "answer": "1 degree of freedom.\n",
        "choiceone": "0 degree of freedom.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 degrees of freedom.\n",
        "choicethree": "3 degrees of freedom.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 022-10217A)\nConsidering the diagram n\u00b0, the flight director command bars position indicates that\nyou should:\n",
        "answer": "bank your aircraft to the left and increase the pitch angle.\n",
        "choiceone": "bank your aircraft to the right and increase the pitch angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "bank your aircraft to the left and reduce the pitch angle.\n",
        "choicethree": "bank your aircraft to the right and reduce the pitch angle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The radio altimeter is required to indicate zero height AGL as the main wheels touch\ndown on the runway. For this reason, it is necessary to:\n",
        "answer": "compensate for residual height and cable length.\n",
        "choiceone": "adjust the gross height according to the aeroplane instantaneous pitch.\n",
        "choicetwo": "change the display scale in short final, in order to have a precise readout.\n",
        "choicethree": "have a specific radio altimeter dedicated to automatic landing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The radio altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "centimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "millimetric\n",
        "choicethree": "metric.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Concerning the TCAS Il:\n",
        "answer": "No protection is available against aircraft not equipped with a serviceable SSR\ntransponder\n",
        "choiceone": "In one of the system modes, the warning: \"TOO LOW TERRAIN\" is generated\n",
        "choicetwo": "In one of the system modes, the warning: \"PULL UP\" is generated\n",
        "choicethree": "No protection is available against aircraft not equipped with a serviceable FMS\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first indication of carburetor ice in an aircraft with a fixed-pitch propeller is\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in RPM.\n",
        "choiceone": "a decrease in manifold pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase in manifold pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of oxygen should be used to replenish an aircraft oxygen system?\n",
        "answer": "Aviation.\n",
        "choiceone": "Medical.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Industrial.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If no corrective action is taken by the pilot as angle of ban!\nvertical component of lift and sink rate affected?\n\ncreased, how is the\n",
        "answer": "Lift decreases and the sink rate increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lift increases and the sink rate increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Lift decreases and the sink rate decreases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the relationship of the rate of turn with the radius of turn with a constant angle of\nbank but increasing airspeed?\n",
        "answer": "Rate will decrease and radius will increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rate will increase and radius will decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rate and radius will increase.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a hydraulic braking system, the accumulator is:\n",
        "answer": "an accumulator designed to restore brake energy in the event of a hydraulic failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "a damping type accumulator designed to take up the pressure fluctuations of the\nautomatic braking system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "designed to take up the hydraulic energy filtered by the anti-skid system in order to\nprevent wheel blocking.\n",
        "choicethree": "a buffer accumulator whose function is to assist the hydraulic system during high\nintensity braking.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An accumulator in a hydraulic system will :\n",
        "answer": "store fluid under pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase pressure surges within the system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "reduce fluid temperature and pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "reduce fluid temperature only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The component that transforms the hydraulic pressure into a linear motion is called ...\n",
        "answer": "An actuator or jack.\n",
        "choiceone": "An accumulator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A Pressure regulator.\n",
        "choicethree": "A hydraulic pump.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cabin pressure is regulated by the:\n",
        "answer": "Outflow valve.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cabin inlet airflow valve.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air cycle machine.\n",
        "choicethree": "Air conditioning pack.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rating of electrical fuses is expressed in:\n",
        "answer": "amperes.\n",
        "choiceone": "volts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "watts.\n",
        "choicethree": "ohms.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order that DC generators will act\nis necessary to ensure that :\n\nve equal load sharing when operating in parallel, it\n",
        "answer": "their voltages are almost equal.\n",
        "choiceone": "the synchronising bus-bar is disconnected from the busbar system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "equal loads are connected to each generator busbar before paralleling.\n",
        "choicethree": "adequate voltage differences exists.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To ensure correct load sharing between AC generators operating in parallel :\n",
        "answer": "both real an reactive loads must be matched.\n",
        "choiceone": "the matching of loads is unimportant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only reactive loads need to be matched.\n",
        "choicethree": "only real loads need to be matched.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an aircraft electrical system where AC generators are not paralleled mounted, the\nchangover relay allows :\n",
        "answer": "power supply to the faulty AC generators busbar.\n",
        "choiceone": "connection of the Auxiliary Power Unit (APU) to its main busbar.\n",
        "choicetwo": "connection of the AC generator to its distribution busbar.\n",
        "choicethree": "connection of the ground power truck to its distribution busbar.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The working cycle of a four-stroke engine is :\n",
        "answer": "induction, compression, power, exhaust.\n",
        "choiceone": "induction, power, compression, exhaust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "compression induction, power, exhaust.\n",
        "choicethree": "induction, compression, expansion, power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The compression ratio of a piston engine is the ratio of the:\n",
        "answer": "volume of the cylinder with the piston at bottom dead centre to that with the piston at\ntop dead centre.\n",
        "choiceone": "weight of the air induced to its weight after compression.\n",
        "choicetwo": "diameter of the bore to the piston stroke.\n",
        "choicethree": "area of the piston to the cylinder volume.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The power of a piston engine which will be measured by using a friction brake is :\n",
        "answer": "Brake horse power.\n",
        "choiceone": "Heat loss power.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicated horse power.\n",
        "choicethree": "Friction horse power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The power output of a piston engine can be calculated by :\n",
        "answer": "Torque times RPM.\n",
        "choiceone": "Force times distance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pressure times arm.\n",
        "choicethree": "Work times velocity.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The conditions under which you obtain the highest engine power are :\n",
        "answer": "cold and dry air at high pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "cold and humid air at high pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "warm and dry air at high pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "warm and humid air at low pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The equipment of an oxygen supply installation must be kept absolutely free of oil or\ngrease traces as:\n",
        "answer": "these substances catch fire spontaneously in the presence of oxygen under\npressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "these substances mixed with oxygen could catch fire in the presence of a spark.\n",
        "choicetwo": "these substances could plug the oxygen masks filters.\n",
        "choicethree": "the oxygen system would be contaminated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A diluter demand oxygen regulator :\n",
        "answer": "delivers oxygen flow when inhaling.\n",
        "choiceone": "mixes air and oxygen in a passenger oxygen mask.\n",
        "choicetwo": "delivers oxygen flow only above FL 100.\n",
        "choicethree": "is only recommended for use with smoke in the cockpit.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, if an aircrat\ncompass will normally indicate\n\naccelerated or decelerated, the magnetic\n",
        "answer": "correctly when on a north or south heading while either accelerating or decelerating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a turn momentarily, with changes in airspeed on any heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a turn toward the south while accelerating on a west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 141.) Which displacement from the localizer centerline and\nglide slope at the 1,300-foot point from the runway is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "21 feet above the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "21 feet below the glide slope and approximately 320 feet to the right of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "28 feet above the glide slope and approximately 250 feet to the left of the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which pul\nbe found?\n\nition can the VOR receiver ground checkpoint(s) for a particular\n",
        "answer": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "En Route Low Altitude Chart.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How will the airspeed icator react if the ram ai\nice, but the drain hole and static port are not?\n\nput to the pitot head is blocked by\n",
        "answer": "Indication will drop to zero.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indication will rise to the top of the scale.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indication will remain constant but will increase in a climb.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "nificance of the blue radial line on the airspeed\nmultiengine airplane and when is it to be used? It indicates the\n\n",
        "answer": "speed which will provide the maximum altitude gain in a given time when one engine\nis inoperative and should be used for climb and final approach during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "choiceone": "minimum speed at which the airplane is controllable when the critical engine is\nsuddenly made inoperative and should be used at all altitudes when an engine is\ninoperative.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed which will provide the greatest height for a given distance of forward travel\nwhen one engine is inoperative and should be used for all climbs during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 87.) At STRUT intersection headed eastbound, ATC instructs you to\nhold west on the 10 DME fix west of LCH on V306, standard turns, what entry procedure\nis recommended?\n",
        "answer": "Direct.\n",
        "choiceone": "Teardrop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Parallel.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pitot line is blocked, the VSI will:\n",
        "answer": "read normally\n",
        "choiceone": "read zero ftmm rate of climb/descent\n",
        "choicetwo": "over-read\n",
        "choicethree": "under-read\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VSI may suffer from error due to:\n",
        "answer": "time lag, instrument calibration, blockage\n",
        "choiceone": "compressibility, time lag, blockage\n",
        "choicetwo": "density, aircraft manoeuvre, position of the static vent\n",
        "choicethree": "pitot blockage, static blockage, aircraft manoeuvre\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "level flight, it becomes necessary to use an alternate source of static pressure\nje the aircraft, with the cabin pressure being lower than static, the following\nvariations in instrument indication would be expected:\n\n",
        "answer": "the altimeter will read higher than normal, airspeed greater than normal and the\nvertical-speed indicator will momentarily show a climb;\n",
        "choiceone": "the altimeter will read higher than normal, airspeed will not change and the vertical-\nspeed indicator will momentarily show a descent;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the altimeter will read lower than normal, airspeed greater than normal and the\nvertical-speed indicator will momentarily show a climb and then a descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "craft is flying from a cold air mass into a warm air mass. The TAS and true altitude\n\n",
        "answer": "Both increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "TAS increases, true altitude decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAS decreases, true altitude increases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airfield, elevation 3000 feet, has a pressure altitude of 3500 feet. What is the QFE?\n",
        "answer": "896.5 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "913.s hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "879.8 hPa\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To allow for changes in the viscosity of the air, the VSI employs:\n",
        "answer": "a restrictive choke\n",
        "choiceone": "a logarithmic scale\n",
        "choicetwo": "diaphragm overload stops\n",
        "choicethree": "a complex capillary/orifice choke system\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A direct reading magnetic compass is affected by coefficients B and C only, which\ntogether cause a maximum deviation of 7 degrees West on heading 247\u00b0 (C). The\nrespective values of coefficients B and C are:\n",
        "answer": "B 6,44 and C 2,73.\n",
        "choiceone": "B 2,73 and C 6,44.\n",
        "choicetwo": "B -3,20 and C - 3,80.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a steep turn, the northerly turning error on a direct reading magnetic compass on the\nnorthern hemisphere\n\n",
        "answer": "equal to 180\u00b0 on a 090\u00b0 heading in a right turn.\n",
        "choiceone": "none on a 270\u00b0 heading in a left turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "none on a 090\u00b0 heading in a right turn.\n",
        "choicethree": "equal to 180\u00b0 on a 270\u00b0 heading in a right turn.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Artificial Horizon employs a;\n",
        "answer": "Earth gyro\n",
        "choiceone": "Tied gyro\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rate gyro\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the rotational speed of the Turn and Slip gyro rotor is below the calibrated speed the:\n",
        "answer": "Turn indicator underreads, slip not affected.\n",
        "choiceone": "Turn indicator overreads.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turn indicator and Slip underreads.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Turn and Slip indicator pre-flight check consists of:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft level, turn needle central, ball central, fluid in tube.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft level, ball central, turn needle central.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft not level, turn needle and ball displaced.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an autopilot system:\n",
        "answer": "the inner loops provide the stability functions and the outer loops provide the\nguidance functions.\n",
        "choiceone": "the outer loops provide the stability functions and the inner loops provide the\nguidance functions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the outer loops provide the stability functions and the inner loops provide the\nguidance functions.\n",
        "choicethree": "the outer loops provide the stability functions only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Concerning the TCAS Il:\n",
        "answer": "No protection is available against aircraft not equipped with a serviceable SSR\ntransponder\n",
        "choiceone": "In one of the system modes, the warning: \"TOO LOW TERRAIN\" is generated\n",
        "choicetwo": "In one of the system modes, the warning: \"PULL UP\" is generated\n",
        "choicethree": "No protection is available against aircraft not equipped with a serviceable FMS\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Adding more oil to the fuel than specified by the manufacturer of a 2-cycle engine will\nresult in\n",
        "answer": "increased carbon buildup and engine fouling.\n",
        "choiceone": "increased engine performance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increased engine lubrication and optimal performance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first indication of carburetor ice in an aircraft with a four-cycle engine and fixed-\npitch propeller is\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in RPM.\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase in RPM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a decrease in oil pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a light, twin-engine airplane with one engine inoperative, when is it acceptable to\nallow the ball of a slip-skid indicator to be deflected outside the reference lines?\n",
        "answer": "When operating at any airspeed greater than V(MC).\n",
        "choiceone": "While maneuvering at minimum controllable airspeed to avoid overbanking.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When practicing imminent stalls in a banked attitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How should a balloon fuel system be checked for leaks prior to flight?\n",
        "answer": "Look, listen, and smell.\n",
        "choiceone": "Check for unusual discoloration on burner coils.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cover all fittings and hoses with soapy water and look for small bubbles.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are outboard ailerons normally used?\n",
        "answer": "Low-speed flight only.\n",
        "choiceone": "High-speed flight only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low-speed and high-speed flight.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aircraft landing gear, an under-inflated tyre:\n",
        "answer": "will wear at the shoulders\n",
        "choiceone": "it's tread will deteriorate faster\n",
        "choicetwo": "will have an increased critical hydroplanning speed\n",
        "choicethree": "will be more subject to viscosity aquaplaning on dry runway\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a hydraulic system, overheat detectors are usually installed:\n",
        "answer": "at the pumps.\n",
        "choiceone": "in the accumulators.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at the actuators.\n",
        "choicethree": "in the coolers.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thermal plugs are installed in:\n",
        "answer": "wheel rims.\n",
        "choiceone": "cabin windows.\n",
        "choicetwo": "cargo compartments.\n",
        "choicethree": "fire warning systems.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cabin rate of descent is:\n",
        "answer": "a cabin pressure increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "a cabin pressure decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not possible at constant airplane altitudes.\n",
        "choicethree": "always the same as the airplane's rate of descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cConditioned\u201d air is air that has :\n",
        "answer": "been controlled in respect of temperature and pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "had any moisture removed from it.\n",
        "choicetwo": "had the oxygen content increased.\n",
        "choicethree": "had the oxygen content reduced.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Electrical bonding of an aircraft is used to:\n1. protect the aircraft against lightning effects.\n\n2. set the electrostatic potential of the aircraft to a value approximating to 0 volt.\n3. prevent radio interference on radio communication systems.\n\n4. set the different aircraft parts to a single potential.\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:\n",
        "answer": "1,3,4\n",
        "choiceone": "1, 2,3\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,3,4\n",
        "choicethree": "1,2,4\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cFrequency wild\" in relation to a AC generation system means the generator :\n",
        "answer": "output frequency varies with engine speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "output frequency is too low.\n",
        "choicetwo": "output frequency is too high.\n",
        "choicethree": "voltage regulator is out of adjustment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Electrical bonding of an aircraft is used to: 1. protect the aircraft against lightning effects.\n2. reset the electrostatic potential of the aircraft to a value approximating 0 volt 3. reduce\nradio interference on radiocommunication systems 4. set the aircraft to a single\npotential The combination regrouping all the correct statements\n",
        "answer": "1,3,4\n",
        "choiceone": "1,2,3\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,4\n",
        "choicethree": "2,4\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The voltage regulator of a DC generator is connected in :\n",
        "answer": "series with the shunt field coil.\n",
        "choiceone": "parallel with the shunt field coil.\n",
        "choicetwo": "parallel with the armature.\n",
        "choicethree": "series with the armature.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a two generator system, a differential relay will ensure that :\n",
        "answer": "generator voltages are almost equal before the generators are paralleled.\n",
        "choiceone": "only one generator can supply the bus-bar at a time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "generator voltages are not equal, dependent on load.\n",
        "choicethree": "one generator comes \"on-line\" before the other.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The octane rating of a fuel characterises the :\n",
        "answer": "the anti-knock capability\n",
        "choiceone": "quantity of heat generated by its combustion\n",
        "choicetwo": "fuel electrical conductivity\n",
        "choicethree": "fuel volatility\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under what condition should stalls never be practiced in a twin-engine airplane?\n",
        "answer": "With one engine inoperative.\n",
        "choiceone": "With climb power on.\n",
        "choicetwo": "With full flaps and gear extended.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The indication of the fire detection systems is performed by a:\n",
        "answer": "warning light and a warning bell (or aural alert).\n",
        "choiceone": "warning light.\n",
        "choicetwo": "gear warning.\n",
        "choicethree": "warning bell.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane suffers an expl:\naltitude of 31000 ft. What is th\noperating crew ?\n\ndecompression at an\njal action by the\n\n",
        "answer": "to put on oxygen masks\n",
        "choiceone": "transmit a MAYDAY message\n",
        "choicetwo": "place the seat belts sign to ON\n",
        "choicethree": "disconnect the autopilot\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "operated at FL 450, with 180 passenger seats, what\nwill be the number of masks available for use\n",
        "answer": "198 (110% of the seating capacity).\n",
        "choiceone": "210 (one additional mask per seat row).\n",
        "choicetwo": "270 (150% of the seating capacity).\n",
        "choicethree": "240 (one additional mask per seat block).\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 85.) What procedure should be followed if communications are lost\nbefore reaching 9,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Continue climb to WAGGE INT, turn left direct to FMG VORTAC, then if at or above\nMCA, proceed on assigned route; if not, continue climb in holding pattern until at the\nproper altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "At 9,000, turn left direct to FMG VORTAC, then via assigned route if at proper altitude;\nif not, climb in holding pattern until reaching the proper altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Continue climb on LOC course to cross WAGGE INT at or above 9,000, turn left direct\nto FMG VORTAC to cross at 10,000 or above, and continue on assigned course.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot head is blocked, what airspeed indication can he expected?\n",
        "answer": "No change of IAS in level flight, even with large power changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "A decrease of IAS during a climb.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Constant IAS during a descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 87.) Where\nLake Charles?\n\nthe VOR COP when flying east on V306 from D:\n",
        "answer": "30 NM east of DAS.\n",
        "choiceone": "50 NM east of DAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "40 NM east of DAS.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How should you preflight check the altimeter prior to an IFR flight?\n",
        "answer": "Set the altimeter to the current altimeter setting. The indication should be within 75\nfeet of the actual elevation for acceptable accuracy.\n",
        "choiceone": "Set the altimeter to 29.92\" Hg. With current temperature and the altimeter indication,\ndetermine the true altitude to compare with the field elevation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Set the altimeter first with 29.92\" Hg and then the current altimeter setting. The\nchange in altitude should correspond to the change in setting.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the indications of the pulsating VASI?\n",
        "answer": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - steady white, slightly below glide slope steady\nred, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choiceone": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - green, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High - pulsing white, on course and on glidepath - steady white, off course but on\nglidepath - pulsing white and red; low - pulsing red.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify touchdown zone lighting (TDZL).\n",
        "answer": "Two rows of transverse light bars disposed symmetrically about the runway\ncenterline.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flush centerline lights spaced at 50-foot intervals extending through the touchdown\nzone.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Alternate white and green centerline lights extending from 75 feet from the threshold\nthrough the touchdown zone.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, a magnetic compass will normally indicate a turn toward\n\nthe north if\n",
        "answer": "an aircraft is accelerated while on an east or west heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "a left turn is entered from a west heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an aircraft is decelerated while on an east or west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "craft is flying from a cold air mass into a warm air mass. The TAS and true altitude\n\n",
        "answer": "Both increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "TAS increases, true altitude decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAS decreases, true altitude increases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an altimeter indicates 3500 FT with the actual QNH of 1004, 7 hPa set, the approximate\npressure altitude i\n\n",
        "answer": "3745 FT\n",
        "choiceone": "3500 FT\n",
        "choicetwo": "3255 FT\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the static source of an altimeter becomes blocked during a descent th\nwill:\n",
        "answer": "continue to display the reading at which the blockage occurred.\n",
        "choiceone": "gradually indicate zero.\n",
        "choicetwo": "under-read.\n",
        "choicethree": "indicate a height with the subscale setting on QNH.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Artificial Horizon employs a;\n",
        "answer": "Earth gyro\n",
        "choiceone": "Tied gyro\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rate gyro\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle of tilt of the rate gyro in a turn indicator is due to:\n",
        "answer": "primary precession which is generated by an aeroplanes rate of turn.\n",
        "choiceone": "the force in the horizontal plane generated by secondary precession balancing the\ntilt caused by primary precession;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the tension of the control spring opposing the angular tilt of the gyro;\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Turn and Slip indicator pre-flight check consists of:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft level, turn needle central, ball central, fluid in tube.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft level, ball central, turn needle central.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft not level, turn needle and ball displaced.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The gyroscope of a turn indicator has:\n\n(NB: the rotor spin axis is not counted for the number of degrees of freedom of the gyro)\n",
        "answer": "1 degree of freedom.\n",
        "choiceone": "0 degree of freedom.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 degrees of freedom.\n",
        "choicethree": "3 degrees of freedom.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering a flight director of the command bars type:\n",
        "answer": "the horizontal bar is associated with the pitch channel.\n",
        "choiceone": "the horizontal bar is associated with the roll channel.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the vertical bar is associated with the pitch channel.\n",
        "choicethree": "the vertical bar may be associated with the pitch channel.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A stall warning system is based on measuring the:\n",
        "answer": "angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "TAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "attitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fuel vents on many powered parachutes and weight shift control aircraft are located\n",
        "answer": "in the fuel cap.\n",
        "choiceone": "adjacent to the crankcase breather.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in the fuel tank pressure relief valve.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Coolant in a liquid cooled engine is normally circulated by\n",
        "answer": "an engine driven pump.\n",
        "choiceone": "capillary attraction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an electric pump.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "craft attitude tends to move farther from\nposition after the controls have been neutralized.\n\noriginal\n",
        "answer": "Negative static stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "Positive static stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Negative dynamic stability.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is considered an auxiliary flight control?\n",
        "answer": "Leading-edge flaps.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ruddervator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Upper rudder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The hydraulic oil, entering the hydraulic pump, is slightly pressurised to :\n",
        "answer": "prevent cavitation in the pump\n",
        "choiceone": "prevent overheating of the pump.\n",
        "choicetwo": "prevent vapour locking.\n",
        "choicethree": "ensure sufficient pump output\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The part of the flight that will cause the highest loads on tyre\n",
        "answer": "Taxiing with a small turning radius.\n",
        "choiceone": "Touch down with crosswind\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gear down selection\n",
        "choicethree": "Braking with an inoperative anti skid system.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum differential pressure of a transonic\n",
        "answer": "9.0 psi\n",
        "choiceone": "15.5 psi\n",
        "choicetwo": "3.5 psi\n",
        "choicethree": "13.5 psi\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When leaning the mixture for the most economic cruise fuel flow, excessive leaning will\ncause:\n",
        "answer": "high cylinder head and exhaust gas temperature\n",
        "choiceone": "high engine rpm\n",
        "choicetwo": "low cylinder head and exhaust gas temperature\n",
        "choicethree": "high manifold pressure\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The essential difference between aircraft AC alternators and DC generators (dynamos)\nis that the:\n",
        "answer": "induced (output) windings of the alternators are fixed (stator), and the dynamos have\na fixed inductor (field) coil.\n",
        "choiceone": "alternators supply all of the output current through the commutators and brush\nassemblies.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The alternators generate much less power than DC generators.\n",
        "choicethree": "induced windings of the alternators are rotating (rotor), and the dynamos have a\nrotary inductor coil.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cFrequency wild\" in relation to a AC generation system means the generator :\n",
        "answer": "output frequency varies with engine speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "output frequency is too low.\n",
        "choicetwo": "output frequency is too high.\n",
        "choicethree": "voltage regulator is out of adjustment.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a two generator system, a differential relay will ensure that :\n",
        "answer": "generator voltages are almost equal before the generators are paralleled.\n",
        "choiceone": "only one generator can supply the bus-bar at a time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "generator voltages are not equal, dependent on load.\n",
        "choicethree": "one generator comes \"on-line\" before the other.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The torque of an aeroplane engine can be measured at the:\n",
        "answer": "gear box which is located between the engine and the propeller.\n",
        "choiceone": "accessory gear box.\n",
        "choicetwo": "camshaft.\n",
        "choicethree": "propeller blades.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The oil system for a piston engine incorporates an oil cooler that is fitted :\n",
        "answer": "in the return line to the oil tank after the oil has passed through the scavenge pump\n",
        "choiceone": "between the oil tank and the pressure pump\n",
        "choicetwo": "after the pressure pump but before the oil passes through the engine\n",
        "choicethree": "after the oil has passed through the engine and before it enters the sump\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The operating principle of magnetos in a piston engine ignition system consists of:\n",
        "answer": "opening the primary circuit in order to induce a low amperage, high voltage current,\nwhich is distributed to the spark plugs.\n",
        "choiceone": "obtaining a high amperage, low voltage current in order to generate the spark.\n",
        "choicetwo": "accumulating in a capacitor a low voltage current from the battery and inducing it as a\nhigh voltage current at the moment the spark is generated.\n",
        "choicethree": "creating a brief high intensity magnetic field that will be sent through the distributor\nat the appropriate time.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In most cases aeroplane piston engines are short stroke engines. This permits a :\n",
        "answer": "lighter construction.\n",
        "choiceone": "lower fuel consumption.\n",
        "choicetwo": "better piston cooling.\n",
        "choicethree": "cheaper construction\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What performance should a pilot of a light, twin-engine airplane be able to m: atV\n\n(Mic)?\n",
        "answer": "Heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Heading and altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Heading, altitude, and ability to climb 50 ft/min.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does V(NE) speed vary with altitude?\n",
        "answer": "Varies inversely with altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Varies directly with altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Remains the same at all altitudes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Engine Pressure Ratio (EPR) is the ratio of:\n",
        "answer": "the total turbine outlet pressure to the total compressor inlet pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "the total turbine inlet pressure to the total compressor outlet pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the total turbine outlet pressure to the total compressor outlet pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "the total turbine inlet pressure to the total compressor inlet pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If air is tapped from a gas turbine HP compressor, the effect on the engine pressure ratio\n(EPR) and the exhaust gas temperature (EG7) is that :\n",
        "answer": "EPR decreases and EGT increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "EPR decreases and EGT remains constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "EPR remains constant and EGT increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "both EPR and EGT decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, if an aircrat\ncompass will normally indicate\n\naccelerated or decelerated, the magnetic\n",
        "answer": "correctly when on a north or south heading while either accelerating or decelerating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a turn momentarily, with changes in airspeed on any heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a turn toward the south while accelerating on a west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true concerning gyroplane operations?\n",
        "answer": "Minimum level flight speed is established when all available power is used to\nmaintain constant altitude and airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rotor RPM will decrease during a vertical descent regardless of weight or density\naltitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A gyroplane can take off from any area in which it can safely land.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the maximum tolerance for the VOI ication when the CDI is centered and\nthe aircraft is directly over the airborne checkpoint?\n",
        "answer": "Plus or minus 6 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plus 6degrees or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Plus or minus 4 degrees of the designated radial.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 85 and 86.) Which combination of indications confirm that you are\napproaching WAGGE intersection slightly to the right of the LOC centerline on\ndeparture?\n\n",
        "answer": "2 and 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 and 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 and 4.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a military airport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choiceone": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choicetwo": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 85.) What is the mi\nWASH2 WAGGE Departure?\n\njum rate climb per NM to 9,000 feet required for the\n",
        "answer": "400 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "750 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "875 feet.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When compared with the volumetric fuel flowmeter, the mass fuel flowmeter takes into\naccount the fuel:\n",
        "answer": "density.\n",
        "choiceone": "permittivity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "turbulent flow in the line.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pitot line is blocked, the VSI will:\n",
        "answer": "read normally\n",
        "choiceone": "read zero ftmm rate of climb/descent\n",
        "choicetwo": "over-read\n",
        "choicethree": "under-read\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airfield, elevation 3000 feet, has a pressure altitude of 3500 feet. What is the QFE?\n",
        "answer": "896.5 hPa\n",
        "choiceone": "913.s hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "879.8 hPa\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "level flight, it becomes necessary to use an alternate source of static pressure\nje the aircraft, with the cabin pressure being lower than static, the following\nvariations in instrument indication would be expected:\n\n",
        "answer": "the altimeter will read higher than normal, airspeed greater than normal and the\nvertical-speed indicator will momentarily show a climb;\n",
        "choiceone": "the altimeter will read higher than normal, airspeed will not change and the vertical-\nspeed indicator will momentarily show a descent;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the altimeter will read lower than normal, airspeed greater than normal and the\nvertical-speed indicator will momentarily show a climb and then a descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Concerning the pitot and static system, the static pressure error:\n",
        "answer": "is caused by disturbed airflow around the static ports.\n",
        "choiceone": "is a direct effect of heating of the static ports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "affects the alternate static port only.\n",
        "choicethree": "is a direct effect of a blockage of the static port.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A machmeter does not suffer from:\n",
        "answer": "compressibility error\n",
        "choiceone": "instrument error\n",
        "choicetwo": "position error\n",
        "choicethree": "error due to blockage of the static vent\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 022-10217A)\nConsidering the diagram n\u00b0, the flight director command bars position indicates that\nyou should:\n",
        "answer": "bank your aircraft to the left and increase the pitch angle.\n",
        "choiceone": "bank your aircraft to the right and increase the pitch angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "bank your aircraft to the left and reduce the pitch angle.\n",
        "choicethree": "bank your aircraft to the right and reduce the pitch angle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The radio altimeter is required to indicate zero height AGL as the main wheels touch\ndown on the runway. For this reason, it is necessary to:\n",
        "answer": "compensate for residual height and cable length.\n",
        "choiceone": "adjust the gross height according to the aeroplane instantaneous pitch.\n",
        "choicetwo": "change the display scale in short final, in order to have a precise readout.\n",
        "choicethree": "have a specific radio altimeter dedicated to automatic landing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Many 4-cycle engines utilize what type of lubrication system?\n",
        "answer": "Forced.\n",
        "choiceone": "Gravity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fuel/oil mixture.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fan guard surrounds the propeller and\n",
        "answer": "protects the parachute suspension lines from damage.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases aerodynamic efficiency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "reduces 'P' factor.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the CFR Part 1 definition of critical engine?\n",
        "answer": "The engine whose failure would most adversely affect airplane performance or\nhandling qualities.\n",
        "choiceone": "The outboard engine whose failure would most adversely affect safety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The engine still running which would most adversely affect performance if it should\nfail.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When refueling aircraft, which precaution would be adequate for eli\npotential hazard of static electricity?\n\n",
        "answer": "Connect a ground wire between the aircraft, fuel truck, fuel nozzle, and ground.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ensure that battery and ignition switches are off.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Connect a ground wire from the fuel truck to ground.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which direction from the primary control surface does an elevator adjustable trim tab\nmove when the control surface is moved?\n",
        "answer": "Remains fixed for all positions.\n",
        "choiceone": "Same direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Opposite direction.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why must the angle of attack be increased during a turn to maintain altitude?\n",
        "answer": "Compensate for loss of vertical component of lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increase the horizontal component of lift equal to the vertical component.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Compensate for increase in drag.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is considered an auxiliary flight control?\n",
        "answer": "Leading-edge flaps.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ruddervator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Upper rudder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What affects indicated stall speed?\n",
        "answer": "Weight, load factor, and power.\n",
        "choiceone": "Load factor, angle of attack, and power.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Angle of attack, weight, and air density.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A tubeless tyre has : 1- a built-in-air tube. 2- no built-in-air tube. 3-acrossed\ncasing. 4- a radial side casing. The combination of correct statements is:\n\n",
        "answer": "2,4.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2, 3.\n",
        "choicethree": "1,3.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term \"Bootstrap\", when used to identify a cabin air conditioning and pressurisation\nsystem, refers to the :\n",
        "answer": "cold air unit (air cycle machine) arrangement.\n",
        "choiceone": "source of the charge air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "means by which pressurisation is controlled.\n",
        "choicethree": "charge air across the inter-cooler heat exchanger.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When leaning the mixture for the most economic cruise fuel flow, excessive leaning will\ncause:\n",
        "answer": "high cylinder head and exhaust gas temperature\n",
        "choiceone": "high engine rpm\n",
        "choicetwo": "low cylinder head and exhaust gas temperature\n",
        "choicethree": "high manifold pressure\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cVapor lock\" is the phenomenon by which:\n",
        "answer": "heat produces vapour plugs in the fuel line.\n",
        "choiceone": "burnt gas plugs forming and remaining in the exhaust manifold following an\noverheat and thereby disturbing the exhaust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "water vapour plugs are formed in the intake fuel line following the condensation of\nwater in fuel tanks which have not been drained for sometime.\n",
        "choicethree": "abrupt and abnormal enrichment of the fuel/air mixture following an inappropriate\nuse of carburettor heat.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During fuelling the automatic fuelling shut off valves will\n",
        "answer": "the fuel has reached a predetermined volume or mass.\n",
        "choiceone": "the surge vent tank is filled.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there is fire.\n",
        "choicethree": "fuelling system has reached a certain pressure.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pressurization of tanks is maintained by the fuel:\n",
        "answer": "vent system.\n",
        "choiceone": "tank drains.\n",
        "choicetwo": "top off unit.\n",
        "choicethree": "dump system.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a current is passed through a conductor,\n",
        "answer": "a force will be exerted on the conductor.\n",
        "choiceone": "the current will increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there will be no effect unless the conductor is moved.\n",
        "choicethree": "the intensity of the magnetic field will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The output of a generator is controlled by :\n",
        "answer": "varying the field strength.\n",
        "choiceone": "varying the length of wire in the armature windings.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the reverse current relay circuit breaker.\n",
        "choicethree": "varying the speed of the engine.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reason for using inverters in an electrical system is\n",
        "answer": "To change DC into AC.\n",
        "choiceone": "To avoid a short circuit.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To change the DC voltage.\n",
        "choicethree": "To change AC into DC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As regards three-phase AC generators, the following conditions must be met for\nparalleling AC generators: 1. Equal voltage 2.Equal current 3.Equal frequencies 4.\nSame 5. Voltages of same phase The combination regrouping all the correct\nstatementsphase rotation is :\n",
        "answer": "1,3,4,5\n",
        "choiceone": "1,4,5\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,2,3,4\n",
        "choicethree": "1,3,5\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The turbine in a cold air unit (air cycle machine):\n",
        "answer": "drives the compressor in the unit, creating a temperature drop in the conditioning\nair.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases the pressure of the air supply to the cabin.\n",
        "choicetwo": "drives the compressor in the unit and causes a pressure increase in the\nconditioning air.\n",
        "choicethree": "drives the compressor which provides pressurisation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which instrument would be affected by excessively low pressure in the\nvacuum system?\n",
        "answer": "Heading indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airspeed indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pressure altimeter.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an altimeter is changed from 30.11\" Hg to 29.96\" Hg,\nindicated altitude change and by what value?\n\nwhich direction will the\n\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter will indicate 150 feet lower.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altimeter will indicate 15 feet lower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Altimeter will indicate 150 feet higher.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A possible result of using the emergency alternate source of static pressure inside the\ncabin of an unpressurized airplane is the\n",
        "answer": "altimeter may indicate an altitude higher than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "airspeed indicator may indicate less than normal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "altimeter may indicate an altitude lower than the actual altitude being flown.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How will the airspeed icator react if the ram ai\nice, but the drain hole and static port are not?\n\nput to the pitot head is blocked by\n",
        "answer": "Indication will drop to zero.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indication will rise to the top of the scale.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indication will remain constant but will increase in a climb.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 139 and 140.) Which\nthe 1.9 NM pointis indicated?\n\nplacement from the localizer and glide slope at\n",
        "answer": "710 feet to the right of the localizer centerline and 140 feet above the glide slope.\n",
        "choiceone": "710 feet to the left of the localizer centerline and 140 feet below the glide slope.\n",
        "choicetwo": "430 feet to the right of the localizer centerline and 28 feet above the glide slope.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, if an aircrat\ncompass will normally indicate\n\naccelerated or decelerated, the magnetic\n",
        "answer": "correctly when on a north or south heading while either accelerating or decelerating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a turn momentarily, with changes in airspeed on any heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a turn toward the south while accelerating on a west heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a pitot tube is clogged, which instrument would be affected?\n",
        "answer": "Airspeed indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Altimeter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vertical speed indicator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot identify a military airport at night?\n",
        "answer": "Green and white beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "choiceone": "Green, yellow, and white beacon light.\n",
        "choicetwo": "White and red beacon light with dual flash of the white.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the static pressure tubes are broken inside a pressurized cabin during a high-altitude\nflight, the altimeter would probably indicate\n",
        "answer": "lower than actual flight altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "sea level.\n",
        "choicetwo": "higher than actual flight altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the advantage of a three-bar VASI?\n",
        "answer": "A normal glide angle is afforded both high and low cockpit aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Pilots have a choice of glide angles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The three-bar VASI is much more visible and can be used at a greater height.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "nificance of the blue radial line on the airspeed\nmultiengine airplane and when is it to be used? It indicates the\n\n",
        "answer": "speed which will provide the maximum altitude gain in a given time when one engine\nis inoperative and should be used for climb and final approach during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "choiceone": "minimum speed at which the airplane is controllable when the critical engine is\nsuddenly made inoperative and should be used at all altitudes when an engine is\ninoperative.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed which will provide the greatest height for a given distance of forward travel\nwhen one engine is inoperative and should be used for all climbs during engine-out\noperations.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the indications of the pulsating VASI?\n",
        "answer": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - steady white, slightly below glide slope steady\nred, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choiceone": "High - pulsing white, on glidepath - green, low - pulsing red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High - pulsing white, on course and on glidepath - steady white, off course but on\nglidepath - pulsing white and red; low - pulsing red.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot head is blocked, what airspeed indication can he expected?\n",
        "answer": "No change of IAS in level flight, even with large power changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "A decrease of IAS during a climb.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Constant IAS during a descent.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VSI may suffer from error due to:\n",
        "answer": "time lag, instrument calibration, blockage\n",
        "choiceone": "compressibility, time lag, blockage\n",
        "choicetwo": "density, aircraft manoeuvre, position of the static vent\n",
        "choicethree": "pitot blockage, static blockage, aircraft manoeuvre\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Pitot Head and Static Vent were blocked by ice, which instruments would be\naffected?\n",
        "answer": "Altimeter, VSI and ASI would give inaccurate readings.\n",
        "choiceone": "ASI, Altimeter and Slip indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ASI would under read.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pitot line is blocked, the VSI will:\n",
        "answer": "read normally\n",
        "choiceone": "read zero ftmm rate of climb/descent\n",
        "choicetwo": "over-read\n",
        "choicethree": "under-read\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A simple pressure altimeter uses:\n",
        "answer": "static pressure fed into a gas tight casing, but outside a partially evacuated capsule\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure fed to an open capsule\n",
        "choicetwo": "pitot pressure fed to an open capsule\n",
        "choicethree": "static pressure fed outside a completely evacuated aneroid capsule.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Transition altitude is obtained from:\n",
        "answer": "Jeppesen or Aerad flight guides.\n",
        "choiceone": "ATC or VOR ATIS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1500 feet above airfield elevation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is maintal\nprobable cause is:\n\n1g FL 120 in cloud. The ASI reading falls to zero. The most\n",
        "answer": "ASI malfunction.\n",
        "choiceone": "Static vent blocked by ice.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pitot head and static vent blocked by ice.\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb, the static line becomes blocked, the ASI will:\n",
        "answer": "under-read\n",
        "choiceone": "read normally\n",
        "choicetwo": "over-read\n",
        "choicethree": "read zero\n",
        "source": "Completed/atg\\atgk.pdf"
    }
]